Hi
I'm Bertil Muth and this is scrum product backlog management, The essentilas
The theory of backlog management is defined in the scrum guide I put a link to it in the about section of this class
Is the practice
Can get tricky sometimes
So instead of just teaching you the concepts of backlog management
I will walk you through a consistent example
From the product Vision
to discovering high level stories
to using a technique called story mapping
To derive the more detail
Stories and I will also teach you what to do in the scrum events
As this is an intermediate level class you should have a basic understanding of how
agile Software development and scrum
Works
If you need a short recap please watch my class agile
and scrum for beginners
And now
Without further ado,
Let's begin.