- You've heard me mention
the YouTube Partner Program
a few times.
This is a program that unlocks
additional opportunities
including monetization.
Let me give a few pieces of
information that are useful,
but do keep in mind
that the Partner Program
is an evolving program
whose requirements change.
First up, what are the benefits
of the Partner Program?
Well, by signing up for
the Partner Program,
this is first and foremost
going to allow you
to monetize your content.
This means that you can take advantage
of serving up ads on your content,
ads that YouTube provides,
paid subscriptions to your content,
and the ability to offer
merchandise for sale
through YouTube or a third party provider.
YouTube Partner Videos can also earn money
from those ads or fees.
This includes if the content
is featured on things
like YouTube Television or YouTube Red
where people are paying for premium access
and it will allow you to reach more people
as the Partner Program content
tends to get more favorable treatment.
It is a non-exclusive agreement,
meaning that you are
allowed to put the content
onto other platforms not just YouTube.
In order to become a
partner, it's pretty simple.
First, make sure your YouTube
account is in good standing
with no complaints from
community guidelines
or copyright infringement.
You want to make sure that
the content you're uploading
is considered advertiser-friendly,
that it's original content,
not just content that
you're taking from others
or that you don't have the rights to.
It is critical that you are
not a copyright infringer.
YouTube has really cracked down on people
uploading videos that they
don't have the rights to
just to get views to try to
make money off of YouTube ads.
In fact, they are making lots of changes
to make this even more difficult lately.
Now very recently in 2018,
YouTube made some significant
changes to the Partner Program
that took a lot of people who
are in it and kicked them out.
I had some channels that were kicked out
because they didn't have
enough subscribers or views
and I had other channels
that were not affected.
What it means is that it used to be that
anybody can join the Partner Program
and start to monetize their content,
but now YouTube has set
certain threshold levels
for a channel or brand account.
This doesn't affect a lot of features
that used to be Partner only.
For example, you still can use cards now
without being a YouTube Partner
and you have access to
Creator Studio, custom URLs,
and custom thumbnails.
All of these used to be
requirements of being a member
in the Partner Program,
but YouTube decided to make
those available to everyone
even if they're not in
the Partner Program.
You can still use end screens
which allow you to put multiple videos up
at the end of your video telling
people what to watch next
and live streaming which is a great way
to engage with folks.
You also can do scheduled videos.
All of these were
features that used to mean
that you had to be a YouTube Partner.
So it used to be that if you wanted
any of these advanced options,
you had to join their program.
And I used to tell folks join
the YouTube Partner Program
and then feel free to turn off ads
if you don't want to use them.
I often find that serving up ads
isn't worth the annoyance to my customers
versus what I got from the other benefits
of reaching more people.
But that's ultimately up to you.
Another feature that's also available
that used to be tied to the
Partner Program is analytics.
So you can still see great statistics now
without joining the Partner Program.
But there are a couple of features
that do require a YouTube
Partner Program membership.
Super Chat, which is the ability
to have monetized chats on live stream,
requires you to be a member
of the Partner Program.
This will allow people
to purchase chat messages
during your live streams
and is particularly
popular with celebrities
and gaming channels.
The Super Chat ends up
highlighted by a color
and it can be pinned for
a certain period of time
based upon what someone is willing to pay.
Sponsorships, which
are also only available
for gaming channels,
require you to be a member
of the Partner Program.
This allows people to sponsor you
for in this case playing games
and people watch and enjoy.
Now personally,
I don't understand the
concept of sponsorships
of paying somebody else
to play video games.
I'd much rather buy the
games and play them myself,
but different types of
entertainment for different people.
So while some folks enjoy watching sports,
other folks enjoy watching video games
and they're willing to
pay for a ticket to do so.
So while it might seem
a little strange to me,
it makes about as much sense
as paying someone to go
watch a baseball game
so if there's an audience,
someone will charge money for it.
There are some benefits
for different levels
of the Creator program.
So this breaks down to
basically these categories.
So if you're just getting started,
you're in the Graphite category.
Most folks after they've
built up an audience
will fall under Opal
and this is where a lot
of my content works in.
Now if you're Bronze,
Silver, Gold, or Diamond,
you start to get a lot more subscribers
and YouTube will unlock
different features for you.
For example, if you're an Opal member,
this is going to give you the ability
to take advantage of Creator
Days and go to local meetups
or visit a YouTube space
or attend workshops.
This is great because it helps
you move to the next level.
Once you've achieved
one of those higher level statuses though
with having 10,000 members or above,
YouTube actually starts to open
up their facilities to you.
So you could actually go
to one of the YouTube production
studios in these cities
and record your content
or hold special events.
You also could be eligible to enter
to win awards and contests
and get some consultation
on improving your channel.
As you continue to grow in the program
and get more and more subscribers,
they even open up the option for
getting a dedicated partner
manager who works with you
and can help actually
improve your channel.
Or you can actually take
advantage of using the spaces more
for events and productions,
getting regular access to YouTube Studios.
So now that you understand
the benefits of the Partner Program
as well as some of the recent changes,
let's move on to talking
about how to sign up.