- In order to become a member
of the YouTube Partner Program,
there are a few things you need to do
to make sure you are eligible.
The general requirements are this.
You are able to join
as long as it's available in your country.
Not all countries allow
the Partner Program
so you have to check
that you are a resident
of an approved country.
Once your channel
reaches 4,000 watch hours
in the past 12 months and
has 1,000 subscribers,
then you are eligible for consideration.
You have to have both pieces of content.
So you can have tons of subscribers,
but if you're releasing
funny 10-second videos,
it might be really hard to
get up to 4,000 watch hours
so consider putting in some
longer form content as well.
You can check your status anytime
by going over to YouTube Analytics.
Now the availability for
the program is pretty broad.
If you fall into any of these
countries, it's available
and it's also available in
all of these countries too.
So as you can see, it's most of the world.
But there are a handful of countries
that have restrictions about
monetizing the internet
and you won't be able
to access the content.
Now when you want to sign
up, it's pretty simple.
First, sign in to YouTube.
Then in the top right corner,
navigate to Creator Studio.
Choose channel, status, and features.
Then under monetization, click enable.
Follow the on-screen steps
and accept the YouTube
Partner Program terms.
So once you're logged in,
you'll see the monetization section
and it should say that you're eligible.
Once you click and you
accept the terms of service,
you're basically enrolled.
However, you will need to
set up an AdSense account
in order to actually connect
and get the revenue from the ads.
And then once you've
done both of those steps,
they'll review your channel and guidelines
and make sure that you are
ready and in compliance.
YouTube will have a person,
a real person actually inspect
your channel and content
to make sure that you're a good match.
This is pretty easy.
Again, just click on your channel icon
and choose Creator Studio.
Look at your channel
and take a look at monetization.
Now in this case, it says I
need to specify my country
so I'll click
and tell it where I am located.
There we go.
And I'll tell it to allow advertisements.
I can specify if I have a website
and it looks like it wants
me to verify my website.
Clicking on this will give me
a handful of verification methods.
You'll see here that one
of the easiest methods
is to upload a small snippet of HTML
and this will verify that the
site is officially affiliated
with your particular channel.
There are other methods here that includes
using a particular tag,
searching by domain name
provider, or Google Analytics.
Now once you've done all of that
and you've linked your AdWord account,
everything should become connected.
I'll go ahead and click save here
and you'll see that I'm
partway through the process.
What it comes down to is
follow all of the instructions
and the requirements will change,
but essentially verify your website,
accept their terms of service,
go ahead and set up a
Google AdSense account
which is where the payments go
and if you've already got
one you can connect it,
and then accept the terms
of service again, and wait.
It's going to take a couple of days
for someone from YouTube to get around
to look at your channel,
but someone will review it and approve it
and you'll receive notification
that you are in the program
or if there are any issues
that need to be fixed.