- Here is the bad news.
Once you're in the partner program,
it doesn't mean you're guaranteed
to always be in the partner program.
You have to actively
maintain and keep publishing
your account on a regular
basis or Google may drop you.
You still need to maintain the
same minimum of viewer hours
and total number of viewers
or you could find yourself
being kicked out of the program.
So how do you keep an eye on this?
Well, first up, if you're
using Creator Studio Classic,
you can just log into your account
and take a look at the analytics.
View the watch time
and here's where you can
easily see what's happened.
You can download the report if
you want to check it as well,
but this gives you a pretty good idea
of how much content has been consumed.
An easier way to access this directly
is to use the analytics link here.
This just took you right to
the analytics and watch time
and you can see how many views you've had.
This will help give you a pretty good idea
on the total number of views
and what you can do is
actually adjust this to see
for the last 12 months if you'd like
and it'll give you a good idea
if you're going to be
eligible for the program.
So I see for example that
I do have enough minutes
to actually qualify of total views.
And it gives you a pretty
good idea of when spikes were.
For example, we had a
really good period here
when we did a lot of
coverage of new software
that just came out
and the company decided to promote it
and feature it as well.
That worked out nicely.
Now as you take a look at this,
this will help you track what's going on
so you can see the total
number of viewing hours.
And remember, you can also take a look
at your general overview to
see the number of subscribers.
Looking at these analytics,
you can get a good idea
of what changes have happened over time.
If you're using the YouTube Studio Beta,
this also provides analytics.
Simply click on the analytics
link in the left-hand menu
and you could take a
look at the overview tab
to see two useful cards,
channel watch time and video watch
which gives you an idea on
comparison between two periods.
If you click on these cards,
you'll get more information.
Here is the watch time card for example
and clicking expands the report
and gives me additional info.
Notice that you can
actually refine this as well
to see what's happened over time.
It gives you a pretty good idea
of what's going on with your content
so you can really make
accurate judgements.
The ability to use analytics
can be quite helpful
as you want to better
understand what content
and what behaviors are connecting.
Now if you lose your membership,
it's going to be because you fell below
the 1,000 subscribers minimum
or the 4,000 watch hours.
You need both.
Channels that previously reached
these requirement thresholds
will not necessarily lose monetization
just because they drop
below 4,000 watch hours
or 1,000 subscribers,
but Google does reserve the right
if you don't maintain these thresholds
to have the ability to kick
you out of the program.
It comes down to this.
Make sure that you keep your numbers up.
Otherwise, Google at its
discretion might remove you.
If you drop below those requirements,
they can strongly consider dropping you.
Or if your channel has been inactive
and you're not uploading
or posting content
for six months or more.
You don't necessarily
have to upload videos.
You can still use the
existing videos you have,
but you need to be making
posts and replying to people
and actively involved in
maintaining your channel.
If you violate any of the
YouTube partner program policies,
regardless of how successful you are
with watch hours and subscriber count,
you may find yourself kicked out
so make sure you take a look
at those terms of service.
Now in the past,
I used to recommend the
YouTube partner program
to just about everyone in
order to take advantage
of some of the most
useful features in YouTube
like links and streaming.
You had to join the partner program.
But YouTube has made it a lot
harder to monetize with ads.
A big part of that, the
official part of that,
is that they don't want
people uploading content
they don't have the rights to
or abusing the system
to monetize with ads.
Google wants the ad money to
go to real content creators
so they've been much more stringent
about letting people in
to the partner program
and evaluating their content
as well as making sure that
people get actual subscribers.
It doesn't matter that
you get a lot of views
because you uploaded some pirated content.
People aren't subscribing to your channel
because you're not providing good stuff.
Therefore, you're ineligible
for the partner program.
Now fortunately, most of the cool stuff
that used to be requirements
of joining the partner program
and dependent upon it,
well that's changed.
You don't have to worry
about being a member
of the partner program
to do live streaming or
to take advantage of cards
or to have custom thumbnails.
So a lot of the stuff that was most useful
and desirable in YouTube is now decoupled
from the partner program.
But if monetization is your goal
or you'd like to take
advantage of YouTube Studios
and other facilities for your productions
or meetings or training,
well then join the
YouTube partner program.
I can tell you that personally,
I don't rely very heavily on it anymore
because I don't use YouTube's
ad system to make money,
but I do love the fact
that I could build in links
to products and donations
or to products that are for sale
or webpages that I run
for other properties
and to connect this all together
in a very effective network.
Ultimately it comes down to this.
Figure out what's the
right fit for your channel,
your customer or organization,
and the content that you're making.
Sometimes ads work and
sometimes they don't,
but you need to determine
what's right for you.