Project managers and business analyst
play absolutely critical roles
in today’s organizations . in today’s
project environment where complexity change
and ambiguity of the norm project managers
and business analyst must collaborate tightly
and build deep relationships with one another
to get great project results and better business
outcomes hi I’m
Angela Wick and welcome to this course which focuses
on project manager and business analyst
collaboration this course guides
PMs and BAs through the critical
areas of role overlap and collaboration points
I introduced to team members that pave
the way for each roll through the course
pat the PM and Bailey BA
will take us through common scenarios in areas
where partnership between these two rolls is
a must things like planning in scope
management they will guide us through the key
mindsets and considerations such as
changing requirements and stakeholder engagement
you learn from Pat and Bailey
that this deep collaboration will build
trust with stakeholders Foster an
environment for stakeholder engagement and help
entire team focus on the outcomes that
matter with the project are you ready
to start your path towards better collaboration
and discover a deeper relationship between
PMs and BA’s . let’s
dive in.