We could all site my projects we’ve been on
have failed and research studies give us many
clues as well but have you ever really
looked at how the PM and BA relationship could
contribute to these failures and possibly even
prevent them let’s look at a few ideas
first - lack of stakeholder engagement
and involvement and this includes engage
sponsor and sponsors having clear vision
and objectives. the BA and PM
have key roles and helping the leaders
take the vision and objectives and
turn them from strategy to execution
stakeholder involvement at the leader and contributor
levels is key to making the strategy and vision
a reality . the PM
and BA are the team members that interact with
stakeholders and leaders the most throughout the project
when both brawls are interacting with the same
stakeholders and often does it
need to collaborate tightly I miss interactions
to keep stakeholder engagement high
the stakeholders typically have full-time roles outside
of the project so keeping the engagement strong
get not burdensome is a key element
next - changing priorities is a key failure
points. how teams handle changing priorities
can have a huge impact on if
Value gets delivered on projects this failure point
also points back to stakeholder involvement.
the PM in BA are both
heavily involved in managing priorities with
stakeholders and influencing stakeholders on prioritization.
and last - changing requirements.
changing requirements can be a good thing or
a bad thing. in bracing changing
requirements can lead to a competitive advantage
of the changes are result of learning more
about what customers and users needs are
at the same time if the project can’t
seem to deliver anything do the starts and stops
with constant changes , this can be to failure
the PM and BA
collaborate heavily on helping stakeholders in the team ,
identify and manage requirements
into pieces of work. these deliverables
if not well defined can be delivered in
increments that make requirements change less risky
while leveraging change for a competitive advantage
Pat PM and Bailey BA start getting
into deep discussions on what does success
mean on a project anyway
is it when a project is delivered on schedule
within budget results in a working product
or meets the business intent
they determine that the best approach for them is
to collaborate on the finance successful projects with stakeholders
the business intent maybe to
beat a competitor to market was sacrificing quality
and cost time is most important
to success or the product
working at a determined quality level with customer delight
may be far more important than cost and schedule
most leaders want cost schedule and
quality while delayed in the customer but
it’s important to know which is leading the success equation
Pat and Bailey has found that this
is dramatically changed how they work and collaborate