- Now that you understand the difference
between your Google ID
and your brand account,
let's go through some of the essential
strategies you need when
creating a new channel.
Remember, with Channel Creation,
it's pretty simple.
Start by making sure you're logged-in
to the correct account you want to use.
Then, click your profile icon.
Click Switch Account.
And check if there's an existing account,
if you want to add it.
Or, check more accounts if you want to add
a new one, or choose
from an existing brand.
This'll be quite useful.
Add Account will allow you to add
a Google Channel based
on an existing brand
that you're logged in to.
And you might see this if you've never
created a channel before.
Otherwise, you can use
the More Accounts option
to set up a custom account
or a Google channel for a brand account.
Remember, you'll see a screen like this
where you can choose from existing brands
or brand accounts that don't yet have
a YouTube channel associated with them.
Or, click the Plus button to create
an all-new brand account.
You'll be prompted to enter the name.
And then the page is created.
So, let's do this.
To start, click on the
icon in the upper corner.
You may see different accounts there.
If you want to use the existing channel
that was automatically created,
just click Creator Studio.
Or choose More Accounts.
This'll take you to a page.
Now I'm going to make a new account here,
this time called Presets.photography.
It's a new account where I'm going to be
promoting photography presets
for different software packages.
And I'll click Create.
It takes a moment, but then the new page
is created and you land on it.
You'll see a very generic page right now
because there is no content uploaded yet,
and no artwork whatsoever.
However, we'll fix this in just a moment.
Remember, you can have multiple channels
tied to each brand account.
So, if you don't want to use your
personal presence on YouTube,
make sure you set up a new brand account
affiliated with your Google ID.
If you skipped that section
earlier in the course,
be sure to go back and watch it.
Because there are a lot of subtle details.