- In order to give your
page a proper look,
it's recommended that
you add some artwork.
The generic person icon in a solid color
probably doesn't really
establish your brand very well.
It makes you look like it's a fake account
or one that you couldn't
be bothered to set up.
There are several pieces
of required artwork.
I'm going to walk you
through what they are now,
and a little bit later in the course,
I'll show you how to make them.
On a computer, sign into YouTube.
Then click in the upper right
menu and choose My Channel.
You'll see the option for new channel art
near the top of the screen.
You can click to add new channel art,
or if you have existing
art, you can choose
to modify the banner and
then choose Edit channel art.
Generally speaking, when you're logged in,
you'll see something like this.
You'll then be presented
with a screen to upload
or choose from existing content
you've already uploaded.
Once you've uploaded it,
then you'll see a preview
of how it looks across multiple devices.
You can also choose to adjust the crop
and then click the Select
button to store the edits.
Some of the specs you need to keep in mind
is that the channel art
is going to look different
on different devices.
This is why YouTube
provides a template file
to make this a bit easier,
and we'll explore that later.
Larger images tend to be
cropped, so for the best results,
you're going to upload a single image
that's 2,560 pixels by 1,440 pixels.
This will allow the artwork
to appear on the page and
give some branding to it.
Let me show you how.
Once you're logged into your page,
you should see the individual channel.
If you don't, click on your
icon and choose My channel.
Now click the Customize button.
You're now presented with
the look of your channel.
If you've uploaded any
videos, these will be shown.
Otherwise, it will show as empty.
I'll click the Add Channel Art button.
You can also click here on the pencil icon
and choose to edit the channel art.
This brings up a new dialogue.
Now click to browse or
drag a new photo in.
I've put together a few
samples in the exercise files,
and I'll choose a sample image here.
Let's just start with a
simple photo for a moment
and we'll try this one here.
I'll click Choose.
The picture uploads, and
it will show it to me
in the editing dialogue box
if it meets the minimum resolution.
Now if it's below, as
it was here, you'll see
that it warns you that it's
not high enough resolution,
so you'll need to find
a higher quality photo
or use an image editing tool to resize it.
Let's select again and this time,
I'm going to choose the
one called Channel Art
that I know is the right
size, and I'll click Choose.
The file uploads and it
gives me a simulation
of what it looks like on each device.
You'll see a preview for
desktop, TV, and mobile.
If I click Adjust the
crop, I can modify things,
and you'll see as you do so,
it's going to show you what it looks like.
The inner box is what it's going to be
on most devices for mobile.
The outer box is how
it looks on televisions
that are connected to YouTube.
So keep in mind that televisions
are going to need a 16
by nine aspect ratio.
I'll go ahead and click Select here
and the image is saved and uploaded.
And you see that it places
it into the top of the bar,
and that works quite nicely.
While we're at it, let's
also upload the social icon.
I'll click on the social icon here
and choose to edit the channel.
Let's choose to upload a file.
I'll go to the same folder
and choose a JPEG file in
this case and click Choose.
The file is uploaded, and you'll see
a similar choice for adjusting the crop.
When satisfied, click Done,
and you see it updates here
on your principal page.
By the way, while you're
updating the icon here,
you might want to also
change the banner artwork
using the same artwork that
you put onto your YouTube page.
And you see that it adds it
to your Google ID profile,
or in this case, the
brand account profile.
Now it's added.
However, the challenge
here is that the logo
is covering up the logo,
so what works on YouTube
might not work on another page.
So let's swap that out
and upload another image.
And I'll go for the
generic version of that
that doesn't have a logo built in
and click Done, and it updates.
So you want to be careful and keep in mind
that artwork for YouTube
might not work on Google Plus
and might not work on your brand account
or personal account profile.
But I'm satisfied now and we'll click OK.
It updates and now let's
switch back to YouTube
and I'll press refresh, and you see
that the new look has been taken on.
Now you might notice,
if you visit your page
on a mobile device, that the
artwork may take a moment
to propagate across all platforms.
Just because you see it on one device
doesn't mean you'll see it on another.
Google serves up things
at multiple resolutions,
so be prepared to wait a little bit
for your artwork to make it
all the way through the system
if you customize it.