- Once you have some artwork in place,
you probably want to
fill in the about tab,
which tells people about your channel.
This is pretty straight forward.
First up, add a description
about your site.
Be sure to also include
any contact information
if you want people to
get in touch with you
for business purposes.
And you can specify a
location to make it easier
to find your business, if this matters.
Also, you can add any relevant links
that you want people to know about.
This can be easily added
on the page itself.
Let's go ahead and
modify a few things here.
On the page, all I need to do
is switch over to the about tab.
Now, it asks me for information.
Click to add a channel description.
I've included a text file that
you can use to copy and paste
if you'd like to follow along.
Or, feel free to sit back and watch.
At the bottom is a link
if you'd like to see
how this description
appears on other websites
that Googles owns.
This'll take you to a page
with a support article
that explains how the
different things are used.
So, there's the channel description
and it gives you a little bit
of additional information.
Now, let's keep going.
Under details here, I can
choose to add an email
for business inquiries.
I can also specify a country for business.
And, let's add an external website.
This is the same user
interface you saw before
where up to five links can
be included on the page.
Let's copy the URL
and I'll attempt to add it in.
There we go.
And now it's added.
And you'll notice that it
actually took the favicon
that was set at the website level.
So, if you take the time to add a favicon
using WordPress or your
other hosting platform,
it will pick up the custom icon.
Alright, let's click done.
And you'll notice that I'm
getting a warning here,
that there's too much information.
Well, you are limited to
a thousand characters here
so, if needed, you might
have to actually remove some.
Then it stores it.
Now, you'll see that the
website has been added
to my top navigation.
Everything else is stored.
Now, let's go ahead and view
the channel as a subscriber.
I can see how it will look to them,
the logo is there,
the artwork is loaded,
there's my link for the
website and it looks good.
Alright, the page is populating.
Remember, later on I'll walk you through
some of the strategies
for creating that artwork
using a tool like Adobe Photoshop.
But, as you see, once you've
got a banner artwork uploaded
and a icon for you as a channel,
it's going to take on a whole new life
and that page starts to look a lot better.