- Another area that you
need to take a look at
is how you control the
settings for discussion
about your channel.
Now, personally, I like to see discussion
on individual videos
but I'm not interested in
having comments available
on the channel itself
where people discuss
the channel as a whole.
However, some people may want this.
It does tend to be a place, though,
where your harshest critics will gather
and post things for everyone to see.
Let me show you how you can control this.
First up, the channel discussion
is going to be done under the gear icon
in the top right corner of the page.
This controls whether people can comment
on a channel as a whole.
What you can do is sign in
and then click on My Channel
and go to your channel banner.
Click the settings icon.
Sign in on your computer
and then click on your icon
and choose my channel.
Under the channel banner,
you'll see a choice
for settings, a gear icon.
Click it and you can now decide
to show the discussion tab
and make things on or off.
If you do turn this on, you can decide
that you'd like to show
comments automatically
without moderation or wait
until you've had a chance
to login and approve them.
Comments will not be
available on private videos
so if you don't want to
allow commenting on a video
that's publicly available,
make sure you post it
as an unlisted video.
Now, let's go to the channel
and I'll click the
customize channel button
to make sure it's editable.
You'll now see the gear
icon and simply click.
You can decide if you want
to show the discussions tab.
Let's close this for a moment
and you'll see discussions.
This is where people can post comments.
If you don't want
discussions on the main page,
click that icon again
and choose to disable it
and it will go away.
Remember, if it's enabled, you can decide
to display automatically
or to moderate them.
I'm gonna turn it off at the
channel level and click save.
You'll see that the
discussions tab goes away.
Now, if you do decide
to enable discussions,
let me give you a few pieces of advice.
First up, make sure that
you choose whether or not
to display them.
I do not recommend being
automatically displayed.
Rather, I would strongly suggest
that if you choose to show
comments on your page,
that you set these to be
only approved comments.
Also, I would recommend
that those comments
are reviewed by either you
or one of the communications manager
before you make them live.
This gives you a chance
to respond to people
and to decide if the comment
adds to the discussion
or is simply somebody venting.
Now, in my own personal experience,
YouTube commenters typically exhibit
some of the worst writing skills.
What it comes down to is make
sure that you're in control.
If this is a brand that matters to you,
you might not want to give
people a free for all.
I'm all for social media and engagement
but think of it this way.
Would you let somebody stand
in the lobby of your building
or the front entryway
screaming negative things?
Probably not.
It can be really distracting
to other customers or visitors.
Now it's fine to see those
comments if they're moderated
and reply to the person as a
customer service opportunity.
So, if you're prepared to
monitor these comments,
turn on the discussion tab but
set them to approval first.
This way, you can get
the negative feedback
and engage the customer
to make them satisfied.
If you don't have time to moderate this
and you don't want to get
customer support complaints
through YouTube, then turn it off
and just make sure that you
have a feedback mechanism
on your company's website.
Now, couple more things
to look at for settings.
I would also suggest that you take a look
at your privacy settings.
Remember, this controls what's
going to be shown to people.
I generally recommend that
these should be disabled.
And take a look at your notifications
to understand what's going
to be put out to people
when you publish.
So, if we go here to our settings icon,
I'm gonna leave things set to private here
so all of my playlists, subscriptions
and viewed videos are private
and if I want other controls, I can click
to access advanced settings.
And this will let me
control what is shared.
So, for example, I'm gonna keep all
of my liked videos private.
And I'm not going to post
to the activity feed.
This way, I don't get
accidental posts on my content.
Additionally, if I click
the notification icon here,
I can control, if there are
any notifications coming in
and I can click the gear icon here
to see the settings and, you see,
it let's me control
what I'm notified about.
So, for example, I can get
emails about all of my activity
or only do ones that are
required announcements.
You see that this affects
what you get notified on,
everything or only specific things.
You can decide what you're
gonna get notified on.
Do you want to get a push
message or an email or both?
And this will show you up
here, as a push message,
in the mobile app and in your email.
And you can decide if you want
to get notified about things.
For example, I don't
really care about activity
on my channel or my comments
but I do want to know about
replies to my comments.
This way I get notified if I
need to respond to somebody
after they've replied to me.
In any case, you're in control
of what you get notified on
and what information
you share with people.
Remember, this is important
because as you go back
to your channel here,
this will affect what
information is going to appear
in the stream and what
notifications people
are told about as you start to
engage with YouTube content.