- Another thing that you can
add to a page is a trailer.
This is a video that gives people an idea
about your products or your company.
Now, here's a couple pieces of advice.
Consider when you create this trailer
that it advertises your
particular channel,
and is there to entice
people to subscribe.
Remember, subscriptions are free.
Try to consider the audience's motivation.
What's gonna drive them
to like your channel
or come back?
And be sure to include a call to action,
driving people to subscribe.
Be sure to emphasize that
subscriptions on Youtube are free.
Now there are ways for people
to pay to be a fan of yours
if you have a certain style
of account on Youtube,
but generally speaking, when
we say "subscribe on Youtube",
that's a free subscription.
And the key benefit here is it ensures
that they won't miss out
on any of the content
or the items that you release.
Now, let me take a moment and
show you a sample trailer.
This is one that we
produced a few years back
for a company called
Adorama-- it's a retail store
that has their own
products, and also carries
many other camera products,
and they put together
an extensive Youtube channel
that informs and educates
folks on how to get more
from their photography.
So, the trailer tries to
entice you with a little bit
of humor to become a fan.
(jazzy music)
(bell dings)
- [Narrator] Meet Bill.
(jaunty music)
Bill likes photography.
Bill wants to make great photos.
(camera shutter snaps)
But Bill could use some help.
(camera shutter snapping)
Adorama TV has everything
a photographer needs.
Bill can watch tutorials
with world-renowned experts,
and get tips on the best
gear, and how to use it.
(bell dings)
Now Bill makes great photos,
and has fun doing it.
(camera shutter snaps)
Bill is one smart cookie.
(twinkle)
Subscribe to Adorama TV to get
the latest photography tips
and tutorials.
Brought to you by Adorama,
more than a camera store.
(twinkle)
- In that case, that was
a full-on commercial,
and the company's Youtube
channel was a key component
of their email-based and
internet marketing strategy.
As such, they had a budget to
produce a decent commercial
about their Youtube channel.
But even a simple personal
introduction from you,
the channel host, or perhaps
a slideshow set to music,
or edited clips as a
montage about what your show
or channel is about is a
great way to give people
information.
You also have the ability to
decide to show the trailer
to people only before they subscribe.
This way, the trailer is shown
to potential subscribers,
but not shown to people
after they subscribe
to your channel.
To do this is pretty simple.
Let me show you where to set this.
I've switched to a page that
already has a video uploaded.
In order to set a trailer,
you'll need to have uploaded
a video already.
Go to your channel and then
click "customize channel."
Click on the "For new visitors" tab
and you can now choose
to add a channel trailer.
You can choose from any
video you've already uploaded
and click "Save."
Now it's shown.
You'll notice that returning subscribers
may not see the trailer,
they'll see what video
is uploaded next.
In this case I only have
one, so it does show as well,
but for new subscribers,
they're gonna be presented
with that video.
So you can decide to feature a video here,
or have a trailer, and it'll
be prominently shown to people
for the first time they visit
your page until they click
the Subscribe button.
Then, once they've done
that, it'll go away.
So let's go ahead here and
customize this really quick.
I'll just go ahead and view
this as a returning subscriber,
and you see that there
is no trailer shown.
The use of a trailer is a
great way to prompt people
to take action and to subscribe.
And as you'll learn
later when we talk about
managing your audience,
driving subscriptions
is an important way to
engage with your audience.