https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] A good team is much more
than just a bunch of people.
But in order to work together,
we need to have a process.
This process will make the team more productive.
Each member will need to help the process,
Sometimes at the expense of their own productivity.
A good process will also help us prevent errors,
and when errors will happen,
find and fix them quickly.
There's nothing worse than a customer
finding out there is a problem before you.
Each company has its own process,
and sometimes, teams inside the same company
will have different process for working.
What works for Google is probably an overkill
for a small startup.
What's a good process for the R&D team
will be a bad match for the operations team.
Remember that the process should serve you.
If you find that the process is hurting your team back,
change it.
Nothing is set in stone.