https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] A good process will help you avoid mistakes.
By following a process,
we take steps that are meant to prevent errors.
Some of these steps are automation.
Automating tasks is a great way to avoid mistakes.
Machines are less prone to make errors than us humans.
Checklists, checklists are great.
Use them when you can't automate.
Checklists embed best practices and eliminate errors
that come from forgetting things.
If you're skeptical about checklists,
you can read The Checklist Manifesto
or search for checklist in our offering
and see how much it's mentioned.
Knowledge transfer.
A good process embeds knowledge acquired over time.
For example, requiring a new test
for every new piece of code.
The cost of mistakes will heavily affect your process.
If you're writing a small API server
used internally by your team,
the cost of error is not that big.
However, if you're writing software for the Mars rover,
any bug can mean billions of dollars going to waste.