https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] As Heraclitus said,
"change is the only constant in life."
Over time, your production environment will change,
your team will change, customers will change,
as well as many other things.
Your process should change as well,
to accommodate for these changes.
Your process should serve you.
If you feel it doesn't, go and fix it.
However, you shouldn't just blindly change things.
You should make changes based on data.
A nice model you can look into is the OODA,
which stands for observe, orient, decide and act loop.
Every time you make a change, you observe the affect it made
and then make changes accordingly.
Repeat forever.
Our eyes into production and the way we can observe changes
is monitoring, which we will discuss in other chapters.
As DJ Patil, who was the Chief Data Scientist
for the White House said,
"if you can't measure it, you can't fix it."