https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] One of Python's models is batteries included.
When you install Python, you get the rich
standard library with many packages.
A lot of times the standard library will be enough.
However sometimes, you'll need a package
that's not in the standard library,
a third-party package.
The center location for third party packages
for Python is PyPI.
At the time of recording, it hosts about 200,000 packages.
It's a lot to chose from.
That's one of the problems of third party packages.
At first glance it's super easy to use
a third party package.
You pip install the package and its ready for you to use.
However, you need a good process that will
ensure that the work done in development
will also run in production.
On top of that, it's possible that the same server will
want two or more applications.
Each of them uses a different versions of a dependency.
And some other things can go wrong as well.
A package you are using can be discontinued.
A package you are using can be malicious.
A package update can crash your code.
And many more things can go wrong.
I highly recommend reading
Russ Cox, Our Software Dependency Problem
that even though it's not
about Python, summarizes the problem well.