https://git.ir/
- You can install Python packages, in many ways.
Copy file over, run Python setup.py install
and several other ways.
You need an established way to install packages;
which means a package manager.
There are several package managers for Python
and by far pip, is the most widely used one.
This makes pip a good choice
since there is a lot of knowledge and tooling around it.
I'm going to talk about pip
but the ideas here, apply to other package managers as well.
You should always version your dependencies.
It will save you from surprises in the future
when some update accidentally introduces a bug
or changes a function parameters.
You should also write your dependencies
and their versions down
and place this file in source control
so other team members and the operations team
will be able to reproduce the same environment.
On top of a package manager,
you should use a virtual environment.
It's an isolated installation of Python
that will let you run several applications
on the same host and will keep the system Python whisting.
Here's an example, the file is called requirements.txt
and we have two dependencies for our project;
pandas of inversion 0.25
and requests in version 2.22.0
Try to sort your requirements alphabetically
it will be easier to scan them.
Once we have this file, we can install it.
First we create a virtual environment, virtualenv venv.
Venv the name of the virtual environment
and, it's a common practice to call it venv.
Once the virtual environment is created
we can use pip inside it to install the dependencies
so... venv bin python dash n pip install
and then we say r and requirements file
and this is going to install
our dependencies and their dependencies.
Now we can run Python from the virtual environment
venv bin python, and for example
import pandas as pd, and it works.
Make sure to have a venv excluded from your source control
for example by adding it to .gitignore.