https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] You might have dependencies
that are used only in development.
Test suites, linters, and others.
The common practice is to have
a separate requirements file for production
and another one for development.
Another issue is that depending on the operating system
you might need different packages.
The common practice here
is to specify only the top-level dependencies
and let pip decide what you need.
For example, when we install pandas,
pip will install panda's dependencies as well.
Some people like to have these sub-dependencies
in their requirements file as well.
I prefer to have only the top-level ones.
Here's our requirement file for production.
We have pandas and we have requests
and we have another file,
which is the development requirements.
And here it has the flake8 linter
and pytest as a testing suite.
You should automate the creation of the virtual environment.
Here's an example using make.
I have a rule to create the virtual environment
and then in line five,
I have a rule to create the development virtual environment,
which is the virtual environment
plus the development requirement.
And now, I can do make dev-venv
and makefile will run the commands required
to create the development virtual environment
and as you can see, in venv/bin/flake8,
now we have the flake8 linter.
Make sure your production installation process
installs only the requirements
needed to run the application.