https://git.ir/
- As your company and code evolves
you'll have some packages that you wrote
and are used by several other projects.
If your company is okay with releasing these packages
as open source, it's a win-win situation.
You can install them from PyPI
and the community gains a package.
However, in some cases
you'd like to keep some packages internal
to your company.
At the same time,
you'd like to use your regular install process.
Lucky for you, PyPI's very flexible
about installing packages.
You need to build your packages as a wheel, egg or sdist.
See the documentation on how to do that.
Once you have a wheel of your package
you can use pips --find-link option.
'-- find-links option' can work both with directories
or actually to be service.
If you have a shared directory, this is the simplest.
Copy the wheel over.
Here's an example of requirements file
for directory.
In line three, we're looking for Python packages
in /opt/packages.
Your location might fail.
So let's create a virtual environment.
And then virtual environment bin python-m pip
install -r requirements dir.pur.
And you see that the lilmath packkage is installed
from /opt/packages.
If you don't have a shared directory
you can have a web server
that serves as directory.
Here's a quick way to do it.
In the same directory that we have the packages
you run python -m http.server.
This will stop web server on port 8000.
And now, in our requirement file
which is requirements-web.txt.
In line three you can see find links now
points to local host 8000.
And now let's install.
So, let's remove
the virtual environment
and recreate it again.
And now, venv/bin/phyton -m pip install -r requirements,
and this time, the web WANS.
Install.
And you can see that lilmath is installed from
local host 88.
Apart from these solutions,
there are applications that host packages
from free open source commercial offerings.