https://git.ir/
- [ Narrator ] Docker and Kubernetes are becoming
the standard way to ship and manage applications.
A Docker container is an isolated environment,
and here we can install packages without
the need for a virtual environment.
To create a Docker image for your application,
you need to write a Docker file.
Let's have a look.
So this is Docker file for the time z HTTP server.
We specify in line 2 that we using
the Python 3.7-slim Docker image.
In line 3 we create a user for our application.
It is considered a good security practice.
In line 6 we set the environment variable
for the port to listen on, for 8080.
In line 8 we copy the requirements file.
In line 9 we install them.
In line 13 we copy the package.
I line 14 we specify the command to run,
Python, dash-m, time z.
And now we can build it.
Docker,
build,
and we say the tag.
The tag is the name of the docker image,
and let's say lil
time z.
And then we say the current directory.
So Docker,
build,
dash t is the name of the image
So l i l slash time z, and then we say the current directory
And Docker is going to build the image for us.
It's going to install dependencies and copy our application.
And now we can run it.
So we can do Docker, run, dash-p, 8080,
We telling Docker to expose port 8080 from the Docker
container, to our local machine,
and dash rm saying remove
this container once it's down, and then
timez.
And now server is running, now we can
open a new tab and try to connect to our server.
So I am going to use a curl command line
and say http
local host
8080,
and then the current time in
Europe,
London
and I get the current time, in JSON format.
If you want to learn more about Docker, or Kubernetes,
check out our offering on these topics.