https://git.ir/
- Testing is important.
It validates your code, and guards against
breaking one part of the code,
when changing another.
If we read about testing,
you notice that there are a lot of test types.
For example, at the site How SQLite is Tested,
you can see the following test types,
out of memory, crash, fuzz, regression,
and much more.
Since you don't have time to implement all the tests,
what should you focus on?
The answer is, of course, what brings the most value.
In my experience, the following test types
yield the best value;
however, it might differ for your project.
Deployment, check that your deployment scripts work.
Integration, this test check the connection
between sub-systems and connections
with external systems.
Regression, these tests check that running the code
over known data, returns a known solution.
Fuzzing, these tests generate random data
and through it at your code.
Linters, these are static checkers
that find common issues without running your tests.
Unit, check your code in isolation for valid outputs.
You should keep track of all the bugs
that every kind of test find,
and when you get a bug report,
think what kind of test could have caught it.
After a while, you'll know which type of tests
bring the most value,
and you should focus your effort
on these types of tests.