https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] We have a joke.
I don't care if it works on your machine.
You're not selling your machine to customers.
CI stands for continuous integration.
It's the practice of running the test suite
on a remote machine every time we make a change to the code.
CI helped detect a big class of errors,
forgetting to add or delete a file,
version mismatches, and more.
CI also helps in integration problems.
It can run tests that a developer
can't run on their machine, due to time, resources,
or other considerations.
CI has become a standard practice,
and there are many CI systems.
Jenkins, Circle CI, Travis CI, and more.
After CI, there's CD, which stands for Continuous Delivery.
CD means that once the tests pass, they automatically deploy
a new version to production.
It's not easy getting to full CD, but there are companies
who manage it and deploy hundreds of changes
to production daily.
I recommend you start with CI,
and aim for CD only if you have the need
and the resources available.