https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] As your code grows,
so does your test suite.
At some point, developers won't be able to run
all of the tests on their machine.
This might be due to complex set up required,
say a load balancer or a special hardware,
or maybe just due to the time it takes to run the tests.
Your rule of thumb should be the test
the developer run on their machine
should take less than a minute.
In my experience, if a test suite takes longer
than a minute to run
developers won't run it as frequently.
Pytest has a built in support for markers.
You can mark tests, say with web mark,
and then run only the web tests.
See the documentation for more details.
I recommend that at the beginning you will start simply.
Split the tests to two groups,
one the developers run and one that runs on CI,
which includes the first group.
Let's have a look.
Here's a code example.
I'm going to environment variable called CI
to check if you are under the CI system or not.
In line three, I'm importing environ,
which is the environment variables
and in line six, I'm setting is_ci,
but true only if CI is inside the environment
meaning we are running under the CI system.
The test on line nine will run regardless,
but the test on line 14 will run only if the CI
environment variable is set.
We're using pytest.mark.skipif for that.
Let's have a look.
In developer machines, so python -m pytest -v,
and we see that we have two tests,
but only the first one is running.
The second one is skipped.
Now we're going to set the environment variable for CI.
So, CI equal yes and then the same line as before,
python -m pytest -v
and now we see that both tests are running.
That's it.