https://git.ir/
- The CI machine run somewhere in the cloud.
It can be your in-house Jenkins system,
or a service such as CircleCI.
When a test fail, you need some way
to get notified about this failure.
There are many ways
to notify developers about failing tests.
The worst one is email.
I say that no matter what the problem is,
email is not the solution.
Most teams have a central chat room,
and they hook the CI system
to send notifications to this room.
Some teams have a dedicated screen on one of
the walls next to where developers sit.
And it shows the last failing test,
and sometimes the picture of
the developer who caused the failure.
The main thing you should avoid
is notifications getting spammy.
Once you flood developers with messages about CI,
they will ignore them.
Digital practice is to notify only on failing tests
and the first successful test after failing one.
If you have a test that fails a lot,
remove it until you fix it.
It's not worth having developer ignoring all
the tests just because of one flaky test.