https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] Your services are running
somewhere in the cloud.
No screen is attached to the computer running your code.
You need a way to know what's going on.
I've consulted with a company that developed
a cybersecurity suite.
They had version one of the system
and wanted to build version two.
I asked them, "How is version one doing?"
And they said, "It's doing great."
Then I asked, "How do you know?"
They really didn't
and once we placed some logging
we saw many many issues in the system.
Logging is a way to write a piece of information somewhere
and there are several decisions you need to make.
What goes into logs?
What format to use?
How many logs do we store?
Where do we store the logs?
And several other questions.
Before you start logging,
think about these points and others.
What do you want the logging system to provide?
And then structure your logging accordingly.
Another part of your ISO production is metrics.
We'll talk about them in another episode.