https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] Python comes with a standard logging package.
This package is old and stable,
and most developers use it.
So should you.
The logging system is composed
of four main components.
Log records represent a piece of information.
They hold information such as time, level,
message, and more.
Loggers are what your applications interact with.
They provide the method to log a piece of information.
Each logger has one or more handlers attached to it.
A handler is responsible for sending your log message
to a destination.
It can be a file, a socket, HTP API, etc.
Each handler has a formatter that gets a log record
and return a chunk of bytes that represent that log.
So a logger gets a log message,
passes it to the handler, the handler passes the message
to the formatter, gets bytes, and sends these bytes
to the log destination.
Python logging system uses levels.
You set a log level, say warning,
and then every log call with level less than warning,
say info, would not be logged.
The documentation is excellent,
with a lot of examples in how to document.
Spend some time and read it.