https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] There are many ways
to configure the logging system.
You can build LEGO-like the components in code.
Grab a logger, create some handlers, add some formatters.
You can use configuration files in various formats.
And you can use the basic config function
which is the simplest way.
After initial setup,
user code should use the logging system
the same way regardless of the configuration.
It's recommended to have a thin layer of code
on top of the Python logging system.
Your application will not use the logging system directly
and it will make it easier for you
to make changes in configuration and implementation
without having to change the client code.
Here's an example of a configuration file.
It's called log.ini.
We say we have one logger called root,
and then one handler called console
and then one formatter called human.
In line 10 we now refer to the root logger,
so logger_root.
We say the level is INFO and the handler to use
is the console handler.
In line 14, we say the handler console
and in configuration for the console handler,
we say it's a class of StreamHandler
which writes to a stream
using the human formatter and the arguments
are to log to standard output.
And then in line 19, we configure the format
for the human formatter.
In log.py, we write a wrapper around the logging system.
In line 11, we have an environment key,
so we can either use the default log file
or the one that specified in the environment.
The setup function sets up the logging system.
In line 37, we called fileConfig with the config file
and then we set the functions for debug,
info, warning, et cetera, et cetera.
And here is how we use the logging.
This is the HTTP server.
You can see that in line 12 we have log.debug
and in line 24 we have log.info.
And notice that in line 20, we explicitly called log.setup
to make sure that the log is being setup correctly.
And now let's have a look.
So I'm going to run the server python -m nlp
and this is going to start the server.
You see we've got the INFO log message coming out.
But if you are going to call the server,
so curl http://localhost:8080
and then go back to our server,
we get a notification from the built-in HTTP server,
but we don't see our log message.
Let's stop the server,
and then go to our configuration
and we're going to change the level
from INFO to DEBUG.
Once we save this file, we can restart our server
and then we can call it again.
And this time, you see both the INFO message
and the DEBUG message.