https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] In essence, metrics are measurements
that tell us something about our system.
For example, what's the current computer load?
How much time did the query take?
Metrics can be computed from our applications as well.
How many visitors we had in the last hour?
How much did we sell in the last day?
Metrics are usually numerical
and come with at least one extra piece of information,
the time of the measurement.
Metrics can contain more information apart from time,
the server name, the application identifier and more.
Since metrics are time serious,
we can see trends, abnormal values called outliers,
and other interesting insights from them.
In my long career writing services,
metrics has been super valuable.
Today, I can't imagine writing a system without designing
and implementing a metric system on top of it.