https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] There are several types of metrics.
The names and definitions will vary from system to system,
but the ideas are the same.
I'm going to use the definitions
from the popular Prometheus system.
The most common type is a gauge.
It's a value that can go up and down.
For example, duration of a query.
Another type is a counter.
It's a value that goes only up.
For example, the number of errors,
which you can use for managing your error budget.
Other common types are histograms or summary.
They are an aggregation of values over time.
For example, the number of website hits in the last second.
Learn the metric types that are supported
by the system you are using
and use the right type for what you measure.