https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] Metics should be designed and reviewed.
You shouldn't just slap metrics here and there,
when you feel like it.
The guiding principle should be the business impact.
It's very hard to know what an 80% full hard drive
would have on the bottom line,
but it's very easy to know what a drop of 10% in visitors
would do to your bottom line.
You should start from KPIs,
key performance indicators.
They are usually defined by the business people
and are not very technical.
You should strive to get actual numbers
and not vague statements, like,
query's should be fast.
Apart from hard numbers,
realize that you won't hit your KPIs 100% of the time.
You should also have an SLA,
service level agreement, in numbers.
A good example is, query's should return
in less than 200 milliseconds, 99.99% of the time.
Once you have your KPIs,
you can start designing the data
and collection points in your application.
Make metrics part of your review process.
Every time there's a code change or a new feature, ask,
do we need a metric here?
Which one?
How can we edit?