https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] Metrics, are usually not an integral part
of the code.
You don't want to mix metrics code and application code.
Python gives us a nice solution for this, using decorators.
If you're not familiar with decorators,
check out our Python classes
that explain them.
Some of the third-party clients for metric systems,
such as Prometheus,
provide ready-made decorators,
but it's very easy to write your own.
here's an example,
we create a metrics client class which gets a URL
for the matrix server,
line 20 is the rapper, the decorator.
In line 23 we start the time,
in line 24 we set the error value to none,
then in line 26 we call the actual function
and in the final Clause,
which will happen either way
if there was an error, or no, we calculate the duration,
use the logging system, to log the information
in actual cases will send this metric,
to the metric server.
And then in line 31 we check if there was an error,
and if there was, we also log that
which might be another metric.
And here is example, on how to use it.
On line 46 we create such a client,
and then in line 49, we create a function for query,
and decorate it, with this metrics.
In line 57 we create a query that succeeds,
and in line 59 we create a query that will fail.
Let's run the code.
Python metrics.py
and we see that the query the didn't fail took 0.3 seconds,
and the query that failed, failed almost immediately
and we also get an error message.