https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] There are many metric systems out there.
There are self hosted ones,
such as Prometheus, InfluxDB, the ELK Stack, and others.
There are hosted solutions like Splunk, Datadog, and others.
At one time I even used Google Analytics
as my metric system.
Some systems are push based,
meaning your application will push metrics
to the metric system.
Others are pull based and will query your application
for metrics periodically.
No matter what system you use,
learn its capabilities and how it can visualize your data
to gain insights.
Some systems have built in dashboard support
and some require other system, such as Grafana,
to visualize the data.
Once you have your data flowing,
think about what are the important metrics
you'd like to show and where?
Some teams place a big monitor with important metrics
at central location, so everybody can view them.