https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] As time goes,
you will have more and more metrics.
You will have metrics composed of other metrics.
The amount of information will be
more than possibly human to watch,
and even if you don't have that much data,
you won't have a dedicated person watching the metrics 24/7.
What you need is an automated alerting system.
Most of the established metric systems
have a built-in alerting system.
You should know how to use them.
The three main things to consider are, what to alert about?
Sometimes it's easy to know when something went wrong
or requires an action.
For example, the disc is 99% full.
In other cases, it's not that clear.
You should discuss your alerts and plan for them.
In some cases, you will even use machine learning techniques
such as outlier detection
to find out if something went wrong.
I suggest to start with simple thresholds
and use more complicated methods only if there's a need.
The second thing is, where do alerts go to?
Email is the wrong answer.
Some themes send alerts to a special chatroom.
My favorite method is to use a beeper-like system
such as PagerDuty.
No matter the system you select, make sure it's effective.
Once alerts become too frequent, people will ignore them.
I prefer to have no alerts over a flaky alert
that will cause people to ignore all others.
The last thing you should think about is,
who responds to the alert?
You should set a rotation
since you can't have the same person
wake up at 4:00 a.m. to fix problems.
An nice system I've used before
is to have a primary and secondary responders,
each doing a week rotation
that changes in the middle of the week.
At the rotation, the secondary becomes the primary,
and a new team member becomes the secondary.
It's a good practice to have all developers
practicing the rotation.
Once you get woken up at 3:00 a.m. due to a bug,
it changes the way you write code.