https://git.ir/
(upbeat music)
- [Man] Here's my solution.
In line eight, we write the decorator.
In line nine, we add the attribute called num errors
to the function object.
And, initialize it to zero.
In line 12, we write the wrapper function.
It will try to run the function.
And, in line 16 we check and if there was an exception.
And, if there was an exception,
in line 18 we incriminate the numbers of errors.
In line 19 and 20, we log.
And here is the uses example, we decorate the div function
with our reports error.
And in the main, we call it once, without an error.
And, line 33 with an error.
Python app.py, and we see that the div is called twice,
but only on the second time, we get the error report.