https://git.ir/
- Your code is ready.
Now it's time to move it to production and run it.
You'd like to give the operations team an easy way
to run and manage your application.
One way is to create a Python script just
for running your application.
This approach has two problems.
The first, is that you need to tell people
of the Python script and where to find it.
The second, is that over time
you find yourself with too many scripts.
Python allows you to run a module
as if they are scripts using the -m switch,
and I find it a great way to run applications as well.
Let's see an example from the Python standard library first.
The calendar module supports the -m.
So Python, -m, calendar,
and then we want to see the calendar
for January 2020 and we have it.
Now let's see how you can use it in your code
using the built-in Argparse library.
So we are using the Argparse,
and we also using the environment.
The usual order of parameters is command line
that overrides environment, that overrides the default.
And the way we do it is in line 17,
we try to get values from the environment
and provide the default value
for the host and then for the port.
And then we use an ArgumentParser
and create subparsers on line 23.
One subparser is the one for the start command in line 25.
And here, we had an argument for the host,
and for the port, which uses the default one.
And you have another command for a health check,
which gets the URL for the server in an optional timeout.
Line 39, we parse the arguments
and call the func value,
which will call the corresponding function
because calling functions are very simple.
In line eight to start,
with the start from the HtDP module,
which is our own module.
And in line 12 we use the health check from
the checks model again, inside our application.
You can see the imports on line five.
And now let's run it.
So Python, -m, bugs,
and we can do a -help to see what helped here.
And we see it says you have a start and a health.
So let's do start -h,
you it tell us to help for the start command.
We get a possible host and a port.
So Python, -m, bugs start,
and this will start the server,
which is running on localhost: 8080.
So we're going to run pythom, -m, bugs
and health for the health check.
And it returns successfully without an error.
If you're curious, you can see
that the server got the request for
the -health URL.
By adding -m support,
you'll have a single script to manage your application.