https://git.ir/
- There are many things that can go wrong
while deploying your code.
Let's go over some of the more common ones
and how you can avoid them.
You might use a new package
and forget to add it to the requirements file.
Or you might use a package in a version
that differs from production environment.
The solution is to have the CI system run tests
in fresh environment every time.
This will catch missing requirements.
The second part of package mismatch
is solved by creating a new virtual environment
for every new deployment.
Your deployment might have configuration issues.
For example, broke name of the database server.
The solution is to run a health check
once the application starts
and to add metrics to applications.
This way, you will know quickly
if something goes wrong.
No matter have much tests, bugs will get into production.
You should be able to detect bugs
as soon as possible.
The solution is to have metrics and alerts
on your code.
As a developer, you should incorporate
metrics in your development process.
Some people even run periodic health checks
in production, to make sure everything is okay.
The other thing you need to have
is a way to quickly roll back a bad release.
This is more in operation hands
but you need to be involved.
Writing deployable code will make you a good friend
with the operation team
and will let you sleep soundly at night.
If you like to read a bit more, I highly recommend
these articles by Ron Tavory.