https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] In this episode we'll discuss
several deployment methods,
these methods are not tied to specific platform
such as, kubernetes AWS or others.
And these guidelines can be applied to each platform,
let's start with the method you don't want to use
the big bang
in this method, once you have a new version
you take down the current code and start the new one.
This method is very risky,
and how to get back from try to avoid it.
The second method is known as blue-green deployment
in this method, you have two production systems running,
the blue environment is currently serving users
and the green one is idle,
once you have a new code
you deployed to the green environment,
run some tests and then direct traffic
to the green environment, making it the current blue.
In this approach it's easy to roll back from mistakes,
we direct traffic back to the old blue and you're done.
The next deployment methods are pretty similar,
they are rolling and canary,
the idea is, that you deploy the code
to part of your server and wait to see how the code behaves.
once you're confident, deploy the new code to more server
and observe again
eventually all of your servers,
will run the new version of the code.
In all of these methods blue-green,
canary enrolling, you must have a good
monitoring analytic system in place,
to know how the new code behaves.
Don't forget to mark releases
on the metrics visualization system.
you also need a way to rollback bad releases,
it might seems like a lot of work
to get these systems in place.
But they will save you in the long run.