https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] No matter how much you test,
some bugs will get into production.
If they are not that bad,
you might want to fix them
and deploy the fix.
However, sometimes your best option is to revert back
to an earlier good version.
To support running back,
you need to have a system in place.
And if you think about it,
running back bad code
is just like deploying a new version.
You have code counting production,
and you want to replace it with another version.
This means you need to version your code,
which means you need to use a version control system
such as GET.
The typical way of versioning is by using tags.
Once your code is in a state
where it's ready for a release,
you add a version type.
It's recommended to use what's known as semantic versioning,
major, minor, and patch level.
The patch is reserved for bug fixes only.
Minor versions are mostly for new features
and should be backward compatible.
Major version means you're doing a breaking change,
and these releases are usually more risky
and involve more work.
Back to reverting.
Once you have tagged your code,
you can always get that version of the code
and deploy it.
Make sure to version your dependencies as well.
They are part of that application as much as your code.
Make sure you can roll back your code
and even do a practice run once in a while.
I can guarantee you'll revert a version
at one point or another.