https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] Your deployment should be automated.
It will prevent you from forgetting steps,
and will get you closer to continuous delivery.
There are many tools for running tasks on servers.
Ansible, Puppet, Chef, and many others.
All of them are great tools.
But take time and effort to learn.
I usually start with a simpler tool called Frabic.
It's a simple system that lets you define commands,
and run them on remote servers over SSH, secure shell.
Using Fabric, you write tasks in FabFile.py file.
And use the Fab tool to run them.
Here is an example.
I have a fabfile.py for our Elmer code.
We import in line seven the task decorator.
And we import the version which is 1.2.3 from Elmer.
And here is our task.
We define it in line 26,
and decorate it in line 25 with a task decorator.
In line 28, we create the application directory.
In line 30, we create a virtual environment.
In line 32 and 33, we copy over the requirements file
and pip install the requirements.
Then, in line 35 we copy over the code,
and in line 37, 38, we unpack the code.
And last, in line 39 and 40, we change directory
to the application directory.
And run gunicorn with our application on port 8080.
Let's see how it works.
So fab -H, which is the host,
and the host for my deployment is called elmer1
and then we say deploy.
And now we can check that it's working.
curl http, elmer1
port 8080.
Let's say the version, and we see that it's running
Elmer version 1.2.3.
Once the code is running,
you can start directing traffic to it.
Depending on the deployment method you're using.
If you find out that Fabric is not enough for you.
Check out our courses on Ansible, Puppet, or Chef.