https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] Continuous delivery means that
if tests are passing in your continuous integration system
your code is automatically deployed production.
Continuous delivery is a hard goal
and it will take time to get to.
I'd start without it, and only when you have a good
grasp of how manual deployment works and also a good
trust in your testing, move to continuous delivery.
Here are some points to consider
on the way to continuous delivery.
Testing.
How can I have a test rate that will be
good enough for automatic deployment?
How can I mimic production in testing?
Monitoring.
What are the metrics I need to monitor?
How can I run self-checks?
And how should I roll back a bad release?
Who should be alerted?
Automation.
How can I automate the process?
How do I version my code?
How can I update load balancers
to direct traffic to new code?
The benefits of continuous delivery are great.
New features are deployed quickly
and you get feedback from actual customers.
Also, your team will be happier,
since code they write goes quickly to production.