https://git.ir/
- [Miki] I hope you found the information
in this course valuable.
It embeds more than 20 years of my experience.
Now it's up to you.
When going back to work,
try to think how you can improve your team
and how you can make your code production ready.
Start little.
Add some logging here, some metrics there.
Start a code review,
and step by step you'll have a more efficient team
and new friends from the Operations team.
If you like to learn more about Python,
we have many courses at all level.
I tried to be platform agnostic in this course,
but you have a specific platform and tools you are using.
Go on and get familiar with them.
AWS, Google Cloud, Azure, Docker, ELK Stack,
there's so much to learn in this area.
And of course, we have many courses
in these subjects as well.
And always feel free to reach us out at 353solutions.
We'd love to hear from you and help you get better.