https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] Modern applications
are composed of many parts.
This means the logs are spread all over the place.
To solve this issue
there are several log aggregator applications.
These applications aggregate logs form several locations
into one central place
and allow you to view and search the logs.
There are solutions you host yourself.
The most common one is the ELK Stack.
The ELK Stack is composed of elastic search
which is a database for your logs.
Logstash which gets logs from various sources
and stores them in elastic.
It is slowly being replaced
with another set of collectors called beats.
In Kibana which is a visual dashboard
and also lets you run searches over the logs.
There are a host of solutions such as
Splunk, Loggly, Sentry and others.
No matter the solution you chose,
here are some points you need to consider
when using a log aggregator.
Log retention policy.
How much time do we store the logs?
A lot of logs means a lot of storage
which means a lot of money that you're going to pay.
Log delivery.
Do we sends logs over the network
over TCP, UDP, in files?
I tend to use files,
since the file system is more robust than the network.
Log format.
Most of these will use some JSON format,
make sure to be compatible.
Log fields.
Design the log fields so we can query them.
For example do you want the host name in the log record.
Context.
A user request will span several services,
have some ID that is added to all the actions
that come from the same request.
Make a survey of what you need from your log aggregator.
Shop around and run a proof of concept
with one or two of the most promising candidates.
It will become a crucial piece of your infrastructure,
so chose wisely.