https://git.ir/
- Whether you're bringing on full-time permanent staff
or finding an individual or a company with short-term needs,
you need to pause for a moment and become familiar
with the variety of UX jobs and skillsets,
so that you can get exactly the professionals you need
to lead your products to business success.
I'll start by saying that this variety of jobs and skillsets
fall primarily into three buckets.
Those involve design.
Those involve research.
And those involve strategy.
It would be most simple if every type of UX job
fell purely into one of these three buckets.
While admittedly this is not the case,
it's still possible to generally group skillsets
you may need for your team.
Let's now take a quick dive into these three skillsets.