https://git.ir/
- Designed-based jobs in UX
aren't just designed for the sake of beauty,
but designed for the people
that will be interacting with your products.
Most likely you need design
for something that at some point is seen on a screen,
so design is often related to websites or apps,
although can involve wearables and the Internet of Things.
And design can certainly leave the screen as well
for real life interaction with products,
services, and people.
An interaction design career
focuses on how a user interacts with elements on the screen
in order to proceed through the website or app.
Can a user understand what they are seeing
as they use your app
and know how to move onto the next step?
An information architecture career or skillset
centers on the organization of information
that a user interacts with.
That can be both the information that is visible,
and the bits of information behind the scenes
that drive the flow of content.
Think about the options available from a website menu,
or think about how you filter down to a listing
of exactly the product you need
when you're shopping for that perfect little something.
Visual design uses color, imagery, space, and typography
to design in a way that makes sense
and is appreciated by users.
Ever notice when a poor color choice
or an awkwardly-chosen font
causes you to move closer to your phone
to figure out your next step.
Technical communication,
and along with what's more recently referred to
as UX writing
focuses on the design of words throughout the interface.
Those perfect just in time instructions
will make all the difference
when you need to do something complex
like file and pay your taxes.
And service design,
which has an ever-growing prominence around the world,
takes UX beyond the screen into every touchpoint
a customer has with a company.
For example, in person experiences in a brock and mortar
or maybe glass retail outlet.
Or a phone conversation with a call center representative.