https://git.ir/
- When it comes to the research bucket,
there are activities that involve research,
that is interactions with and observations of,
actual and representative product users.
And there are activities that involve evaluation,
which compares a product with expected UX best practices.
The most typical job type and skill set to do this work,
is my UX specialty, that of user researcher.
As a user researcher, I've gone
literally all over the United States
and occasionally to other countries
to meet with the right users and understand their needs.
I've met with disaster survivors
after their homes were damaged or destroyed.
I've met with car buyers, tax payers, small business owners,
truckers, sales people.
They all have different needs
and different reactions to technological products.
Understanding those needs and reactions
leads to better offerings that can really help them.
In addition, a research skill set,
which can also be a stand alone career,
is that of an accessibility specialist.
Accessibility is focuses on making sure that products
adhere to international and country specific standards
for universal usability, usable by everyone,
regardless of any disability.
What if someone who was blind
was told they couldn't make online purchases?
What if someone who was deaf
was told they couldn't watch an instructional video?
This is what happens when products are created inaccessibly.
Lastly in the research bucket is human factors.
When I started my career many years ago,
human factors broadly meant what we now call UX.
Today, however, it's used to refer specifically
to research of physical products,
often focused on safety and comfort.
Think about an airplane cockpit or a car.
Now that we've covered design and research,
we have one more big bucket to discuss, strategy.