https://git.ir/
- Our third bucket, strategy,
winds its way through both design
and research skillsets and careers.
But strategy has careers and skillsets of its own right.
UX strategy ties business goals
to the use of products by intended users.
Are you able to achieve both happy business owners
and simultaneously happy customers
with products that actually lead to business success?
Then there is content strategy which makes sure
that content and messaging are consistent
in tone and voice across a product.
It is understandable by the intended audience
and align with business goals.
Have you ever found it jarring when going
from one page of a website that informs you
with succinct bits of information
and the next page overwhelms you with wordiness?
Beyond just the interaction, customer experience or CX,
makes sure that there is strategic alignment
between all customer touchpoints in the business,
seeking to improve experience and financial success.
I bet you've seen an email
or text recently asking you likely you are
to recommend a company to a friend.
That's customer experience.