https://git.ir/
- We've only lightly touched on these three buckets
and associated jobs and skillsets at a very high level.
And as you can start to see,
sometimes there's a little overlap in those defined roles.
If you're looking to hire someone,
start by figuring out what you need,
and do a little bit of research to confirm
what kind of position will help you fit those needs.
I had a client recently
who developed a web based application
that was a total failure among the intended users.
They thought that by doing user acceptance testing,
a typical development centric alignment activity,
was user research.
They didn't understand why this research wasn't working.
What they needed was research with the people
who actually use the product.
They thought the developers
hired to do a vague UX/UI development process
would get them good user experience.
But all stakeholders meant by UX/UI
was an attractive user interface, not a usable one.
They still have a lot ahead of them,
but as their user researcher, I've gone to five cities
and met with their actual users over nine days.
I've documented what they need to do,
and I'm now working with the UX design staff
to create interactions
that will actually work for these users.
But this only came about because they realized
that they really truly needed to understand
the necessary UX skillsets
and find those who have expertise in those skillsets
to do the work.
If you want to get one step deeper
than what I've talked about here
so that you too can better understand
what you need for product success,
check out my Planning a Career in User Experience course
where we spend half the course expanding on these job types.
Or look at my book, the UX Careers Handbook
with about a quarter of the book, over 80 pages of detail,
about these career types.
Now that we've covered what UX is
and the buckets of skillsets,
let's turn our attention away
from the details of the UX work
and instead towards the people who are doing that work.