https://git.ir/
- There is UX work to do and someone has to do it.
Maybe this is an employee or several employees.
Maybe the work is done by a contractor,
whether a freelancer or a moonlighter
who has a regular day job.
Or maybe you're using an agency or a larger company
to contract out the work.
There are certainly pros and cons to each option.
In theory, in a world of agile development,
UX should be as regular, iterative and ongoing
as any other job.
And maybe times that is true.
If you have ongoing full-time UX work,
the most economical way to get that work done
is by bringing on a full-time hire.
Hiring someone as a regular full-time employee
of your company gives you the most control
over their work and their time.
In return for a level of loyalty and commitment,
you as the employer should commit to invest
in those employees, and help them to grow professionally.
That said, there are a number of reasons
that you might consider a contract position instead.
UX is hot, and there may simply not be enough skilled talent
to go around, making it hard to find employees.
Or given these hot fields, you may find
that limited available talent makes the hiring process
take longer than you're anticipating.
And you need someone to fill in the gaps
as you continue your search.
Or you may have irregular development cycles,
so UX work, such as your user research,
isn't always needed or budgeted.
Or maybe there's already a UX team,
but you have some overflow design work
that needs doing urgently.
In cases like these,
a contractor can fill the gap with expertise.
A freelancer is an individual contractor
that represents their own business interest
and functions as a limited contracting resource.
I say limited contracting resource because their ability
to help is defined by how much one person can do.
As long as a designated freelancer is available,
and as long as a business is willing to offer
that person appropriate rate of pay, which may admittedly be
higher for UX expertise than you might expect,
it's possible to rapidly bring on a level of UX expertise
without a need for long-term commitment.
For example, I spent a decade as a freelancer
focused largely in UX research and evaluation.
While in my dream world research is done very regularly,
this is not always the case.
So in actuality, the user research that I do
is well suited to freelancing.
I often find that I'm called on to jump into a project,
help assess some user needs,
or perhaps how usable an existing product is,
and then jump out after meeting the urgent needs.
And then, I don't hear from the company again
for a few weeks, or maybe a few months, until they,
again, have an urgent need and no external experts.
While I like the term freelancer, I'm also a micro-business.
I'm not the only one who works directly
for my company Lebsontech.
And to deal with varying bandwidth needs,
I've taken on subcontractors, others freelancers
and small businesses, as I manage projects
and typically take a lead role.
A UX moonlighter is a special kind of freelancer
who also has a day job, where they work full time.
Moonlighters expand the options you have on who can help you
with your UX work, and many have a good level
of UX expertise as well.
The downside is that since they have a full-time day job,
which may not be so flexible,
they may need to work exclusively off hours.
And their first loyalty is going to be
to their primary employer no matter how much you want it
to be otherwise.
But that said, you may find moonlighters
are a little bit cheaper
than their full-time, freelancing counterparts.
All these options are focused at person level,
but what if you have a project that you want to hand off
to a team to get that project done?
That's where a larger agency or consulting firm comes in.
Let's now explore this a bit more.