https://git.ir/
- You may have a UX-oriented project
that needs to get done
but requires more than one person.
In fact, the project can require a whole team
of people complete with someone to manage that team.
Agencies are likely more expensive
than hiring individual freelancers
but when you need a lot of UX expertise quickly,
hiring a larger agency or consulting firm
gives you that option.
Working with agencies can be more complex,
at at the beginning
and you're also likely to have the least control
over the process.
Agencies have to balance their projects
with all their clients,
with some staff dedicated to you for the duration
but other who only come and go based
on their other responsibilities.
An agency could supply the whole UX project team,
all with expert skills
inclusive of research, design and strategy
in a more reliable way
than you may be able to find
when only trying to pull in a freelancer
or when hiring a single employee.
Bringing on agencies and larger consulting firms,
however, introduces a different set of processes
than bringing individuals in any context.
In a while, we'll talk about RFPs
or request for proposals
and why these are better suited for businesses
that are big enough to handle regular proposal writing.
These larger businesses also provide you
with another option, staff augmentation.
Staff augmentation means you can get a person full time
for a long duration
such that they seem to be no different
than an employee of yours
except that you pay another company
and that company pays the individual.
Whereas freelance contractors
are often hired per project,
staff augmentation can be much longer term than that
just like you would hire an employee for the long term.
When UX talent is hard to find,
staff augmentation basically takes
this responsibility off your plate
and lets someone else find you
who you need and they take responsibility for them
but stick with staff augmentation from a larger business.
Taking on an individual freelancer
for staff augmentation
could put you on the wrong side of the law.
Here in the United States,
the IRS has a number of tests
for businesses in terms of the level
of behavioral and financial control
that a business has over an individual.
The IRS also looks for justification
that the individual is acting as a business
that promotes services with a certain level of autonomy.
While I'm not a lawyer
and in no way giving you legal advice,
I would say that pulling an individual freelancer
into a staff augmentation role
may be harder to justify against the criteria
of what constitutes an employee.
However, using a larger agency,
particularly one that is essentially set up
to provide UX temps for a short
or long duration may be your best bet
when you truly don't want to hire an employee
but need a person full time for a longer duration
and rest assured that those types of companies do exist.
Now you're ready to find someone,
so let's consider whether you need a generalist
or an expert.