https://git.ir/
- We talked earlier about UX not being a single skill set
or a career, but rather a whole collection of skills
that form a variety of career pathways.
Of course, in an ideal world with unlimited budget,
you could bring in experts
to cover each type of skill set that you need,
but maybe you only have enough budget for a single hire,
or you don't have enough work
for a different unique UX skill set.
So you may want to find everything you need in one person,
the UX generalist.
There's nothing wrong with wanting a UX generalist
who can cover your business in multiple areas.
If you're looking for a junior staffer,
someone near the beginning of their career,
you can find a generalist.
There is no expectation of expertise,
and within the framework
of their interests and inclinations,
you will have the opportunity to shape this person
to exactly what your business needs.
If you're looking for a UX expert however,
someone who can lead the charge
to get a particular aspect of your work done,
be it design, research or strategy,
that's when your desire for a generalist
could be in conflict with the need for acquired expertise.
It takes a few years to really become an expert
in any given UX discipline,
to experience the ins and outs of methods,
software and approaches.
The more UX skill sets you need to account for
in a single person, the longer a period of time is needed
to acquire that expertise.
For example, someone who has been doing
heavy interaction design work for five years,
probably has a solid understanding of interaction design.
If someone has been split evenly between interaction design
and user research for the past five years,
then while they likely have reasonable skills in both,
they are not as experienced an interaction designer
as the person doing this exclusively.
Now mix in information architecture skills, visual design
and imagine those are split evenly.
How much expertise would you get?
Oh, to make matters worse, let's imagine that you decide
some front end coding experience is needed as well.
No, front end coding really isn't UX,
but it's often thrown in with UX job recs anyway.
So now, you have a valid generalist, fine,
but you don't have an expert in anything.
If you didn't need the expertise then okay,
but expertise counts for something.
Speaking personally, while I'm happy to tell you
that anyone can do user research,
I make my living off user research expertise.
Because I spent so many years
almost exclusively as a user researcher,
people hire me to propose exactly
the right kind of research for their needs,
to conduct that research in the right way,
to appropriately gather information
while dealing on the fly with varied
and unanticipated situations,
to record the critical data points
that answer the research questions
and to properly analyze that data.
So yes, a generalist with some research
among many other skill sets is a real thing,
but this person is not going to be anywhere near
the level of expertise of a research expert.
No matter how much you want it all,
just stay aware of what is realistic and what isn't.