https://git.ir/
- There is no one right answer
to whether you should bring on permanent staff
or freelancers or larger businesses.
You may find that your best option
is to mix and match towards business success.
If you are going to mix and match,
it's critical that you have leadership
that really understand the entire UX framework,
and can manage what needs to get accomplished.
These leaders can support both directly and indirectly,
the growth of hires and the integration of those
who are only on board a short time.
Leadership could take the form
of a small business owner,
a project or program manager who has strong UX knowledge,
or a dedicated UX lead.
That leadership position, whatever it may be,
is likely to be a full-time hire itself,
but could also be a contract position,
if for example, it's only of limited duration.
If you're going to hire, pull in novice generalists,
that the UX leadership can shape,
and hire experts who cover some critical areas
that you're going to need,
as well as mentor the novice generalist
in these specific areas.
Now, as needed,
sprinkle in UX freelancers for shorter periods
when work overflows existing bandwidth.
The freelancer should also likely be experts.
If you do hire junior UX staff
and don't have more experienced permanent staff available,
your freelancers can also be contracted
to help mentor the junior staff.
In this way, you are increasing your in-house capabilities
for the future.
I can tell you that as a freelance researcher,
while I love to get repeat business,
it's also really rewarding to be able
to help UX novices grow their skills
and blossom into experts in their own right.
If you have a project
that requires many experts quickly to get the job done,
pull in a larger company to help you.
But again, figure out if there's a way to leverage
that larger company to help grow the skills and knowledge
of your staff along the way.
Ultimately, as your UX needs shift, grow,
and sometimes shrink,
it's going to be a mix of employment types
when you are likely to find the best balance
for business success.