https://git.ir/
- The supply and demand ratio
often favors talent over employers.
Employers and recruiters need to make a pitch
that their business provides awesome opportunities
as places to work, and has great people to work with.
Employees want an employer that really understands
and values UX, and understands the difference between UX
and other aspects of the creation process, like development.
They want an employer that understands that there are
multiple skill sets within UX,
even if the employer needs more than one skill set,
and even if they themselves represent more than one
of those skill sets.
They want an employer who values people as much as they do,
and an employer that values them and supports them
becoming better UX professionals,
helping them grow their knowledge and skills.
Those skills need to grow with work that challenges them
to think creatively as they make a difference.
And they want to be able to work
with like-minded individuals, others who care about UX
as much as they do.
Think about it, you only have a moment to tell people
why your business is awesome as you pitch
coming to work for the business.
Maybe at a networking event,
and maybe when they're actually in front of you
for a job interview.
As you start to think about what you would say,
here are some recommendations.
When you make an elevator pitch,
frame your specific staffing needs in a way that shows
that you understand what user experience is about.
Are you specific?
What exciting projects are you working on?
How will your corporate mission resonate with the people?
Did you think about what the office environment is like?
Do you mention your exceptional lifestyle benefits?
Did you include how you're a place that supports
both work and play?
Your pitch is also about you.
What makes it clear that you know what you're talking about
and that you have legitimate UX knowledge
and the expertise necessary to hire what's really needed?
Practice your elevator pitch in phone conversations
and in person.
Iterate your pitch at meet-ups and events.
Carefully watch the reaction of listeners
to figure out what is inspiring to them
and what causes their eyes to glaze over.
No matter what, be honest.
Don't try to sell what your business is not.
Don't try to sell work that you don't have.
An inspiring but inaccurate pitch could get people in,
but misaligned expectations will cause you to lose
those good people and generate ill will very quickly.
So stay honest and inspiring and pull in those job seekers.