https://git.ir/
- At some point, you're going to want to post a job,
a title that encourages prospects to read further
along with an enticing job description.
Clearly, the title and job description
are critical pieces of finding the employees that you need.
And truth be told,
it's not necessarily just employees that you're posting for.
You can post for temporary talent, too.
Before we get into the specifics of the job posting,
it's important to figure out what you really want.
Earlier, we talked at a high level
about the varying types of UX jobs and skill sets
clustered into design, research, and strategy.
You shouldn't try to get it all in one person,
particularly if you are looking for a level of expertise.
Instead, focus on your core needs,
the UX superpowers that you are really looking for,
along with those UX skills which would be nice to have,
but aren't critical.
Let's start with the title.
If your primary skill set is interaction design,
then title your job interaction designer or UX designer.
If it's critical to you that you get someone
with both interaction design and research skills,
then you can use interaction designer/user researcher,
or UX designer/researcher.
Beware of going too generic.
You may think that user experience specialist
gives you the Big 10,
but it doesn't tell potential applicants
what kind of skill sets you're looking for.
Also, if you want a UX professional,
please avoid calling the job UX/UI.
The UI part muddies the waters.
Sometimes it's used to indicate visual design skills.
Other times,
it can mean that you're actually looking for someone
with front-end developer skills.
In short, if you call a job UX/UI,
it could look to a job seeker
that you don't know what you're looking for.
I understand that you may have a limited budget,
but again, don't try to get UX expertise
and development expertise in the same person.
You can get solid development and some UX,
or solid UX and some development,
but truly getting expertise in both is difficult.
Seeing coding expertise in a job title or description
will frighten off a lot of potential applicants
who do have the appropriate UX expertise.
You also need to specify a level of seniority.
Feel free to use terms like junior, mid-level, or senior,
but keep in mind that these terms
don't mean the same thing to everyone.
Many people would agree that titles
like director and principal or even vice president
are above senior,
but again, those terms don't have a single definition.
And no matter what,
don't use internal classification
to designate seniority on a public job posting.
I recently got an email from a recruiter
that tacked on the number four to the job title,
as if I'm supposed to know what kind of seniority
is implied from a UX designer four.
Now let's think about the job description.
Keep your critical skills as narrow as you can
within that UX umbrella,
and then expand in a follow-up nice-to-have section.
But even that nice-to-have section
shouldn't expand too wide,
or it may look like you're looking
for that elusive UX unicorn,
that magical creature who's an expert in everything.
It's a big turnoff to experienced job-seekers.
Your description needs to be specific about job functions.
Feel free to mention tools you use.
For example, a design team may already be using InVision
or the various Adobe products.
But be cautious about requiring specific software expertise,
which can be an instant turnoff
to a very experienced professional
who hasn't interacted with a piece of software
but has lots of experience on similar tools.
It's much easier to translate knowledge
between software products
than it is to learn new software concepts from scratch.
If you have headcount for two UX professionals,
consider the possibility that you may find
one person with some of the necessary UX skills
and another person with the other UX skills,
so keep your descriptions open enough
that you can leave yourself flexibility
to work with whomever happens
to be in a job market at that time.
Also, feel free to mention that you are looking
for specialists with a subset of areas of expertise
for your master list,
and make it clear that these areas of expertise
may be covered over multiple hires.
Oh, just one more thing.
There are a handful of certifications out there,
so which one do you request
when you post your job description?
I will strongly and emphatically say none.
Do not require or even prefer a certification.
Certification of UX professionals,
when there are widely diverse skill sets
and no single definition
of what it means to be a UX professional,
is highly controversial.
Don't even suggest that this matters to you.
Instead, focus on asking for a level
of UX knowledge and expertise
that match the seniority and expertise required of the role.