https://git.ir/
- Posting a position to job boards
can be great for pulling in full-time hires,
and can be useful for temporary work, too.
But there are other good ways to get visibility
when seeking UX contractors,
and especially creative agencies.
As we discussed earlier,
you should try to become a part of the UX community
by participating in UX events
and being part of social media.
This builds you direct access
to potential future job candidates.
In addition, having a ready pool of freelancers
in advance of your needs,
particularly those who don't usually get booked
on full-time, long-term engagements,
is very valuable.
How do companies find me?
Largely, they find me for smaller projects
through ad hoc methods,
such as being referred by those
that already know and have worked with me.
Sometimes they find me on LinkedIn,
presumably with a keyword search for research freelancers.
Sometimes I get contacted directly through LinkedIn,
Twitter, or Facebook by existing connections.
By and large as a freelancer,
I've found companies have a lot of success booking me
through these methods,
as well as finding other freelancer types.
Knowing agencies with larger talent pools
that they can assign to projects as needed
is certainly great for future planning, too,
especially when urgent needs present themselves.
For larger projects, however you want to define that,
you may want to consider more formal methods
of securing talent.
In these cases, you may consider seeking out UX contractors
with an RFP, or request for proposals.
Every now and again,
I get a request from a business
that goes something like this.
"We've heard great things about your user research efforts.
"We'd like to consider engaging you.
"Just complete a response to our proposal,
"and we'll consider you."
The problem I find is that
if I'm heavily involved in another project at the time,
such as a usability study,
I don't have the time needed
to give a proper response to the proposal.
I often end up declining to respond for lack of time,
or passing it on to a larger business
and letting them know I'm happy
to be part of the project if they'd like.
So on the one hand,
RFPs are a great way to get UX-oriented companies
to bid on an engagement,
so that you can get an apples-to-apples comparison
on methods, staffing, and pricing.
On the other hand,
you may be limiting yourself to bigger businesses
with the dedicated staff needed
to regularly respond to RFPs.
I'm not saying that you shouldn't use RFPs,
simply that they're better suited
to target larger businesses
that can spend time properly responding to them.
Finally, consider your options when you post job listings.
You can post for full-time jobs,
but you can also post short-term and contract roles.
LinkedIn is a great resource for these postings,
as well as Indeed
and a number of other general hiring sites.
There are UX-specific job boards as well.
Sites like UX Job Board, UX Jobs 24/7, and more.
You can get a longer list on my UX Careers Handbook website.
The advantage of these sites
is that they are all UX, all the time,
and they attract UX freelancers, too.
The downside is that even though
they get the right kind of traffic,
they're usually non-locally targeted.
The less frequent fresh job postings
also mean that those freelancers and contractors
aren't necessarily checking in too regularly
when they're hungry for work.