https://git.ir/
- When I've given talks about UX careers in the past,
one of the common frustrations I here about
from those new to UX is the struggle to get their first job.
They don't understand.
If there are so many UX jobs out there,
why are they having trouble getting hired
as a varied junior UX practitioner?
The fundamental problem is
that while there are many UX jobs,
there's also the desire the desire to bring on staff
who have at least some professional UX experience.
If you are pooling in senior-level or contract resources,
you would expect to pay them well.
But you would have people
who can immediately hit the ground running.
However, there is no absolute playbook
on exactly how UX is practiced.
So the way they do their work may be different
than the way your business wants work done.
You have the opportunity to shape UX novices
into professionals that you need.
Yes, you have to be willing
to invest your time and resources,
but you can bring these resources on for a lower cost.
And you'll have staff who can provide needed support to you
and other existing resources,
as these other staff go about doing
their expert-level UX work.
That's not to say they should be starting
completely from scratch.
I'd recommend you'd look for someone
with some type of UX education,
be it from a university, a supplemental business program,
or clear ethnician that they have
really take and the initiative
to learn from LinkedIn Learning or other online resources.
You might be the person that helps them launch
their amazing UX career,
that can supply them with the basic resources
and give them the confidence they need
through appropriate mentoring and training.
In return, you not only get the satisfaction
of helping them be who they were meant to be
as a UX professional,
but you also get a person who you've shaped
to fit your business needs.