https://git.ir/
(uplifting music)
- When I was young, when I was a teenager,
I had this quote in my bedroom.
Right across the door it said,
"Some things must be believed to be seen."
This quote, even as a teenager, it felt right to me.
It felt like something meaningful
that was driving my life even back then.
But I didn't really understand how.
It's all about saying that you can control luck.
Everyone really has the power to improve the serendipity
of their career, and it's really all about meeting people.
It's interacting with people.
This is the way that you can control your career
by setting lots of things in motion.
It doesn't matter whether you're a freelancer
or whether you're a longtime employee,
but at some point, there's going to be a new job.
There's going to be new opportunities.
There's going to be new adventures,
however adventurous you want to get, related to your work.
And it's all about setting everything in motion.
It's about meeting people in different places.
It's about meeting people at different times.
It's about increased exposure to others.
In my own career, I've found that all the work I've done,
and all the projects that I've gotten,
have been traceable to some meeting or some interaction,
or some conversation, often in person,
sometimes virtual too, as well, or through social media.
But it's traceable.
I don't respond to requests for proposals, or RFPs.
I really just get work by meeting people, that's it.
My business development time is meeting people.
It's about caring about the other people too.
It's not just about, "What can I get from you?"
It's about, "I care about you as a person,"
and I'm relationship building.
I'm building this relationship with you and you and you,
to the extent, and it's not about,
"Oh, sorry, you can't do anything for me.
"Bye, I'm off to the next person."
Because, really, thinking practically, you never know.
It's just getting to know people
and building those relationships.
(uplifting music)