https://git.ir/
- Once you've identified someone as a potential employee
of your company, or a valuable freelance resource,
how do you figure out if they are really right for you?
Someone that is newer to UX may not have a UX brand yet.
But someone who is coming to you who has experience,
whether an employee or a contractor,
should be self-branded as a UX professional.
First off, does their LinkedIn profile
and their resume articulate a solid set of UX experiences?
And do those experiences tell the story of a UX professional
who does UX activities within the design, research,
and strategy framework?
And without too much time away from UX in the narrative.
If you Google that person, you should ideally
be able to see a UX brand.
Preferably with evidence that they've been associated
with UX activities, have some semblance
of UX represented on social media.
And perhaps have blogged about UX or even spoken at events.
That's not to say that someone who doesn't have a brand
that is steep in UX is wrong for you,
but positive UX branding provides you clues
that this is someone who wants to stay on top of things
and be connected to UX knowledge, ideas, and people.
UX isn't a static field
but doesn't have standardized continue education either.
Look for evidence through what you can gather online
or simply by talking with them
that no matter what the level of experience,
they show an interest in growing and learning.
And that they are excited to try new things
within their respective slice or slices of UX.
When you look at a portfolio,
make sure that you are presented in some way
with a narrative that tells you
that they not only understand the UX framework,
but also specific skills to a level
that matches the target expectations of the position.
If they're describing their portfolio to you in real time,
listen for that narrative as well.
What is the story of their experiences?
How do users fit into the story?
How does their story mesh with your needs?
Finally, remember that UX
does not have a single body of knowledge
or a single set of terminology.
Or, involve a single type of practice
within any particular slice of skills.
So even if someone comes in as an expert,
but is missing one or two of your required experiences,
don't discount them just yet.
If they solidly understand what UX is about,
what they are doing, and who they are doing it for,
the end users, then consider
that one or two missing experiences
can likely be picked up with use.