https://git.ir/
- How do you assess whether a business that you identify
is actually an organization worth bringing on to help you?
First off, look at what they tell you.
If they write a proposal for the work,
how do they prioritize UX?
Look at the language they use.
Do they talk about user experience throughout the process,
and ideally in an iterative way?
Or does it look like UX was thrown in haphazardly,
just to win the bid?
If they talk about past performance,
is UX clearly integrated into those projects?
Look at their website.
Is UX prioritized there?
If the business is large enough, look at job posts
on their website, or do a quick search for job postings,
and see if they hire for specific UX types of jobs.
See if you can find UX people at that company on LinkedIn.
And make sure that they too are properly branded
as UX professionals, especially true if you know who
is being proposed for your project.
Even googling the company could get you some clues
as to how established they are in the UX culture,
and how employees may be involved beyond their regular work,
for example, by speaking at conferences and events.
Conversely, if you see that the company described themselves
as doing UX, often with the slash-UI after it,
and you notice that the core competencies
look less like the kinds of UX we've talked about
and more like something else,
such as web or app development,
be cautious of their UX expertise.
They may have tacked on those letters, U and X,
because they believe that they're doing UX work
whenever they're creating a user interface.
Or they may simply see UX inclusion as a useful SEO tool,
without fully understanding what UX means.
Either way, when UX comes without the users,
represented by those core UX skills and services
that we talked about, do not just go and accept
their UX work at face value.
If the business is a microbusiness, for example,
a freelancer perhaps with one or two others,
you can seek to establish credibility
on the individual level as we discussed earlier.
However, also make sure that the freelancer
has an established business presence
and clearly seeks out UX work as a business.
Does a freelancer through a microbusiness
clearly have business processes in place?
For example, in the United States, do they know
what you're talking about if you ask them for a W-9
or a certificate of insurance?
Or, alternatively, do your conversations with them make them
sound like they are trying to just fill their time
until they can get hired somewhere as an employee?
It's not that you can't contract out to a freelancer
as an individual, but in some ways,
it gets a little trickier, both legally
and in terms of how your relationship with them is framed.