https://git.ir/
- UX job seekers are often asked
to share a portfolio of prior work
to establish that they have the appropriate experiences.
Portfolios are an inherently tricky thing, however,
since often by definition a portfolio showcases work
at prior jobs and those jobs might
require nondisclosure agreements or NDAs.
While the NDAs at other companies
shouldn't really be your problem,
you may run into job candidates
who tell you that they are hindered
by the rules of their agreements.
There's a hierarchy of what can be shared.
If you find a good candidate but want some evidence
of prior experience it could be up to you
to help them figure out what
is okay to share and in what way.
If they aren't constrained by an NDA at all
then sharing full work is certainly preferable.
Not only the final effort which may be public anyway
but also their pieces of the design,
or research, or strategic thinking
that went in to creating that effort.
If they have constraints with sharing actual items
in their portfolio, discuss with them whether
it's possible to strip out or blur confidential parts.
If all else fails, ask them to explain
the narrative of what they did and their work process.
They can avoid mentioning anything
that is truly confidential
and you can get an understanding
about how they perceive user experience and their role.
In some ways this framing is even better
than the actual items.
While it feels good to get to see what they are showing,
often these deliverables are part
of a team effort anyway.
Understanding the narrative of how they work,
and what their role was, and how they perceive the effort,
really can help you understand
how they can help you and your business.