https://git.ir/
- You may worry about bringing on agencies and freelancers
who are less in your control,
and who provide greater risk
and potentially more variability in your management
of the project timeline, scope, and budget.
The key is communication.
As soon as you possibly can,
ideally while you're still scoping out the effort,
work with your designated contractor to figure out
what their expectations may be,
and how these expectations align
with what you see yourself needing.
Different UX activities take different amounts of time
for different people.
However, in a time and materials contract,
meaning you pay people by the hour or perhaps by the day,
you certainly do have the right to tell contractors
that they need to fit within a certain set of hours or days.
If they have concerns they can discuss these with you
at that point.
But if they do propose more hours than you want
and you successfully talk them down,
still make sure to assess whether they plan to do this
in a way that could risk compromising
the quality of the UX work that you are planning.
Conversely, you don't want to over budget
significantly on their time,
particularly if this forces you
not to spend enough elsewhere
in order to stick to your project budget.
If you want to propose a fixed price contract
drill down very precisely to what is required,
and allow for extra buffer time
so that the contractor doesn't feel taken advantage of.
For example, when a client wants to give me
a fixed price to do a usability test,
I want to nail down little details to fully understand
the prep work required.
I seek to understand the amount of effort
I'll need to learn the system,
the maximum number of participants,
the number of days of testing,
whether it's a remote study, locally in-person,
or requires out-of-town travel,
the session length, and recruiting approach.
I also ask about the type of reporting and due date
for any reporting deliverables,
as well as what is expected of me
after the reports are delivered.
Once I know all these details,
I'll typically feel comfortable giving a fixed price quote.
Don't worry if you don't feel comfortable
with all the details enough to scope it out yourself.
You can certainly leverage the knowledge
of your selected resource to help you.
Even if you aren't drafting the contract yourself,
you may also find yourself in the position of negotiator
with your contracting office.
Again, don't hesitate to reach out to your new resource
and have them review and if necessary
redline early contract drafts to avoid surprises later on.
On the flip side, there's a dynamic nature to UX work.
A discovery early on could change the direction
of subsequent UX activities.
So particularly if you present your contractors
with hourly contracts,
consider keeping the contract adaptable enough
to give you flexibility later on in the process
without needing to involve your contracts office
or sending multiple change orders.
Also, talk with your contractors as early on as possible
about what equipment and software they already own
and what they might need.
Sure, you could be a stickler and require your contractors
to have what you consider standard software.
If they don't, however,
see if you can build a license into your budget,
or temporarily reallocate a license
that your company may have.
For the most part, contracting out work is negotiable.
No matter the size of the business,
whether a freelancer or a larger organization,
they want your business.
They're likely willing to talk through situations
where their price offering
is more than you can afford to pay.
Or where their typical approach
doesn't quite fit with what you are looking for.
This is within reason, of course.
For both an individual contractor
and for a larger organization,
it's a balance of availability and free time,
and avoidance of effectively lost revenue
if higher paid work comes through.
In other words, as a contractor,
I don't want to not work and would commit to
a reasonably lower rate in the short term,
knowing it won't displace other, more typically paid work.
But should work at a more comfortable, hourly rate
come through a month or more down the road,
I don't want to be committed to something long term
that is keeping me so busy
I'm locked out of the preferred rate work.
As a contractor, while I may be fine at a lower rate now,
I'm also cautious about setting a future precedent
for uncomfortably low paid work,
when asked to help out in the future.