https://git.ir/
- It's fair to expect that a new contract resource
can hit the ground running,
but be aware that every organization or even work group
likely has an established unique UX culture
and corporate culture.
The contractor isn't going to be familiar with that culture
and may need to align themselves.
Corporate UX employees may share a common body of knowledge
that combines typical UX practice
with industry and corporate influences.
Expect your new UX resource to understand and respond
to a typical UX framework.
But when that's combined with an additional unique framework
of your company or industry,
you'll have to provide some additional context.
You'll need to define terms that you use differently.
For example, a client recently told me
that they were going to do both user research
and usability testing.
Since I would typically consider user research
as an umbrella of methods,
and usability testing as one such method,
I asked the client for further clarification
so that I would better understand what he was expecting.
It turns out that he was framing user research
as more ethnographic,
and oriented at requirements gathering,
what I might call contextual inquiry,
while usability testing
was a more formal task-based assessment.
Once we agreed on our definitions,
the conversation continued smoothly.
Also, don't be surprised if your new resource
comes with some preconceived ideas
about the way that things should be done
or how to conduct specific UX activities.
While you certainly have the last word,
do consider that contract resources
can provide you with some cross-pollination,
taking their best experiences
from other companies and projects
and bringing these approaches to you.
Do your best not to squash these opportunities
for innovation by micromanaging.
You'll likely find value in the varied, innovative ideas
that they can bring to you and your company.