https://git.ir/
- Over the course of your project,
employees may have established
and effective methods of communicating with each other.
But a short-term resource may not be as fully dialed in.
So make sure to keep them in the loop too.
While you have less control over a contractor's schedule
and work than your employees,
you can partially compensate for this
with regular communication.
From the outset let your contractors know
that they have an open channel of communication
with your team and be specific about how communication
would be most easily facilitated from your side.
This is true whether they've allocated office space
in your work area or they're in a different time zone.
At a project level, as we talked about,
that communication starts with the contract.
And at a project level it extends
through the project life cycle,
both when the project starts and how the work
ebbs and flows over the duration.
This person likely also has their own preconceived ideas
about what deliverables will look like
based on prior work that they've done.
If you want them to produce you X deliverables
that match what your team has done before,
communicate there too.
Show them some examples and let them use
the actual documents as templates for their deliverables.
We'll talk shortly about UXer's being somewhere between
introversion and extroversion,
but for the moment just know that the people
you bring on as contractors
may have personality elements that combine a desire
to be social and have in-person interactions
with time alone focused on creating
what needs to get created.
So particularly if your resource is local,
if you can give them the option to work in person
with your team sometimes, do it.
That said, don't require them to always be on site
when doing the project,
especially when it makes sense for them work on their own.
Work with them to understand how they work best,
and understand how best they'll work with your team.
And finally, while you may really like
your contractor's work and want to work with them again,
the next time that you need them they may be busier
and not as likely to jump at what you have to offer.
So focus on building some loyalty as soon as you can.
Remember to do the simple things,
like telling them when you like their work,
not just when you want modifications.
And be aware that they don't necessarily
have colleagues to interact with regularly
to the extent that your employees
get to interact with each other.
So if you're all heading out
to a happy hour one day after work
and are going to treat your employees to drinks, by all means,
consider inviting and treating your contractors too.
Always remember that it's often the little things
in your control that can have an out-sized impact,
both in your relationship now and your future relationship
when you need that contractor again.