https://git.ir/
(lively music)
- On my LinkedIn profile,
I actually write and it says in my description,
if you're interested in having me do some work for you
in some context or other,
please email me first, don't call me.
It's not that I don't want to talk with recruiters,
but I get so much junk
which is like someone calling,
"Hi, I'm so and so from this tech company
"and we are looking for this wonderful position."
I'm like well, that's not what I do.
And they're like, "Oh but it pays this wonderful amount."
It doesn't sound so good to me.
"Oh, I see you're a freelancer.
"This is long-term full time."
Well, I still don't want it.
"But come on, can you tell your friends about it?"
No.
I get so many of those,
those calls, those emails of like,
it's totally misaligned
but versus the amazing recruiter
who calls, even if I'm not interested,
they say, "I recently read your blog
"about such and such
"and it was so interesting to me
"because I'm also learning about UX
"and I understood this concept
"and it was so meaningful to me.
"Oh and by the way, I looked at your profile
"and see you've been traveling a lot lately,
"so I'm sure you're really busy right now
"but when you get home next time
"and you want to talk,
"I've got this great thing for you
"and here's why it's great and so."
Wow, I do want to talk to you
even if I'm not interested in the job,
you care about me.
You understand who I am, you understand me.
The best thing that someone can actually do
is learn UX.
Learn the language of UX,
learn the terminology,
learn what UX is about.
It doesn't mean every nuance
of every software application someone might use
but at least at the big picture,
understand that umbrella of UX skills,
of UX job types
that someone may have.
Understand the big picture and that said,
certainly I would recommend
that hiring managers, that recruiters go
to UX meetups
and when they go to a UX meetup,
they start learning the language of UX,
they start hearing from speakers,
they start meeting people
and again, it's similar
to any other situation where if they go to people
and say, "Okay, I'm a recruiter
"and I need you right now."
It's a bit overwhelming
but if they just go, "Hey, I'm interested
"in learning about UX, I'm a recruiter,
"I recruit for these positions, not for a specific need,
"I just want to understand better UX
"and the people that do UX
"and the types of UX jobs within that umbrella
"and it's about my learning as the hiring manager,
"as the recruiter."
That is oh so important.