https://git.ir/
- Let's make a few broad generalizations
about UX professionals.
I believe that many UX professionals,
and I count myself here,
are neither introverts nor extroverts.
Rather, they're somewhere in between.
They're often people who sometimes enjoy the energy
from being and interacting with others,
and then find that they need
to have some time alone to recharge.
Additionally, when you hear UXers declare introversion,
well, it's true they might be.
More often than not, the term introvert
is actually and incorrectly being used
as a synonym for being shy.
And UX professionals are naturally curious.
They seek to gather information, to understand,
and to learn more about the world around them,
and to create for that world.
UX professionals are perhaps a bit more
feeling and emotion-driven than those in other professions.
So, what does that mean for you as an employer?
How do you best manage people
who are neither introverted nor extroverted,
who might sometimes be shy,
but are also curious, creative,
emotional information-seekers?
The physical space you have available isn't going to change,
but no matter what,
you need to have places of collaboration
and places of solitude.
Allow work areas where employees can collaborate
as they passionately discuss how best
to create what your customers want.
And carve out places where employees can retreat to
when they want to work alone.
If you've done what you can to have that quiet space
and you don't think it's good enough,
consider some liberal work-from-home policies
where you also help employees
really create an effective quiet workspace
where they live.
While flexible work arrangements are often best,
do make sure you provide a robust technology infrastructure
to allow staff to communicate effectively
when not in the same place.
If you don't have a permanent office,
consider opportunities to rent low-budget space
in a shared work environment,
somewhere with good coffee, good lighting,
and good restaurants around
so that a team can work together in person when needed.
You can create opportunities for socialization,
and consider providing at least some light structure
some of the time,
such as a non-work activity to mix it up a bit.
And go beyond only providing essential software technology.
If employees learn about a new helpful product
and want to experiment with it,
encourage them to get a trial version, for example.
And encourage that experimentation
with new processes and new methods.
Because UX professionals are focused on people,
they are perhaps more apt
to absorb the emotions of others.
UXers may very well be the first to be affected negatively
by ongoing workplace stress.
Additionally, when you have UX professionals
on the ground interacting with users,
remember that they could be absorbing
those emotions as well.
For six years,
I was doing a lot of research with disaster survivors,
and I remember a few times
when I would be struggling not to cry
when listening to some of their stories.
These interactions impacted me,
not in too serious a way,
but there are other situations where unnecessary empathy
could negatively affect UX staff.
So, be aware of this,
and provide appropriate counterbalances where necessary.
Focus on helping people feel good,
feel good about themselves
and about interactions with others.