https://git.ir/
- UX professionals tend to be information seekers.
They often want to grow their professional skill set
and knowledge, so help them.
It may seem counterintuitive,
but your job is to give them the skills, knowledge
and confidence that they'll need so they can be
an excellent candidate in the future job market.
Are they going to stay with you forever?
Probably not,
but giving them what they need to move on
doesn't mean that they will move on.
It means that they will respect and appreciate you.
Combined with a salary that's on par with the industry,
and a generally positive work environment,
that respect is going to make them all the more valuable.
Support learning.
Support the purchase of books and dare I say it,
a subscription to LinkedIn Learning
and other video and online learning resources.
Support attending events, local events
and national, international conferences
and support your staff speaking at those events,
where you also then get implicit promotion of your company.
You can also consider hosting your own events,
where you task your employees with helping to run the event.
I can tell you from experience that running events
provides a wonderful opportunity for visibility
and appreciation,
where your employees won't feel like wallflowers,
as they do the necessary tasks to make your event a success.
And help employees by framing
a valid career pathway for them.
Show them how they can move up in your company
and provide them with leadership skills.
Note that not every UX leader has to be a manager of others.
While management of UX staff or UX projects
are certainly valid and important career pathways for some,
practitioner seniority itself, with opportunities
to mentor and demonstrate by example
is another form of leadership, as is thought leadership.
So encourage blogging and writing UX related articles.
We talked about how UX is a field
that constantly deals with change, so growing and learning
are critical traits of UX professionals.
By encouraging their writing, you are helping them
to help others to grow.
And while you can get your employees
to help host your own events, you can also encourage them
to be UX leaders out in the wider UX community.
Almost by definition,
UX is composed of people who value people.
As such, this may very well be
why UXers so frequently enjoy being a part of local,
national and international communities.
Help your UXers do what they do naturally,
be a part of and build socially cohesive communities,
and the satisfaction that they gain from UX social cohesion
can also extend to their satisfaction with your workplace.
If you're involved in managing UX professionals,
set a good example as a caring leader,
who wants what is best for employees
and do your part to create an environment
where UX growth and leadership, however it's defined,
is second nature.