https://git.ir/
- We've covered a number of topics about UX hiring,
contracting and career management.
And you probably want to know where you can go from here.
To get more in depth on the variety of UX career pathways
as well as to see things from your staff's perspective,
check out my very popular,
Planning a Career in User Experience course.
To go even deeper, check out my book,
"The UX Careers Handbook."
For additional perspective, I'd encourage you
to check out my course,
Freelancing and Consulting in User Experience,
as well as other courses in the library.
Thanks for watching, and I wish you success
as you build your UX team by hiring, contracting
and inspiring those around you.