https://git.ir/
- No two projects are the same.
That's true across all industries.
Projects, regardless of framework or methodology,
share the same project life cycles.
Specifically, all projects face initiating, planning,
executing, and closing.
Even as these steps are shared,
software development projects are unique in themselves.
They have a development life cycle to contend with
that's separate and distinct from the project life cycle.
You need to know how to blend
what you already know as a project manager,
so you can adapt your skills to the specialized needs
of software development.
In this course, we'll explore in depth
how software projects are different.
We'll cover everything from project management frameworks,
vendor selection, and stakeholder mapping
to user experience and developing for scalability.
Hi, I'm Kelley O'Connell.
I've been a traditional project manager,
a scrum master,
and I'm now an agile coach and transformation strategist.
I've been leading teams for more than 20 years.
I've also been leading organizations
through agile transitions for 10 years.
Please join me as we explore the world
of software development project management.