https://git.ir/
- In the project world,
there's two competing frameworks.
Waterfall and Agile.
Depending on where you work,
you may execute your software project
using an Agile or Waterfall framework.
Let's take a quick look at both of these
so we have some foundational context.
Let's start with Waterfall.
Waterfall is often called traditional project management,
and we'll use these two terms interchangeably.
In simple terms, Waterfall is a series of sequential steps
the project manager leads the team through.
Based on your organization, the terms may be different,
but generally speaking, the linear steps
and sub processes are initiating, planning,
executing, monitoring and controlling, and closing.
Each of these linear steps must fully complete
before you and the team can move on to the next step.
This is a pretty rigid framework,
so anything that's missed in one of the sub processes
can throw a wrench in the works.
Common factors and software development projects
that can throw things off are late requirements,
increased scope, and gaps in the development tool set.
These typically force the project manager
to complete change request forms
to update the documentation from past phases.
Let's move on to Agile.
Remember that Agile is a family of frameworks.
With Agile, since it's a family of frameworks,
you and your organization may choose scrum,
extreme programming,
or some other Agile framework for your project.
For the sake of simplicity,
we'll use scrum as our Agile model
since it's the most common Agile framework in use.
In Agile, project processes are the same,
but they're handled differently.
Projects still have to initiate, plan,
execute, monitor, and close,
but the approach is more flexible.
What we see most often is that the initiation of a project
is a quick step, lasting only a week or two
to understand the project objective
and pull the team together.
From there, the project sub processes aren't linear.
They're repeating on a cyclical fashion
through the life of the project.
In scrum, two week sprints are used
to keep the sub processes moving forward quickly.
In a nutshell, the team plans, designs,
builds, and tests within the confines of the sprint.
The goal is to learn quickly
and produce working software every two weeks.
For a deep examination of Waterfall and Agile,
check out my course on how to transition from Waterfall
to Agile project management.
For now, it's most important to remember
that no matter which framework you're using,
software projects will need all of your skills to succeed.