https://git.ir/
- A project is a project is a project, right?
Well, actually, no.
Software development projects are different.
They tend to be more complex
with additional moving parts when compared
to your garden variety project.
We already know that software development has its own
software development lifecycle we need to look out for.
That by itself adds complexity,
but that's not our only constraint,
so let's take a look at what contributes
to the additional complexity
of software development projects.
First, there are many different
software design patterns a team can use.
These patterns are repeatable ways
to solve common software design problems.
Here, you'll need to partner with your development team
to understand which pattern they plan to utilize.
Knowing this, the team will guide you
to understand the pattern steps they'll follow.
This will help you know the way
in which work will flow through the team.
On a higher level, there are software architecture patterns
that define the overall layout of the application.
The most common pattern is the layered pattern.
This is simply a way in which the code
is split up into different layers.
Each layer has its own set of responsibilities.
The advantage of this comes in terms
of troubleshooting and maintenance.
It's easier to identify which layer may be the culprit
of trouble in your application.
First, let's get the lingo established.
The layered pattern is also
called a multi-layered architecture.
Most commonly, it's referred to as multi-tier architecture.
Sometimes you'll see it referenced as N-tier
to indicate there's no requirement on the number
of layers your software can have.
So, let's talk about the most common multi-tier structure
that you'll run into.
In this architecture, you'll usually find
the presentation layer.
This is the space where your users will interact
with your system.
You'll need to be sure that user experience
is considered in the design.
Second is the application layer.
Logic and business rules are applied in this layer.
For example, if your presentation layer has a shopping cart
in it, this is where the contents are tallied
and taxes applied.
Lastly, we have the data layer.
This is where the data persists
through the database servers, file shares, et cetera.
Be aware that this tier is also the one
that exposes the data.
Say your customer has three items in their shopping cart.
When they add an item, it's saved to the data tier.
This is why online vendors can show you
what's in your shopping cart.
As your team goes through the software design process,
they'll need to consider all the architectural layers.
This contributes to the complexity
of software development project management.
When you consider these complexities
for your software project, you'll be ready
to create the application your business needs.