https://git.ir/
- There are two dominant categories of project frameworks
that your company can use.
Broadly speaking, the categories I'll use
are highly structured and highly flexible.
All frameworks in each category are valid options.
At the same time, it's important to know
the limitations of each category so you can choose wisely.
First, lets talk about the highly structured frameworks.
In this category, our frameworks such as PRINCE2
and the Waterfall model, both of these are very common
and emphasize dividing projects into pieces or phases
that can be estimated at the beginning
and controlled throughout the life of the project.
If your project is well-defined,
and implemented in an environment that rarely changes,
the highly structured approach
may be a good fit for your work.
The challenge for these frameworks
with emphasis on structure and control,
is that they tend to be inflexible
when late requirements are discovered.
What this means is that creating change control forms
and updating design and scope documents
can actually have a negative impact on the project timeline.
On the flip side are the highly flexible frameworks.
Two examples here are in the agile family, Scrum and Kanban.
These frameworks are designed for complex projects
happening in fast changing environments.
Their emphasis is on planning,
just as much as needed.
Requirements are constantly evolving
and the frameworks allow the flexibility
to absorb these unknowns when they come up.
Further, software projects are all about
building an intangible product.
Because it's intangible, it's highly likely
that your requirements will change
as the team and customers discover additional needs.
If your project is clearly defined
with a low likelihood of hidden requirements,
you can easily choose a highly structured
framework and be just fine.
On the other hand, if you're building something
with high levels of complexity
and potential for unknowns to crop up,
the highly flexible frameworks could
very well be a better choice.
Whatever you choose,
having this information available
to support your informed decision
will be critical for your project success.