https://git.ir/
- We've established that software development projects
are unique.
Do you think all software development projects are the same?
I can tell you for sure they're not.
In fact, there are many types of software projects
you might manage in your career.
I've categorized these into three broad groups
of software projects. Each category will demand
a slightly different skill set from you.
The first is known as a Commercial Off-The-Shelf
or COTS project.
You'll work on this type of project whenever a company
chooses to buy a solution to a business problem
instead of building a solution to the problem.
In many cases it's less expensive and delivers
faster results if a product is purchased
instead of developed.
This project type occurs across industries so it's
very likely you'll have a chance to run
this software project during your career.
One of the challenges in the COTS category
is your dependency on a vendor to partner with you
during an implementation.
You can use a Request For Proposal, or RFP,
to help you make your choice.
The next type of software project
is the software enhancement project.
This often occurs when a company has
built a solution themselves at some point in the past.
The benefit of enhancing an existing application
is that you have people already using it.
That makes it easier to understand what changes are needed.
This type can be particularly challenging if the original
development team didn't leave robust documentation.
In those cases you'll need the team to do some
reverse engineering to understand how the software was built
and what design decisions they made.
Finally, there's the New Build Software project;
sometimes this is called Scratch Development.
The benefit to this type of project is the opportunity
to create exactly what your business needs.
In this category you'll face many challenges,
not the least of which is the fact that you and the team
may only have an objective or idea in mind when you start.
Use your leadership skills to navigate the team
through the unknown.
A blank sheet of paper is always intimidating, so this will
take strong communication and guidance from you.
One of the keys to this type of software project is to
fully understand the problem,
have strong contacts within the user community,
and keep those lines of communication open.
In the rest of this course we'll explore each of these
software project types in detail, in its own chapter.
We'll look into how each one is unique, and follow
a real life example of a project, so you develop
a great understanding of the knowledge you'll need.
As you learn all this information you'll grow
in your confidence and ability to manage any kind of
software project that comes your way.