https://git.ir/
- Many companies and government organizations
prefer to solve their business problems
using commercially available software.
The logic is pretty straightforward.
It's much more economical to buy software than to build it.
There are six steps to implementing
a commercial off-the-shelf or COTS application.
Let's use an example to explore further.
Say we're on a project
to find the perfect customer relationship management
or CRM system for our company.
What steps would we take?
Well the first step is understanding the requirements
of the software you're shopping for.
In this step we'd start by working with our users.
We'll need to understand
what functions they need to perform.
For example, the sales team may need to maintain
customer contact information
and a workflow that matches the sales cycle.
Requirements for customer support
and the IT teams will be different.
So identify all the potential users
and capture everyone's needs.
The second step is to evaluate and select a product.
In our case we'll start researching
potential vendors in the CRM space.
Usually in a COTS project the users think they know
which vendor they want.
At the same time it's a great idea
to host a competitive bid process
where we select several vendors, share our requirements,
and ask them to submit a proposal for our review.
The third step is to finalize terms
with your selected vendor.
This will include interaction
with your legal and procurement teams.
Let them know in advance that a purchase is coming
and provide them insight
into when their assistance will be needed.
The fourth step is to implement the solution we've selected.
In my experience the vendor that's selected
will do most of the work.
However, it's essential that you and your team
are partnered closely with them.
For COTS applications
there are significant configurations to be made
so the solution works the way your users need it to.
And don't forget to account for data migration
if you're moving from one system to another.
Keep in mind any integrations that need to happen.
For our CRM system perhaps we want to include an integration
with the inventory system
so when our customer buys something
the inventory counts are updated.
Finally, in a COTS implementation
you'll need a lot of of system validation.
Be sure your project team, user base,
and technical experts are ready to validate
that everything is working as needed.
The fifth step is maintenance and upgrade of the solution.
While this probably won't happen during your project,
as the project itself closes down,
make sure the IT infrastructure and support teams
are ready to take this on when your project wraps up.
Include these teams well before going live
to ensure support is available.
The sixth and last step
is to maintain licenses and subscription fees.
Again this will be outside the control of the project,
but it's your responsibility
to make sure the area paying for the software
has this accounted for in their annual budgets.
While there aren't many steps to a COTS implementation
there are several items to consider.
When you do your COTS implementation will be a huge success.