https://git.ir/
- There are thousands of COTS applications on the market.
How on earth can you be sure you're selecting the right one?
I've been through several of these types of projects,
and one key to making sure you select
the right product and vendor,
is the request for proposal, RFP for short.
There are key elements that every RFP needs to include.
Let's take a look at these
in the context of our sample CRM project.
First, always open your RFP
with an introduction or executive summary.
This section is pretty short,
and just really sets the stage for potential vendors.
Using our CRM project example,
I would explain the high level goals we hope to attain
from the right CRM solution.
Next, be sure to include the business background.
It's really helpful for vendors to understand your company,
markets you serve, company values,
and what makes your company special.
Third, be sure to include your project goals.
Here, we let them know
who the users will be in your company.
In our example, we want a CRM solution that's built
for both our sales people and our customer support team,
Next, is where all that requirements work comes in.
We need to include our project scope, and deliverables.
In this section, I usually include these details:
how we'll be managing the project,
communication and progress monitoring,
any dependencies we know about,
how we plan to accept and validate the vendor's work,
how our changes will be handled,
and our expectations about support and maintenance.
Finally, I create a table
and put the requirements I've gathered here.
Fifth, we need to include our timeline.
How soon do we want to implement a solution?
Next, we need to share
the vendor response format we want them to use.
We do this to help simplify our analysis
when the responses roll in.
Usually, I ask them to send an executive summary,
background information on them,
proposed solution and deliverables,
details of how closely they meet our requirements,
their preferred timeline and budget,
and customer references.
Then, I share our budget information with them.
Generally, I provide an expected budget range
for both the implementation
and ongoing support and maintenance costs.
Next, I offer details of the important selection criteria.
This section isn't restricted
to our most important requirements.
It also offers a window
into the kind of vendor we want to work with,
and what type of partnership we prefer.
Finally, I share with the vendors, the proposal timeline.
I usually provide potential vendors
a 30 day window to respond.
I also tell them how long it will take us
to make a decision, and how they'll be notified.
Usually, I also include a window for them
to demonstrate their product to our decision makers.
I've placed a sample RFP template in the exercise files
for you to review or use as you need.
While the RFP process can be lengthy,
when you follow these steps,
you'll be sure to select the right COTS solution
for your organization.