https://git.ir/
- When implementing a COTS solution,
one of the key challenges you're dealing with
is having more than one team.
Let's explore this using our CRM solution.
Let's say we've successfully selected a vendor
and completed all the legal documentation.
We're ready to kick off the implementation itself.
Now we're going to host a planning meeting
with both our internal team and the vendor's team.
At the beginning,
we start with a road map.
Vendors usually have a basic implementation road map
they follow with all of their clients.
This is a great place to start.
We'll get the vendor team in a planning session
with our team so we both understand
what all the deliverables are on the vendor road map.
As we decompose the road map into smaller pieces,
we begin to see the dependencies within it.
Let's assume that we've selected
to follow an Agile framework.
Each of the deliverables on the road map
can be decomposed into stories
and assigned to one of the teams.
There will be items only the vendor team can tackle
and items only our internal team can handle.
As we go through this planning session,
we'll see how the team need to pass work back
and forth to each other.
Coming out of this initial planning,
we also need to establish our future processes
to stay in sync.
First, establish a scrum of scrums
where the teams can come together at least once a week
to share their progress, challenges, and ask for help.
Next, set up a way to share work.
Usually we'll need a task or Kanban board
that both teams can access, see, and update.
Then we'll define how we'll continue to plan jointly
for the duration of the project.
Oh, and it's a great idea to complete sprint planning
at the same time every two weeks.
A successful method for this that I've used in the past
is to hold joint planning every other Wednesday.
That means we get on a teleconference where we can see
and speak to each other and see our shared task board.
This joint planning takes care
of the tactical aspect of implementation.
It's also a great idea to have a slightly longer session
every four to six weeks
or two to three sprints
to take a step back and compare the team's progress
against the road map we started with.
When we do this,
we're making sure that we're on track both
at the ground level and at the strategic level.
A COTS application will require you
to balance your normal internal practices
with the vendor team's needs.
With just a little bit of planning,
you can do this and keep your COTS implementation on track.