https://git.ir/
- No matter what vendor or solution you're dealing with,
be sure you take into account the integration angle
of your COTS project.
Let's go back to our CRM project
and explore integrations from this perspective.
We've selected our vendor and our solution.
Now we're ready to hold a joint planning session
with our team and the vendor's team.
We need to deeply explore the idea
of integrating the new application
into our technical ecosystem.
It would be a rare occurrence
if a COTS application could stand alone.
In all likelihood, we'll need the new system
to receive information from or send information
to other systems we already have.
Thinking about our CRM project,
we'll talk to our stakeholders and our IT experts
to find out what information or systems
exist both upstream and downstream from our CRM.
For example, perhaps we have a website with a contact form.
If we do, do we need our new CRM solution
to receive information from the website?
What flags, notifications, or workflow
should this form trigger in our application?
This is an example of an upstream integration.
Next, let's think about how our CRM solution
should share information it captures.
For example, perhaps we call a customer
while we're in the CRM.
Do we want integration with a purchasing application
so we can place a customer's order from the CRM?
This is an example of a downstream integration.
That means that data captured in our CRM solution
flows out to other applications.
In most COTS projects,
the company will decide who should do the work,
our team or the vendor's.
Many COTS products now come
with application program interfaces or APIs
that teams can use to create these integrations.
In my experience many COTS agreements
request the vendor to do the integration work.
This is because the vendor has usually done
these types of integrations with their products before.
It reduces the risk to our company
if we have them perform this work.
All COTS products require some level
of integration with existing systems.
Make sure you're asking your users and IT pros
for help in identifying the key integrations needed.
When you do, you'll make sure your COTS application
works exactly as planned.