https://git.ir/
- A software enhancement isn't a defect,
or even a collection of defects that you're fixing,
all at the same time.
So what is it then?
Simply put, an enhancement is a collection of improvements
that users want to see in a system.
For example, if you have a banking website,
that sends you to a new log-in page when you click
my balance, that's a defect.
But, if users want to see their balances in various
currencies, that would be an enhancement.
Do you see the difference?
For a defect, something isn't functioning correctly.
For an enhancement, you're adding new features
that users have requested.
Now that we know this, let's explore some of the challenges
you'll face when you're working on an enhancement project.
The first issue you might run into, is there's no existing
documentation about how the current website was built.
You may have to allocate a sprint or two, for the team
to reverse engineer the website.
Reverse engineering is simply having the developers
read through the code to understand the software,
logic, and workflow of the system.
This is a fairly straightforward issue for your team
to work through.
The key, is allowing them enough time to reach a healthy
level of understanding, before diving into writing new code.
Another issue is that enhancing an application currently
in use is like changing the engine
of an airplane mid-flight.
You have people already using the system, and your changes
may alter the features they already use and like.
Your changes then, could result in user alienation.
User alienation can be mitigated
through careful change management.
Some of the techniques you can use here are stakeholder
mapping and joint-application design.
Finally, the biggest and most common issue related
to enhancing an existing application
is unintended consequences.
As you might guess, this means that what you build
could have a negative impact on features or functions
that you didn't change.
Common areas where this crops up are in the overall
performance of the system.
Using our website example, adding a function to allow
more than one currency value to be displayed
may slow the page load time to several seconds.
That would be unacceptable to your users.
Another unintended consequence may be that when we make
our currency change, we may impact reports that bank
departments use for balance calculations or other metrics.
In any case, it's essential that you ensure enough
regression testing is performed on your enhancements,
to confirm you haven't broken anything with the new code,
and performance is maintained.
It's tricky to enhance an existing application.
By knowing these potential pitfalls, you'll be ready
for them, and you can help your team succeed.