https://git.ir/
- When you're enhancing an existing application,
you have to be very careful to ensure
that all your customers or stakeholders
are identified and engaged in your efforts.
By doing this, you'll make sure your enhancements
don't alienate your users.
One of the biggest mistakes that can be made
is by only identifying direct users of your system.
Sounds strange, but let's explore this idea.
If we're enhancing an existing application,
say, a website, of course the people who use the site
need to be considered, but are they the only ones?
No, of course not.
Think about all the other people
who indirectly use the website.
For example, imagine we need to upgrade a bank's website.
Now think about all the people besides your customers
who rely on the website in some way.
Perhaps there's a marketing department
that uses the site to post about new products,
or it pulls statistics from the site
to see what customers use most frequently.
What about a customer accounting department
that relies on site transactions to keep balances updated?
You get the idea.
There are many stakeholders to consider
when making enhancements.
So what do you do about it?
I always use the process of stakeholder mapping
to guide me as I engage my stakeholders, learn from them,
and keep them up to date on progress.
It sounds mysterious, but stakeholder mapping
is actually pretty easy to do.
Here's how.
Start by identifying your stakeholders
by making a list of everyone you can think of.
No filters, just brainstorm to generate a list.
Once you have a list,
you need to prioritize your stakeholders.
No, that doesn't mean that some
are more important than others.
It simply means that you're analyzing to determine
which ones have the most influence over your project
and have the most interest.
Now you'll map them onto a grid like this one.
In my experience,
I use categories of users for this exercise.
So I'd map the marketing department as a whole
even though I have a single point of contact for the group.
Next, you'll meet with your stakeholders
to understand what they want, need,
don't want, and fear from your project.
This valuable insight keeps everyone aligned
throughout the project.
Finally, you'll decide how to engage with each quadrant.
Those in the upper-right quadrant
will need the most communication and engagement.
Those in the upper-left quadrant
will need high engagement but not so intensely.
As you move to the bottom half of the grid,
keep stakeholders informed of what you're doing
and how things are going.
As you start your software enhancement project,
be sure to map your stakeholders
so you don't leave anyone behind.