https://git.ir/
- In enhancement projects, you'll have many diverse
stakeholders to please.
While this is true for all projects,
it can be particularly tricky for enhancement projects.
How do you make sure that all voices are heard?
Holding a joint application design, or JAD session,
is a great tool you can use to solve that problem.
Let's look at how a JAD session works
and how it can help you.
First, a JAD is a collaborative way
to gather requirements across people and groups.
It focuses on eliciting the needs of everyone
and instilling a sense of ownership among your users.
Rather than spending time meeting
with each stakeholder group,
you're bringing them all together.
They can hear each other's needs
and negotiate when they have conflicting requirements.
So, who attends?
Well, you'll need a representative
from each stakeholder group you mapped.
For example, if we're enhancing a banking website,
I'd want a representative from marketing,
customer accounting, customer relationship, online banking,
and online support.
I don't want all the teams there,
just a designated representative from each area.
Keep the JAD session user count to less than 10 people
to ensure great dialogue.
Each representative needs to be familiar
with the day-to-day operations in their area.
This will give us the best perspective of their needs.
I usually include my project team, too,
but exclude them from the headcount.
Why?
Well, the team is there to ask clarifying questions,
not to direct the conversation or contribute.
Next, you'll need the project requestor or sponsor
to open and close the JAD sessions.
This person will provide framing for the attendees.
They'll lay out why the project is requested
and the objectives the sponsor is hoping for.
Finally, you'll need a strong facilitator
to host the session.
The facilitator role is critical to the success
of your JAD since they handle the scheduling,
dispute mediation, and guide the JAD process.
They also need to have zero vested interest in the outcome
of the JAD.
This builds trust with the attendees,
knowing the facilitator is a neutral third party.
In my experience, JAD sessions are full-day meetings
and they run anywhere from two to four days in length
depending on the scope of work.
When you're starting a project with a lot of stakeholders,
making sure their needs are met is essential
to your success.