https://git.ir/
- You've done a great job at listening to your stakeholders.
You know what they need and why.
And your teams been at working building
what they've asked for.
But is that enough?
In my experience it's not.
You need to verify that what your stakeholders have
asked for truly matches what's being delivered.
In Agile frameworks, user acceptance is handled
in the form of demos at the end of each sprint.
That's a great first step,
but I believe more needs to happen.
Demonstrating software to the people who use it
is a one dimensional review of what you've built.
Adding in additional hands on access will deepen
users' understanding of what's built
and reveal issues that a demo can't.
So, how do you do this?
Well first off, make sure you've created
a test environment where users can access
what's been developed throughout the life of the project.
Work with the stakeholder groups you've mapped
and schedule their resources for testing.
Ideally, everyone should do coordinated testing
at the same time.
This is the only way to see
how your enhancements hold up
in something like the real world.
You'll want them all to have hands on access
to your development at least once a month.
I know this sounds like a lot
but the early errors are found the better.
It costs less to make changes earlier
and consistently throughout the life of the project.
You'll work with your stakeholders
to define the tests they'll perform.
This doesn't need to be a formal exercise
in building test cases.
It can be as simple as having them select
their normal, abnormal and unusual work scenarios
from their area.
With these samples, they can execute their work
in the new environment and see
how the enhanced system handles them.
Before you give users access to the system,
create a plan for their feedback.
There are a couple of ways to do this.
To be formal, you could develop a spreadsheet
or use a testing tool.
You can also be less formal by interviewing the users
when they complete their testing.
No matter which path you choose
make sure you know how their experience went
and whether and defects or new requirements have been found.
Finally, define an approach for change management.
This means knowing the process to tackle defects
and changes when identified.
In most cases, these are added to the backlog
and prioritized just like other work.
When you coordinate your user testing
throughout the life of your project,
you're ensuring users are getting what they need
and you're also making sure
your enhancement project will be successful.