https://git.ir/
- When I was assigned my first new build software project,
I thought, no problem how hard can this be, it's brand new.
Boy, was I wrong.
I quickly learned how hard it can be
and how many things can go wrong.
This type of project has its own unique
set of challenges to get in front of.
Lets take a look at them.
First, there's user experience, UX for short.
No matter what type of application you're building,
a website, mobile app, or an accounting system,
you're going to need a feature rich front end.
If you don't build it with UX in mind,
you may produce an application your users won't want to use.
Next, comes the fact that no application stands alone.
Address issues related to
existing legacy systems and infrastructure.
Maybe the app you're building
is replacing a legacy system
or perhaps it's just integrating
with these existing apps.
Either way, you may face barriers
to your new application because of these entrenched areas.
Another challenge unique to new build appplications
is building it for the future.
I don't mean that your application needs to be futuristic,
but it does need to be built for scalability.
Your application will grow and be modified
over time in a way that enhances its usefulness.
Finally, along the lines of scalability,
is developing your application for maintenance and support.
Your team needs to release an application
that both users and support teams love.
There's a special balance your team
has to use to make sure both sides are being heard
as the design progresses.
While on the surface it seems that building something
from scratch is easy, it's far more difficult than that.
As you tackle your new build software project,
keep these challenges in mind
so you can prepare for them.
When you do, you'll deliver a new app everyone will love.