https://git.ir/
- I used to confuse a good user interface, UI for short,
with a good user experience, or UX for short.
Looking at some of the apps I've been using,
I think I'm not the only one.
A good user interface looks great.
It's stylish and attractive.
A good user experience may have a nice-looking interface,
but more importantly, it also functions well.
It understands users' common pathways through the system
and makes those features easy to use and access.
That means rule number one when planning your UX
is know the difference and recognize that a good UI
is only a part of the whole user experience.
So how do you do that?
Well the most important action to take with your new app
is spending sufficient time with the people
who will be using it.
The main thought behind your design approach
must be what's best for the user?
Guide your team toward using design thinking techniques
to make sure it gets its UX design right from the beginning.
Design thinking is a way to blend the user's needs
with the organization's strategic goals and context.
A team using design thinking
will consider multiple solutions to the problem
before choosing one solution.
Here's a five-step process to practice
design thinking on your project.
First is empathize.
Meet with users by interviewing them
and perhaps shadowing them as they do their work.
Understand their real-life experiences without judgment.
Go in with the goal to understand.
Define is the second step.
Map out personas and the objectives of their role.
This is where you'll define the challenges that users face.
Third is ideate where your team brainstorms ways
to solve the pain points you discovered
in the first two steps.
Your team will conduct a lot of research
and explore for solutions.
Then prioritize the ones they've discovered
for further investigation.
The fourth step is prototyping.
Develop mock-ups and storyboards
to flush out the ideas more fully.
The key is to fail fast by trying several ideas
and assessing feasibility quickly.
Finally, the fifth step is test.
Try the prototypes out to see what really works.
This won't be a one and done step.
Expect to go through more than one iteration
before your team finds the right solution.
Designing for the whole UX is essential
to making sure the app you build is fit for purpose.
When you guide your team through design thinking,
you're helping them succeed with a great user experience.