https://git.ir/
- Your new application won't be launched
into a world of its own.
What I mean is that your new software
will move into an existing ecosystem.
This poses a challenge to your project.
You must take into account the current
technology infrastructure and tackle integrations
with legacy or existing systems.
There's one popular mechanism your team
can use to take on this challenge.
It's called DevOps.
DevOps has been around for a while,
and it came from lean and agile approaches to working.
Currently, DevOps focuses on the collaboration
of development teams, Dev, and operations teams, Ops.
The goal is for collaboration on both sides
of the system, original development teams working with
the operations or maintenance and support teams.
This teamwork creates fantastic products
because development takes into account post go-live support.
You'll build a more robust product simply because
the product is designed to work well with legacy systems.
Further, the application is designed to perform
throughout its normal application lifetime.
So how do you do that?
Well, keeping your team grounded
in an agile mindset of learning, experimentation,
and collaboration is a great place to start.
From there, explore DevOps practices
and use all the approaches you can
to ensure the integrity of your app.
A great example of a DevOps practice is to use
continuous integration where code from all your developers
is integrated together at least once a day.
This makes sure coding errors don't break the build,
and if they do, the team knows which code it is
so they can fix it quickly.
Automation is another hallmark of DevOps
and is particularly helpful.
You can automate your build and your testing.
When you automate your testing, it's easier to validate
your integrations with legacy systems.
A third DevOps practice is to automate your provisioning.
When your development team needs to establish
a new environment, perhaps for user testing,
it can do so with minimal support from the operations teams.
Deploying a new app into an existing ecosystem
presents its own set of challenges.
Using DevOps practices can help you
and your team do it gracefully.