https://git.ir/
- Have you ever watched something on a streaming platform
and suddenly in the middle of the movie
a spinning wait circle pops up?
It drives me crazy because it's a software problem.
Software engineers are terrific
and they build scalable platforms.
The problem is that the app in that moment
has reached its maximum anticipated load
and we just need to patiently wait.
So, what makes a system scalable then?
Scalable systems don't need to be completely redesigned.
They'll still perform well during
or after a huge increase in workload.
In our streaming example, that workload usually
comes in the form of simultaneous users, but it can also
apply to storage capacity, concurrent transactions
or anything else that pushes the system past
its originally designed capacity.
You can design scalability into your app, too.
Let's take a look at the key principles of scalability
so you can encourage your team to design for them.
Availability is the first principle of scalability.
It's all about making sure
users can access your application.
It doesn't matter how wonderful
the app is if no one can get to it.
Next is performance.
As you might imagine, this is about speed.
Even when your application is carrying a heavy load
of users or transactions, it still needs to be fast.
Speed is a critical predictor of user
satisfaction with your application.
This is a key to insuring the user experience
is one that generates loyalty and not shopping.
Finally, there's reliability.
Maybe your app is always available and performs well
under heavy workloads, but if the data presented
to your users is wrong, it's not reliable.
Being reliable means that the most current data is always
presented to users and you're not defaulting to old data.
Your users should trust all the information
to be accurate even when the workload is high.
There are many ways your team can design for scalability.
You don't need to be an expert at scalable design
to ask the team questions about these principles.
Tab into your architects to help the team
if these principles are new to them.
Ensuring that your team is designing for scalability
can have a huge impact on whether
your app is considered a success.
Build these ideas into your design
and you'll build scalability into your application.