https://git.ir/
- You may already know how you're going to
release your application.
If you're working in an agile environment,
you may release your product
in small, frequent, modular pieces.
If you're working in a more traditional environment,
you may release your application all at once.
This is often referred to as a big bang release.
Either way, there are actions you need to do
to ensure your release goes smoothly,
and teams are ready to offer support
for your new application.
Let's explore these essential steps.
First and foremost, be sure all forms
of testing have occurred.
Ideally, you'll tackle these throughout
the development life cycle.
At a minimum, you'll need user acceptance testing,
integration testing, regression testing,
performance testing, and end-to-end,
or system testing.
All of these types, combined together,
provide visibility into how well
your application will perform.
Further, these will confirm that your users
are getting exactly what they're expecting.
Next, address user readiness.
Let your users know when your application is coming,
so they're ready for it.
If there are user guides being developed,
these need to be ready to go as well.
And don't limit your user-readiness
to just your direct users.
Make sure users of systems integrated with your app
know the release is coming too.
Another key item to tackle is operations readiness.
Work with the operations and support teams
to let them know about your release,
and how they may need to help you during that final push.
I hope you've put some Dev Ops practices in place.
If you have, the Ops teams already know what's been built,
and how it integrates seamlessly into the ecosystem.
The Ops team will also be ready to partner
with your development team
to create a great support experience for your users.
Finally, connect with your team
to handle the migration readiness.
Double-check that everyone knows exactly what steps to take
to move your application to the production environment.
Simple check lists for the migration steps
can help the team immensely,
especially if the migration process isn't automated.
Be sure to take the time to prepare for your release.
When you do, you'll find the process can be simple.