https://git.ir/
- Thank you so much for joining me
on this journey of managing different types
of software development projects.
Each type of software project has its own
special circumstances for you to tackle.
I'm sure you recognize that the techniques
we talked about can be used on any project.
In the exercise files, you'll find a checklist
for each type of software project
and the approaches we discovered along the way.
To continue your learning, I recommend
you check out "Leading the Transformation"
by Gary Gruver and Tommy Mouser.
This is a wonderful guide on implementing
DevOps in your Legacy environment.
Explore the deep content in the LinkedIn
learning library around DevOps.
This knowledge will make your
software projects more successful.
And search for more on user experience in the library
if you're passionate about ensuring
your users have great experiences with your applications.
Thank you again for joining me as we looked
at the foundations of software project management.
Please feel free to reach out to me on LinkedIn.
I'd love to connect and to hear
how your software journey is going.