- [Instructor] As we discussed in the previous chapter
of this course, you may need to begin your journey
into Agile new product development change management
by giving your business an introduction or a refresher
into the Agile methodology, and Agile vocabulary.
Similarly, we reviewed that the business users
may be thinking about requirements
and not necessarily in tune
with the way that you formulate your actual work,
and your actual work breakdown structure under Agile.
As Socrates reminds us,
the secret to success is letting go of the old
and embracing the new paradigm.
Let's discuss how you can facilitate such a transformation.
To begin with, remind your stakeholders
and your project team that you want
to deliver a product, and you think
to deliver a product, not documentation.
Now clearly as we discussed earlier in this course,
some documentation's very important,
and some documentation is dictated
by regulating bodies in government agencies.
So you cannot get away with doing no documentation
for a physical product.
But you want to make sure that you are minimizing
the documentation done and the documentation
that is done is done in a very efficient manner.
You also need to make your project team comfortable,
with the fact that you sometimes need
to stop, assess, and re-plan product requirements
in an Agile methodology.
Because a core tentative Agile
is that you begin building things
or you begin working on the design,
before all the requirements are known.
This is very different
from the traditional waterfall methodology.
Again, another difference in Agile,
you purposely delay decisions.
This can be very foreign to folks familiar
with the traditional waterfall methodology,
in which, a known unmade decision is viewed as a risk.
Another big part of Agile is involving the customer
and involving the customer early on,
even in the change process.
The companies that are using
Agile methodologies most effectively,
are on those that are leveraging change
as a competitive advantage.
Now viewing it as something that they have to do
but something that they almost want to do,
so that they can satisfy the customer
and come out with a more optimized design.
Another technique based on industry best practices
is to make your product modular.
Making a product modular does have some costs,
in that you need to define the interfaces.
But it also adds some benefits,
in that it allows you to fence in change.
Later on this chapter, we will have an example
of how a well known manufacturer
is using the idea of modular projects
to create their designs in a manner
that fences in change,
allowing them to freely make changes to styling for example,
but not make changes to structural components.