- [Instructor] Given what we just discussed,
there would seem to be many factors involved
in adopting Agile methodologies for new product development.
Aachen University in Germany performed
an exhaustive study of leading manufacturers
who had adopted Agile, or Agile-like methodologies,
particularly for change management.
And the results can provide us
with some interesting analysis.
First, when viewed as a graph,
comparing product maturity to rigor,
the study found that leading companies
are able to progressively introduce rigor
into their processes and into
their new product development methodologies.
How linear this rigor can be introduced
seems influenced by a number of factors.
The study found, interestingly,
that there were typically three plateaus,
although sometimes there were more or fewer.
While the study did not say,
I believe that these plateaus are actually indications
that the leading companies are using
a Agile stage gate hybrid methodology.
If you're not familiar with this hybrid methodology,
you can find information in it
in my Agile Project Management
for New Product Development course.
If we dig a little bit deeper into the results
of this study, Aachen University found
that almost every aspect of product information
from how much automation was used to produce the parts
to how compliant the products are to industry standards
progressed at roughly the same rate.
This indicates, as Agile prescribes,
that the key stakeholders are involved early
and continuously throughout
the new product development process.
Now if we dig a little bit deeper,
specifically into the change management aspects
of this paradigm, what we'll find
is that the increase in rigor is very similar
to what we've just described.
In the beginning of the new product development process,
for example, leading companies often have
design professionals and production
or manufacturing personnel working very closely together.
They collaborate using digital tools
to view actual CAD models and provide redlines and feedback
in a format that can be consumed in the CAD tool.
This provides a very iterative, fast,
flexible environment for capturing
those early design changes.
As the product maturity increases,
the paradigm slowly changes.
In this example, we've introduced the validation
and verification stakeholders to the equation.
At this point, typically, change would be managed
through something like a design review.
The design review is shown here as a Word document.
But it's generally an artifact that's stored
in a PDM system under revision control,
or it's a business object in a PDM or PLM system.
Regardless, the design review artifact
allows information to be captured and stored,
under revision control, about the changes
that are being applied to the product as it's maturing
in kind of this middle state.
Moving to the right, or moving along in time
as the product gets very mature,
the equation changes to where change is managed
under a formal change management system,
typically using engineering change requests
and engineering change orders and so forth.
As you can see in this example here,
we have added the regulatory stakeholders to the equation.
Now in reality, all the stakeholders
should have been involved at some level
all the way along, though according to,
and as illustrated by, that Aachen University study,
the rigor in which they participate
increases as we move along the maturity of the product.