- [Narrator] The agile methodology, embraces, and stresses
the complexity of project delivery by implementing
empirical process control. Or essentially what we'd call
closed-loop feedback. We've discussed this several times
in the course already. But I wanted to take just a moment,
and illustrate what this might look like as a project
moves along, and as the design moves further in maturity.
Very similar to the very generic example we had
with the University study a few minutes ago.
In this case, what we have.
Is we have a series of running sprints.
So a design is underway. In this case,
as an early prototype is tested we get feedback
from various stakeholders indicating the performance
of the design, indicating some feedback about what
could be changed. And even,
as we can see from the stakeholder on the left.
indicating what might be possible to change.
So a properly functioning,
agile new product development team is able to bring
feedback, and suggestions together
in the design review meetings.
Now as this design moves along, and as we go through
another set of sprints or perhaps several other sprints,
we get more feedback, we get more refined designs,
and we continue using this closed loop feedback.
This information should be stored so that it can be
reused later, and recalled.
This middle phase again is typically where we would use
a formal design review tool of some type.
And we'd be capturing that information,
and keeping it under revision control.
As we move further to the right in time,
or further along in time,
the design runs through a series of sprints again.
And what we find is that we get very near the final product,
or we get the completed product.
Feedback from the testers indicates that it meets
all the requirements, and the design professionals agree
that the design can be frozen.
So a couple things I want to point out here at this time.
As you would expect, any changes moving forward
would have to be handled through a formal
change management process, not a design review process.
Similarly I think it's important to note that the design
team, or the product development team is agreeing on things
in this process. It's very important that as a manager
of agile new product development projects,
that you seek to have agreements, and that you seek
to have decisions made at the time that they can be made,
and by the stakeholders most empowered to make them.