- [Instructor] In the Agile Project Management
For New Product Development course,
we discussed the process through which backlog items
get turned into products.
This is the standard agile sprint methodology.
In this course, we introduce the importance
of anticipating change.
If we consider that this diagram
shows a typical running agile project,
we know that changes are invariably brought up,
usually at the worst time.
We want to ensure that the potential change
that's brought up does not impact
the current running sprint.
Rather, we want to move that potential change
into the backlog planning so that it gets planned
into the subsequent sprint, or sprints.
In such a fashion, we ensure that the change
is accounted for and even anticipated,
but does not turn into churn,
by altering the existing running sprint.