- [Instructor] As we just discussed,
building in the idea if anticipating change
is a very solid practice.
To further refine this idea,
we need to discuss fencing in change.
Fencing in change is a technique
used in Agile New Product Development
to help mitigate one of the primary risks
of the Agile New Product Development system,
which is changed propagation due to coupling.
In simple terms, change propagation due to coupling means
that any particular change made may have a ripple effect
or may impact other components or other parts of the design
that caused changes to be propagated.
As you can probably imagine,
this can even cause an endless loop of changes.
So, it can be very difficult to maintain
and it can be very, very costly,
and in fact can go well beyond the benefits gained
by using the Agile New Product Development methodologies.
So, let's take a look at an actual example of this.
In this particular case,
we have the design of a car door
from a well-known automobile manufacturer.
In the simplest fashion to describe this design,
we have an inner skin
which is where all the interior cosmetic parts attached to.
We have an outer skin
which is what defines the outside style of the vehicle.
And we have a structural component,
shown here in red,
which is the component that has been validated
according to the automobile's safety and crash standards.
What we want to do is we want to ensure
that changes made for cosmetic reasons
don't accidentally impact the structural component.
So, what this manufacturer did
is they chose to focus on the structural component
as well as the interface components,
shown here in yellow.
In such a fashion,
what they have done is they have set up a rule
so no changes can be made to the structural component
since it's a validated and governed by industry regulations.
Conversely, they have said that changes
to the interface components can be freely made
since they act simply as attachment points
to the other components of the door design.
In such a fashion, this manufacturer was able to contain
where changes can happen
and therefore ensure that propagation of changes
through coupling does not happen.