Welcome to the Agile Crash Course,
these scores will cover the most important
concepts and tools of agile development
and agile project management. But I should
note that agile is not only for the IT industry,
nor just for developers
or project managers, actually anyone
can apply agile across different industries
in almost any project. But I'll go over
which projects are better suited for agile
later in the course. For now, let's
just go over the basics. So let's start
by answering what is probably the most
important question in this course, what
is agile? You probably heard the term
a couple of times and we're wondering what
it meant, how it was different to what
you were already doing and whether
it was actually good or not. Well, I have
good news for you. If you are able
to understand the pictures you are seeing
on your screen right now, then you're
already going through the learning
process of understanding what agile means
because it's pretty much what you're
seeing there. Seriously, it's just that
simple. This summarizes what agile
is and what it means as a methodology
for delivering projects. And I wanted
to give you an analogy, because I know
it will help you understand it better.
So let's start with the left side at the top.
You have the process or traditional
project delivery. As you can see, we start
to build the whole car ride, the Ferrari,
the best product that has everything,
all the requirements and all the bells
and whistles. And we don't consider a project
done until we reach that stage. So the actual
delivery can take many months
and sometimes even years. And the customer
might not be happy along the way
since he's just waiting and waiting to get
something. But agile is quite different.
Look at the pig below that. Do you see
it? Agile is an iterative process
in which you deliver value through a basic
solution and then enhance it over time,
you deliver quickly and you deliver
often throughout the whole process. You have
constant communication and interaction
with your customer to ensure he's happy
with every product you give him. He can
actually start using even your first
iteration, the skateboard, to go
from point A to be sure, it would be nice
to have a car. But isn't a skateboard
better than nothing? Isn't it better
to have a skateboard while you build
the car? That is precisely what Agile does.
So let's put this into a real web
development example. Say you were building
a website to sell products on different
categories, flavors and colors in Agile.
You wouldn't spend months building that
website. Instead, you would create a basic
first iteration, maybe just the homepage
you'll get started and to get the concept
out there and then you would enhance
it over time and start adding to it more
and more pages to the website. More
and more product features over time in Agile.
We call that period of time
sprints and sprints less generally two weeks.
Now let's shift our attention to the right.
Do you see the sofa? The analogy
also explains a key concept in agile.
Keep it simple. Build the minimum. You really
need to deliver what the customer
expects. And that relates to another key concept
in Agile, which we called the MVP
or minimum viable product. So it's
the minimum you can deliver, which satisfies
the basic requirement. So like
the tire with the rope. So let's
recap about the concept of agile, agile
is a methodology to deliver
incrementally, it's imperative on time boxed and that
period of time, which is generally
two weeks, is what we call sprints. And what
you work on during those two weeks,
which are basically features that give value
to the customer, are what we call user
stories. But don't worry about the terms.
You'll learn them over time and I'll
go over this in more detail later
in the course. For now, I just want you to start
getting familiar with the concepts
and terminology we use in agile, such as
sprints and user stories. And if you ever
hear the word iteration and get
confused, don't be iteration is just another word
for Sprint, which, as you just
learned, is just a period of time to do something.
Generally two weeks, but sometimes
even three or four. That is something
for the project team to decide.