- One of the most useful ways
to manage content on YouTube
is with a playlist.
A playlist is simply a list of
videos that people can play,
but it's a little bit more than that.
With a playlist, you
have some great controls.
For example, you could put
together a collection of videos
that you've created
or you can use a playlist to
group videos that you've made
in a large library by topic or type.
Playlists can also be
embedded into a single player,
meaning that on your website,
you could put a collection of videos
or allow someone who's browsing YouTube
to easily find a playlist
and watch multiple things from you.
Playlists can also contain
videos by other folks
and this is one of the greatest ways
of helping people discover content.
Think of it as curation.
To create a playlist is pretty simple.
There are several places
where the create playlist
function is listed.
You can create a playlist a few ways,
for example by clicking on
playlist in the left-hand column.
This is currently only available
in the primary YouTube Studio.
You could also click new playlist.
As you see here, there's playlists
and this gives you the option
to easily create new ones.
Now once you've created a playlist,
you're going to enter a descriptive title,
add a general description
about the playlist,
and add multiple videos to it.
Now that you understand the
general concepts of a playlist,
let's build one.
To view playlists, simply
access your channel
and then go to the Creator Studio.
You'll see playlists
in the left-hand column
under the video manager.
If you're using a newer
version of the YouTube Studio,
you'll notice that
playlists may be missing
and clicking will redirect you
to the old version of Studio.
Let's take a look at a sample playlist.
Here are some that I've already created,
but I'm going to click the
button here for new playlist.
We'll give it a name
and currently set this to
unlisted as I refine it.
Later on, I can move this to public
and this is just like other videos.
A playlist can be public,
unlisted, or private.
Let's click create.
Now you'll see that it
just needs videos added.
One of the easiest ways to do this
is to click the edit button.
Now what we can do is start to add videos
so I'll click add videos
and it brings up a dialogue.
You'll note that you can
search by specific URLs,
search with general videos,
or your YouTube videos.
Since I want to make a
playlist of my content,
I'll click on your YouTube videos
and it allows me to see
what's happening here.
Now I can scroll through my content
and look for particular things
that I would like to add.
I can in fact hold down the Command key
or the Control key on a PC
and start to select multiple videos.
When I click add videos, they
are placed into the playlist.
If you want to change
the order of the videos,
you can simply click and drag
to move them to a new stacking order.
For advanced options, click
the playlist settings.
This allows you to control
additional properties.
You'll notice for example
that you can control
public versus unlisted versus private,
private being just like
videos that are invite only.
You have the ability to sort
manually like I did here
or to sort based upon date
added, date published,
or which ones are most popular.
And if this is something
that's tied to an ongoing web series,
you can go ahead and market
as the official series.
Now let's leave this as is
and we'll talk about more
of the options in a moment.