- [Instructor] Once you've
built some playlists,
there are some great
options you have to control
how it actually works.
Let's talk about that.
When it comes managing your playlists,
you have the ability to re-order videos,
change their general settings,
and use options like auto add.
This is easiest explained by taking a look
at an existing playlist.
So either take one that
you created yourself
or just follow along.
When you're working with the playlist,
remember you have the ability to click
on playlist settings
to access the controls.
This is where you can
change things like the order
and the privacy settings
we discussed earlier.
You also can take advantage of auto add.
This means that you can create a rule.
For example, I can say add any videos
that contain the word luminar
to this luminar playlist.
And I can also add an additional rule,
and you see that we can work with things
that are tagged with luminar.
That way, whether the title
or the tag says luminar,
it's automatically added.
I also have the ability to collaborate.
So I can turn this on and
that means that I can invite
specific collaborators to
actually work with this.
So if I get this particular
link and send it to em,
what this means is is that
if I have other people
within my organization
or trusted colleagues
that I want to invite,
they have the ability
to also add their videos to the playlist.
This is independent of
people who have access
to your channel.
If you've invited managers or
collaborators to the channel,
they can of course access the playlist
through the brand account.
But this is ideal if you want to work
with outside contributors who are not
managing your channel.
This gives them management
ability to add videos
to a playlist that's meant to
be shared with the community.
When you click save, it will go ahead
and capture these
settings for the playlist.
I'll go ahead and do this.
It says there's another video that
has the word luminar in
it, so I'll click done.
And you see now that it put
another video into the playlist.
Now if I decide that I don't want that,
from the more menu here,
you'll see that I can actually
move things around, or I can change things
like the thumbnails, or move
it to the top or bottom.
This works quite well.
If you decide you also
want to add videos again,
just click the add videos button.
But now, this is ready to share,
and the only thing missing
is the description.
And in this case I'm just
adding a simple description,
much like I would describe
an individual video.
But including that this is
a collection or a playlist
is a good idea, and this gives
me a simple pop-up control
where I can share this
or embed it on a website
or easily email it to folks.
So this is quite useful.
Your ability to control
playlists is a great way
to organize your content
and easily invite others
to experience it and enjoy it.