- Besides creating playlists
to organize your content,
you can take advantage of sections.
Sections are parts of your channel
that are dedicated to a particular video
or series of videos.
And oftentimes, playlists
will become a section.
Now using sections is an easy way
because you can take
this as a simple method
to organize the content and promote it,
giving visual weight to it on the page.
You can create a section
from a single playlist.
You can use multiple playlists
or even a group of other channels
that you'd like to recommend
or if you have additional brand accounts
that are associated with your company.
Some good examples of using sections
include grouping things by topic
or perhaps a family of products
or maybe a promotion that you're running
or perhaps it's videos
that feature the same host.
You could have a total of
10 sections on your channel.
And as you see here, this is
an example of Adorama's channel
and they've organized their videos
based upon different types of
items such as product reviews
or perhaps an individual host or author.
Here's another example of a
series on the Photo Focus site
where we've taken particular videos
such as the story behind a photo.
All right, how does this work?
When you're logged in,
simply visit My Channel
and you can click on Customize Channel.
Now you'll see different sections.
So for example if I want
to prioritize something,
I can select it here and just click
to continue to move it up in the stack.
That's for an existing playlist.
If I decide to, I can also
click the edit button here
and you see I can control what's
happening in that section.
For example, I'm using a single playlist
and I can change the style
of how that's presented.
There's a vertical list which
features the descriptions more
or a horizontal row
with just the thumbnails
and you choose if you want
to use one of your playlists
or the URL of somebody
else's shared playlist.
When you click done, it updates.
Now if you decide to add another section,
you'll notice that you have
that ability at the very bottom,
add a section.
Clicking this gives you the option
to choose what to feature.
For example, I can say
I want to feature my most popular uploads.
And that's going to easily add that
and I'll click save or done
and you see that that's
my most popular videos.
In fact, that's probably a
good thing to put at the top
so let's move that all the
way to the top of the stack.
This is a very easy way
to put your most popular content first.
Now you'll notice here that all sections
have the ability to
control what's being shown.
For example here with the feature content,
I've chosen to show the latest upload
or I can show the latest activity,
videos that have comments on them.
For example, I recently made this playlist
and I'm going to call that out.
You'll notice that new visitors
are going to see a trailer by default.
You just need to assign it and
we talked about that earlier
while returning subscribers
will see recent content
or featured content towards the top.
All right, this works pretty
well and as you can tell,
taking the time to add additional sections
really makes it easy to call
out the content on your page.