- Now if you go to edit
your page and you can't
easily find the options
to do so, you might have
disabled the ability to
customize your channel.
Let me show you where this is.
If you want to take advantage of editing
the navigation, make sure
you sign into your account
and visit the channel.
You can then click the edit layout button.
Then choose the settings
icon and make sure
that customize is on.
Pretty simple.
You click the settings icon there
and in the pop-up list
make sure that customize
is enabled.
Here we are back on
Photofocus and I'll click
the settings button.
You'll notice that customize
the layout of the channel
is turned on.
If you don't have this
turned on and you disable it,
what'll happen is it
goes to default layout.
However, I'm going to leave that enabled
but if for some reason
you're unable to add sections
or rearrange items on the page, make sure
you enable this option.
Additionally, feel free to click over
to advanced settings.
This will give you additional
controls over what's happening
on the page for example,
if you want to allow ads
to appear on the page, if
there's an associated website,
and if you want your content to be shown
on other channel recommendations.
By allowing your content
to appear on other channels
as a recommended channel,
this means that other channels
will appear on your page.
Additionally you can
choose if you want to show
the subscriber count or not
and if you want to track
with Google Analytics.
What you'll notice for example
if we visit the channel
is there are some of those
featured promotion channels.
These are channels that
are similar to mine
and they appear in my sidebar.
There's a good chance
that my channel may be
promoted on theirs or on other websites
that are similar.
Additionally I turned off the
option to show subscribers
so that doesn't appear on the channel page
but you do have that option
of making it visible or not.
Taking the time to customize
your channel is essential.
Don't go through all of this
work of uploading videos,
organizing them and
putting a graphic identity
just to let YouTube automatically generate
your channel navigation.
You should decide what's
strategically important
and what content you want
to feature and what videos
are going to have the best
results to drive subscribers
and viewers.