This course is intended to deepen your understanding
of both the waterfall and agile project frameworks.
There are many specific ways to implement each one of them.
Your situation and organization will be unique,
and this course takes a very tactical approach
in how and when each methodology can be applied.
If you're new to agile, I recommend taking my course
on Transitioning from Waterfall to Agile Project Management
or the Agile at Work series.
This will help you understand the agile mindset more deeply
before this course dives into the tactics.
If you understand agile, but are less comfortable
in the traditional or waterfall project methods,
I recommend taking the course
Project Management Foundations.
This course will ground you
in the basics of this methodology.
Each of these frameworks has their own
unique strengths and weaknesses.
We'll be probing these aspects so you can choose which path
to follow with full awareness.
All projects measure success by the value they deliver
to their stakeholders.
Additionally, organizations measure success
through the amount of time they take,
the costs they require, and the features they complete.
We'll explore how each framework
approaches these success measurements differently.
Finally, we'll examine how each methodology measures
and reports its ongoing progress and status to stakeholders.
Utilizing the right key performance indicators
will help you and your team remain on track.
If you're ready for a deep tactical examination
of agile and waterfall, this is the course for you.