So let's talk about traditional project management.
It's really been around for over 50 years,
and most of the time we call this methodology waterfall.
Why?
Well, each step, or phase, must be completed
before the next one can start.
So the visualization of this is really
like the structure of a waterfall.
It's a defined process.
And all that means is that each step is laid out in advance.
It originated with manufacturing and construction,
because in those fields, each step has to happen
and complete before the next one can actually start.
It was then translated into software development.
So let's talk about the phases
of waterfall project management.
There are five of them.
They are initiating, planning, executing,
monitoring and controlling and, finally, closing.
We are going to look at each one of these in more detail.
Let's start with the initiating phase.
This is how you start a new project,
the team, you as a project manager,
you're granted the authority to begin.
That means you have the authority to direct the work,
you have the authorization to spend the money.
Usually there's a steering committee
that authorizes you to get started.
Once you have their approval to move forward,
you move right into the planning phase.
This is where you're defining your project in great detail.
It can be requirements analysis that result
in defined objectives and scope of what you're going to do,
and it defines how execution will happen.
So, in this phase, you're defining who do you need
to do the work, how long is it going to take,
what's the quality going to look like,
what are the risks you're going to face,
and you're define your communication plan,
your cost management plan, and stakeholder management plan.
So all of these plans are defined in this planning phase.
As you can tell, this can be a very time consuming stage,
because you're defining all of this
on larger multi-million dollar projects.
I've seen some of these planning phases
last literally months.
But what it does is it provides a detailed roadmap,
everyone on the project, everyone interested in the project,
knows everything that has to happen, when,
and how to get the objectives you want.
Once you've completed planning,
you move right into execution.
This execution phase is pretty straightforward,
you're just following the plans that you defined.
The work is done in this stage
to accomplish the objectives the way you defined them.
You're putting all of those plans,
management, quality, stakeholder, cost plans,
all of that goes into action in this phase.
The next phase, monitoring and controlling,
actually runs in parallel to execution.
While normally you would see the waterfall
move like this, what's actually happening
is you can't execute without monitoring and controlling.
So those kind of run together,
where monitoring and controlling can kind of track off.
Here, you are tracking the work that's being done,
you're governing the performance of the project,
and you're doing it throughout the entire execution.
So this encompasses status reports and everything else
you need to do to provide visibility
to the steering committee and stakeholders.
This is also how you manage changes that come up,
like if you missed a requirement
or something changes, your resource changes,
this is how you manage those changes.
This is where you find your change control processes.
Finally, when you're done executing,
you'll move right into the closing phase.
The closing phase is where you figure out
how you're going to transition this project to support.
You're also going to figure out how you're going to release
this to your customers.
You're going to maybe give them documentation,
maybe you're going to train them,
you're going to figure out exactly what they need
to successfully use your product.
Finally, you'll use lessons learned sessions
to get some objective reviews of how your project went.
What could be done better, what did you learn,
and what should future projects know
that you learned from this one?
And then you'll get your official sign off
from your steering committee
that you did what you said you were going to do,
when and how you said you were going to do it,
and your project ends.
As you can see, there is a lot of work
that goes into the waterfall process lifecycle.
Successful project managers can follow these phases
and deliver the value that their company's need.