Agile is a very broad term for a family
of project life cycles.
All of these approaches share their foundation
in lean methods, where the focus is on eliminating wasteful
or non-valuable work.
For a full discussion of the agile mindset
and all the different ways it can be used,
check out the course Agile Foundations.
To keep our discussion here brief,
we'll pick just one way the agile mindset
is put into practice.
The most common framework is scrum.
So, how does scrum begin?
Well, there's an assumption from the scrum mindset
that your organization already has a process in place
for projects to get approved.
This does not dictate how you initiate your projects,
all it says is that when you have those
processes established in your organization,
it should be efficient, it should be quick,
and it shouldn't burden the team or the stakeholders
with unnecessary or wasteful work.
In scrum, there are three key players,
and the product owner is arguably the most important one.
The product owner, or PO for short,
is the business and stakeholder rep for the team.
They're really the glue that takes the idea of the product
or project and links it with the team
because they're deciding what is the most valuable work
that this team needs to do.
Another key player is the scrum master.
This individual owns the scrum process.
They control the framework
and how the team applies the framework
as they're doing the work.
They help the team to deliver as much as possible
with high quality and a focus on the detail
of the work execution.
Finally, the next key player is the scrum team.
The scrum team is a cross-functional group of individuals.
They have all the skills needed
to complete the work in the product backlog.
The PO is the one requesting the work to be done,
the team is the one deciding how to accomplish this work.
So, in scrum, how do they actually do their work?
Well, they don't have phases.
They use time boxes, or sprints,
and sprints are usually two weeks,
and they keep cycling through sprint after sprint
after sprint until all the project work is done,
or all the requests from the product owner are complete.
So, it sounds very loose, but they do stay organized.
There are two ways that scrum teams stay organized,
they use artifacts and they use ceremonies.
Artifacts are just documents,
and ceremonies are the meetings
that they use to coordinate their activities.
So, let's talk a little bit about the kinds
of artifacts that the scrum team uses.
Well, the first, and probably the most important,
is the product backlog.
This is the long list of work that the PO wants completed.
The team, then, works with the product owner
to select a subset of this to create the next artifact,
which is the sprint backlog.
What's in the sprint backlog is
what the team is actually committing
to for the next two-week period.
Finally, there's the product increment itself.
The increment is the embodiment of all the work
that's completed in the current sprint
and all the previous sprints.
So, how do they coordinate their work with each other?
Well, let's talk about the ceremonies they use.
There are five of them.
The first is the sprint itself, it's a ceremony.
It has a start and an end, and it lasts about two weeks.
Next is a ceremony called sprint planning.
Within sprint planning, the team comes together
with the scrum master and the product owner
and they define what are they going to finish this sprint,
and they make a commitment to that.
Then, every day, they have the next ceremony,
which is the daily scrum.
The team comes together every day and says,
this is what I did yesterday, this is what I'm doing today,
and this is where I could use some help.
Next there's the sprint review, or the demo,
that they do at the end.
This is where they show the product owner
and the stakeholders everything that they've completed
and make sure that it's up to their expectations.
Finally, the last ceremony the team uses
is the sprint retrospective.
This is where they really become very internally focused
and they say, what did we do really well in the sprint?
How do we capitalize on that and do more of it?
What didn't go so well for us, and how do we change it?
And finally, what changes do we want to commit
to in the future sprints?
The scrum process is really easy to understand.
It is, however, hard to master and do well.
Using these artifacts and ceremonies,
the team can deliver value very quickly.