- Running a project is like maintaining a home.
There are always repairs and improvements to be done.
But when you consider repairs and improvements to your home,
you also have to consider three things.
How soon do I need it done?
How much do I have in the bank to pay for it?
And what tasks will get it done the way I want?
The same thing happens in businesses,
and these three things are known in the project world
as the triple constraint.
You may have heard of it as the iron triangle
or the project management triangle,
but it means the same thing.
The triple constraint is really all
about managing cost, scope, and time.
Let's talk about cost first.
With cost we ask, what are the financial limitations
that the project can't exceed?
And remember, as you're going through this planning,
you need to ensure that you're counting everything.
Labor cost, so it's the people on your team.
It's the labor of people you're going to bring in
once in awhile.
It's equipment.
Do you need new equipment for this project?
Do you need new hardware or new software to do the work?
Oh, and vendors.
Are you going to hire any outside vendors
to do work for you on an hourly basis?
So you'll need to bake all of that in.
In the waterfall method,
cost is set at the initiating phase of the project,
and it can't be changed, just like we talked about,
unless you get an approved project change request done.
So you'd have to go back through your steering committee
and make sure everyone's okay with that additional cost.
Next, you'll need to think about scope.
In dealing with scope, you really need to ask yourself,
what are all the features we need to complete
in order to deliver the value that we need?
During planning, you're going to start thinking
about how much time, how much effort is it going to take,
and then you're going to match
that time and effort and those estimates
against possible work item that needs to be done.
As you go through this process,
you're going to compare that against your cost,
so now you're going to lock down the scope
that will fit within that cost
by doing that analysis and that comparison.
Finally, let's talk about time.
What we need to know about time is
what's the estimated schedule to complete this job
to give the deliverable that we need?
So you're going to take
into consideration things like deadlines.
Is there a specific window
that you have to finish this in?
For example, I once ran a project
to set up a new financial accounting system,
but I also knew that I could only deliver that
in the middle of a quarter.
I couldn't deliver that at the end of a quarter
when it's not acceptable for our accountants
to be working on new software.
They need time.
So at the end of planning,
you're going to lock those time schedule boundaries.
They're going to be in sync with the work
that needs to be done that you've already estimated.
It's going to be in sync with the window that you have
for releasing your project and your deliverable.
So the nice thing is that you can use the triple constraint
to evaluate project success.
It's kind of a double-edged sword.
So from this perspective, from waterfall's perspective,
the perfect project means
that you've completed all of the scope
within your allotted time and using all or less
than the cost that was established.
The strict interpretation of waterfall says any violation
of the triple constraint in any one of the categories
means your project was unsuccessful.
On the plus side,
there are benefits to the triple constraint.
The teams and leaders are on the same page at all times
in relation to time, scope, and cost.
Everybody has the same expectations,
and everybody's working toward that same goal.
From this perspective,
the PM can easily identify variables
that are going to impact those project constraints.
So as something comes up, the project manager will compare
against time, cost, and scope
and make sure that there are no changes
that require a change request.
Project management is really a juggling act.
You have to make trade-offs to deliver value
without violating the constraints.
Let's go back to our home repair analogy for an example.
Let's say you set aside the month of June
to install new windows in your kitchen
to improve energy efficiency.
You have the money to have the work completed.
So far it looks like you're clear
on your time, your cost, and your scope.
But maybe you learn about a new type
of more attractive window.
Like any good project manager,
you'll review this option to determine
if it can be completed in the month of June
for the same or lower cost
and still deliver the needed energy efficiency.
When you balance the triple constraints
throughout your project,
you'll be able to get the outcome your leaders expect.