- Once your project is up and running,
it's expected that the project manager
will track how the team is performing.
Remember, in Waterfall, the requirements are gathered
and the plan is defined at the beginning of the effort,
during the planning phase.
So what are the levels of reporting?
Well, there are actually three of them.
First, is tracking progress by phase.
Remember, each phase has an estimated time frame
for duration and completion that's
established in the beginning.
Remember your phases that you're tracking
are initiating, planning, executing and closing.
Then you're also going to track within each phase.
Each phase then, will have predefined milestones
that will tell you whether or not
that phase is on track to be completed
within its estimated timeframe.
So how are those milestones tracked?
Well, it's actually pretty simple.
You're going to identify all the tasks
within each milestone that are needed to be done
in order to complete the milestone.
In the planning phase, you may have milestones within it,
like signed statement of work, SOW for short,
requirements review and estimates completed.
For example, let's talk about breaking down a milestone.
Let's use the signed statement of work,
signed, the SOW, and the tasks
that might be a part of that.
Some of the tasks you might tackle here
are receiving the statement of work from your vendor,
doing a legal review with your in-house legal
and then signing that statement of work.
So you will track progress against each one of those tasks
because each task is given a time estimate for completion.
For example, the legal review task
may have a four hour effort estimate for the work,
and a five day window to complete those four hours.
As the PM tracks the progress of these signed SOW milestone,
she'll look at the targeted window for the work.
Let's say July fifth through the ninth.
Then she'll check on progress
with the person assigned to the task.
If it's Monday, and the task has started,
she'll know the task is on target based on the plan.
She'll also be confident that it will be complete
by the ninth, so the task will be marked
as being in good shape for the deadline.
However, if it's the eighth and the task hasn't started
the PM will know to take some corrective measures
to get that task right back on track.
At the same time, if the work has started,
but more than four hours have been used,
she'll know there's a problem,
and we'll, again, take steps to fix things.
That's how time and scope are managed.
For budget, the PM will track the hours
applied to each task against the estimates.
All the work hours will be calculated
and reduced from the project's total budget.
Tracking team progress in Waterfall
is a very detailed exercise of
following the progress and cost of each task.
Now that you know how Waterfall tracks progress,
you can easily share this information
with your stakeholders.