- Knowing that our organization
is changing can be unsettling.
But preparing ourselves by learning
positions us to be successful
and can make us the leaders of the change.
As your organization moves forward
with both agile and waterfall methodologies,
learn everything you can about both.
By taking this step,
you'll be ready to lead
the organization as it changes.
As you start this process of learning,
I recommend you check out my course
on transitioning from waterfall to agile.
Also, take some time to watch
the Agile at Work series with Doug Rose.
These courses will deepen
your understanding of both methodologies.
I hope that you've already started exploring.
There are many approaches
to the triple constraints
in both methodologies.
Further, if you can start
to incrementally shift your portfolio
into a single report,
your organization will be
much healthier for your efforts.
Don't hesitate to share your stories
with me on LinkedIn.
I'd love to hear about your experiences
and answer any questions you may have.
Best of luck to you, your teams,
and your portfolios.