- Earlier in the course, we talked
about the limitations on replacing a movie
and I mentioned cards or annotations.
Even if you're not looking
to replace a movie,
cards and annotations give a great way
to add interactivity
to your YouTube content
and use it as a lead generator
or to give people additional
ways that they can interact.
What exactly is a card?
Well, cards are
pre-formatted notifications
that appear on desktop and mobile
and they can popup over your video.
They can be used to promote a brand
or other videos that you
have on your channel.
Once they're set up, a
small rectangular box,
or a teaser, will appear
in the top right corner
of the video.
If the viewers click on
this, well, then the card
will actually trigger an interaction
and content can load to the
side of the video or below it,
depending upon where you're accessing it.
Now you might be wondering
how could you use these links?
Well, these cards can actually serve
several different purposes.
First up, a lot of folks
will use it to link
to an individual video or a playlist.
Maybe this is a newer version
of the video or related content.
Also, you can link back to
your individual channel,
promoting your channel or another channel
where people can get a lot more
content similar to this one.
You can use it as a call for donations.
This allows you to feature
a nonprofit of your choice
or if you are a nonprofit
and YouTube recognizes you,
then you can link to yourself.
You can have a poll where people can vote
or engage in the content,
maybe commenting on what type of videos
they'd like you to record next.
And you can link to a
pre-approved website.
Generally speaking, you will
be limited to one website
so you'll have to affiliate a website
with your YouTube channel
under the brand account
and then you might have to
actually do something to prove
that that's the official website.
Usually it's pretty simple.
Sometimes they'll give you a code to embed
or they may see that you've connected
an authorized social media account
but you are going to need
to validate that website.
Once you've done this, the user interface
is pretty straight forward
and it allows you to add
a card for interactivity.
Then, that card can contain a link
and a call to action as well as a graphic.
Then, when the video is playing,
this will have an overlay.
Now, it might be closed initially,
but with a click, it
can open up and reveal.
Let me show you how this works.
I'll go to creator studio and
then go to my video manager.
Now it's just a matter of finding a video
that I want to tag.
Let's go ahead here and edit
this first one on Luminar.
Now, I'll just switch
over to the cards screen.
It's the fifth tab in.
And you'll see a simple editor.
Now as the video plays, the
timeline will move down below
and cards can be placed at
specific points in time.
Let's go ahead and add a card here
and put a link in.
Now it asks me where I want to link.
Now, I can choose from other websites
that have been affiliated and validated
or I can link to particular
merchandise sites
or crowdfunding sites if I'm
using this for fundraising.
You'll see, for example,
if you click on these,
it gives you a list of all
of the different websites
that YouTube has approved
for either merchandise or crowdfunding.
And there's quite a few.
Now, I'm going to go ahead
and enter a specific link here
so I'll choose photo focus,
but you'll see the link
URL is pre-populated.
I can also customize that.
So, if I have a particular
article on Photo Focus
that I want to link
people to, I can do that.
Let's go and visit photofocus.com
and I'll do a search for Luminar.
And maybe I want to link to
this particular article here
to get free presets.
So I'll just right
click and copy the link.
Now, back in YouTube, what
I can do is say let's link
to that specific URL
and I'll click next.
It's going to validate that URL
and should show me some more
information in a moment.
I'll label this here.
Now, you'll notice that
there's a limit here
so let's shorten this
and I'll add teaser text.
You'll notice there is a
limit on the character count.
And I can click to change the image.
Now, it needs to be a square.
And let's just navigate
to a .png file here,
in this case, the application icon.
So I've got the URL, I've
got a title for the card
and a little bit of a call to
action and some teaser text.
So I can click create card.
And you'll see that
it's added to the list.
Now, it's currently set
to come in at six seconds
'cause that's were I put this
but that can be easily moved.
Just grab it and position it in time
where you want it to appear.
Now, once it hits that point
the information will pop up
and it will display.
There we go.
Now if I wanted to, I
could add additional cards
for interactivity, such as a poll.
If I create here, you see I
can actually add a question
and give people choices
so they can answer it.
Works very well, allowing here
for a multiple choice poll.
Let's click cancel though.
And in this case, all the
changes have been saved
so I'm just going to go ahead
and take a look at that video.
Let's go back here
and we'll visit that video
and take a look at it full screen.
And around 19 seconds or so,
that ad's going to pop up.
You see the call to action there.
Get 15 free Luminar Presets.
Oh, that's interesting.
And if I don't take
action, it just disappears,
not interfering with
the viewer's enjoyment.
But if that does catch their eye
and it pops back on screen here,
if I mouse over it here and click,
you see that is shows me a great little ad
telling me what's possible.
So now with a click, it's
going to trigger a visit
to that webpage and as you see,
I pulled somebody from
YouTube back to my website
where they can engage
and download free presets
and I can use this as a method
to actually capture their email as a lead.
The use of cards are a really good idea
and it's something that I, myself,
need to take better advantage of.
YouTube frequently pulls
people from your website
or other websites back to YouTube
but this is YouTube giving back,
allowing you to take your own content
and drive people to a crowdfunding site
or to a merchandise site or
to your own validated website
and I highly recommend you
take advantage of this.
If you're looking for some best practices,
remember, that cards will work best
when there's a scripted call to action
or it's highly relevant.
So, in the case of those presets,
if I used a preset in the video
and then say, "oh, if you'd
like to download the presets,
"just click the link on the screen,"
people would notice that.
Do keep in mind that
cards are quite convenient
because they give the
viewer the option to click
and if they don't click,
it simply disappears
and doesn't annoy them.
Now, you can of course put links
into the bottom of the
video's description,
but this is right there
on the content itself
and if someone is watching full screen
or on a device that is
really just taking them
into the content,
this will make it that much easier
to click and visit.