- Captions can be useful
to many different viewers
of YouTube content.
There's a large population
that's hard of hearing or deaf
so making captions available
can be quite useful to them.
Additionally, there are many
places that videos are watched
that it's difficult to hear,
perhaps a busy location with
lots of environmental sound.
You're riding a subway train
and you've got a YouTube video playing,
well it's much more useful
to actually be able to read those titles
than just hear them due to
the environmental noise.
And captions can be loaded
in different languages,
helping people with translations
so they can enjoy content
that wasn't recorded
in their native tongue.
So let's give you some practical
advice on how to use these.
YouTube will automatically create captions
based upon the language of your content.
Now they don't have
this for every language,
but they do for most,
and the automatic captions
are eventually created
depending upon the back load
and how many videos have
been loaded up at a time.
Once the captions are generated,
you can edit them so if
there are spelling mistakes
or proper names that aren't
coming through correctly,
you can fix it.
Do note that the quality
varies from video to video
so you might not want to
rely upon automatic captions
if it's incredibly important
that this is accurate.
Now what I find is that my own voice
is captioned pretty clearly.
That's because I frequently teach
and I'm used to speaking
clearly, deliberately,
and taking pauses from time to time.
Now if I was talking really fast
and just going through things like this,
it might not get all of those things.
So somebody speaking quite
rapidly or with a thick accent
or slurring their words,
well a computer is not as
good at distinguishing sounds
as the human ear,
but it has come a long way
and a lot of the technology used
in mobile phones for speech-to-text
is being employed here on YouTube.
So think of it this way.
Once a video is done, you
can access its captions
and this is pretty easy to edit.
You can see all of the
content on the captions
and where they fall at the video.
If you choose to edit, every
single block becomes fixable
so you can scroll through
and fix any mistakes.
To edit the captions on a video,
simply make sure you're
logged into your account
and then click edit video.
Then switch over to the subtitles
and closed captions tab.
You'll see here if there are
multiple languages available
or if there's only a
single set of captions.
In this case, I haven't
uploaded any additional captions
so only the automatic English
captions have been generated
based upon the language of my video.
If you don't set the language
for a video and upload,
it might not be able to
generate automatic captions.
Now if you need to,
you can load up new subtitles or captions.
For example here we can search
for a particular language
that's supported.
And then if I knew that I needed this,
well I can upload the file
or I can go in and start
to create this by hand
and simply type what's being said.
Albeit that's a bit slow,
but there is no auto
captioning for Chinese here.
This would be more of
a method of putting up
a translation set of captions
and that's the sort of thing
that either a colleague,
a community member or a
paid service can provide.
Now let's go backwards here
and you'll see that in this case,
there are the English captions.
If I click on that,
I can see what's been
automatically generated.
And as the video plays,
you see they're available right below
with scrolling timelines
and the audio waveform.
You can watch what's happening there.
Now if I pause this,
I see for example that
it's referring to accent AI
and this needs to be a proper noun
because it's the name of a filter.
So I'm going to choose to edit this here
and I have the ability to download it
if I want to take it into a text editor.
So if you need to, you can
actually download these captions
to use on other services
or download the file,
open it up in a text editor
and make a global change,
and then reupload it.
That's a very simple way
to actually do bulk edits.
Or if you just need to do a quick fix,
you can click edit to fix it right here
in the YouTube browser.
So in this case I'll just do a search
and type in the word accent
and you see it found it.
So I'll change that to a capital A
and it made the change.
There's three more matches.
Let's go ahead here and search.
Yup and that's all
instances on the screen.
Now let's do a search for the word Luminar
and it looks like it
found it there correctly,
but not necessarily in
the application itself.
So as we scroll through,
I can take a look and see
if there's any challenges
in the application with proper
names not being recognized.
Notice here it's pretty simple.
All of these controls are spelled out
and you can see the
captions that are being used
in the video itself.
If you find that if you
need to make a change,
that's simple enough.
Just click on the caption
itself and edit it.
This is a useful way to make
small changes for minor fixes.
If there are global changes,
just be sure to download the file
and you can actually make changes
and then upload it back to replace.
Now to make editing easier,
there are a series of keyboard shortcuts
if you're going to be
editing captions a lot.
I'm not going to walk
through all of these,
but as you see by using some
of the keyboard shortcuts
of left and right arrows
or the ability to use
the spacebar or enter,
this is going to make it
easy to actually make edits.
So you can very quickly jump
from forward and back in time,
go from one caption to the next
and easily make edits of those captions
and then add them into the timeline.
This could be quite useful.
Now besides using the built-in
auto generated captions,
you can of course upload
captions of your choice
and let's talk about that next.