- If your content has been
professionally captioned
by an outside vendor, you can upload that.
There's also great
tools like Transcriptive
from Digital Anarchy, that
makes it easy to submit your
video editing project to an online service
and use computer intelligence
to get it captioned.
And of course there are
numerous captioning companies
out there that will use
live people to go through
and caption the video.
So there are many ways to solve this,
and in fact we do have
some additional training
in the online library.
The important thing here is
that YouTube makes it easy
for you to upload captions.
So, if you have captions for your content,
whether those be the native
language or a translation,
it's pretty simple.
Make sure that your videos are accessible
because of the captioning track.
This means that people who
have different challenges
in consuming the content will
have an easier time with it,
and it may even be a legal
requirement depending upon
the country you're working in.
You can have multiple
caption tracks as well.
In different languages or dialects.
What it comes down to
is it's pretty simple.
You're going to go into the video manager
and select and individual
video, then edit it.
Once there, choose the subtitles
and closed captions tab,
and you click the add button to add more.
Let me show you this one more time.
From the video manager.
I'll simply click edit to open up a video,
and then go to the subtitles
and closed captions tab.
This will show me any existing captions.
Remember, you can click on
this to edit the automatic ones
or click the add button to add more.
This'll make it easy for
you to upload content.
You'll see here for example,
we can choose to upload a file.
We can have it do the transcriptions
This is generally automatically done,
but if for some reason
it hasn't been done yet,
or you didn't specify a language,
you can tell it to
transcribe and auto-sync,
or you can create your own from scratch.
And clicking this will
take you into the editor,
but for the most part it's a simple
as choosing to upload a file.
Once you've done this, you
have the ability to upload
one of two types.
You can go ahead and put a transcript in
or a subtitles file.
And the difference here is pretty subtle.
The transcript is going to be
what's being said on screen,
while subtitles are generally
a different language.
Subtitles can also be chosen to be left up
while transcriptions are usually going to
go ahead and roll on.
If you click learn more, you'll learn
about the many different
formats that are available
and here you can decide if you wanted
to use closed captions or subtitles,
as well as find out what type of
file formats are going to work.
There are many different
programs out there
for subtitling and transcript
as this is technology
that's been used on things
like DVDs and Blu-Rays
as well as broadcast television.