- When you log into Creator Studio
there's an initial view
called the Dashboard
where you can get a good
overview of your content.
Let me show you how it works.
With the Dashboard,
you can control what
information YouTube shows you.
Now, you can dig deeper into any section
and some sections will provide
a certain level of customization.
In order to view this,
just go to Creator Studio
and visit the top tab for Dashboard.
Your view may look a little bit different.
You'll notice if you scroll
down there's different areas.
And these areas can be navigated to.
Clicking on the settings
icon, for example,
controls how many items are
shown here for comments.
And it updates.
If I want to remove a section,
I can click and it goes away.
That's easy enough.
Maybe I decide that I want to
get rid of the What's New section.
Well, now it's not cluttered.
But, you'll see here that
sections can be dragged,
and reordered.
Giving you a little bit of flexibility
on the content itself.
You see it reflows.
Now, what you have the option for here
is clicking the little pad here
will give you the ability to move that.
If you click View all,
it'll dig into the tile and
show you more information.
In this case, on Analytics.
So this does make it pretty simple.
Now, when you go back you might notice
that some things come back here
and it's going to tell you
more about other options.
So, for example, it tells me here
I can add a customized
notification widget.
It's just prompting me.
So, if I click that there, it's
going to give me some tips.
So it just suggested
that I add that back in.
If I click Add widget here,
you'll see there are some other options.
So, if I want to know what's new,
I click and it comes back.
And this gives me those articles.
If I decide to, I can move
that to a different location.
Some tiles or widgets
actually have a gear icon
and you'll see that you can name it.
So, I made one called Published Videos
and told it to show the
four videos that are public.
On the other hand, I also
made another widget down here
that was set to show me four videos
that were currently set to private
or, perhaps, that were unlisted.
This makes it easy to track
different types of content.
Or you can do a custom search here
and set a key word or other area.
Clicking here for advanced search
will give you some particular tips
and recipes on which
parameters you can search for.
Now, this is easy enough
and just take a look at
the different widgets
and options you have.
The big thing here is you can really add
a lot of different video widgets.
Clicking here on the settings
are going to allow you to customize that
and you can easily tell it to look
for particular types of content.
Remember, the Custom search
is the most powerful way
to find particular videos
that are doing well.
For example, if I say search for custom
I can search for a particular title.
Let's do a copy here.
And I'll say search for videos
who's title contains Luminar.
And I'll click Save.
And you see that it found
all of those videos.
So if I want to track
a particular campaign
and see how those videos are doing,
well, this makes it
easy to track a keyword
or engagement within my channel.
There are lots of different
ways to do custom searches.
But customizing this
Dashboard is a good idea.
Now, if you take a look at
the newer YouTube Studio,
what you'll notice is that customization
really isn't much of an option.
We can go here to different
tabs like Analytics
and we'll talk more about these analytics.
I actually think they're very well done.
But, under settings here,
you really only have one choice which is
show me the old one or
show me the new one.
And you just don't have
the level of control
that you do inside of
Creator Studio Classic,
which is why YouTube is
still making both available
for some time to come.