- Earlier, we talked about
modifying multiple videos.
I just want to quickly
revisit the video manager
to show you how useful it
is for doing bulk edits.
The video manager lets you
see all of your content,
and with the ability to browse
and select multiple files,
it's quite easy to then make a change.
Let's go to the video manager here.
One thing I like to do is
browse the content and look for issues.
For example, here's a spelling mistake,
or more appropriately, a grammar mistake.
I can click Edit, and it
takes me right to that video.
I can add the apostrophe,
and click Save Changes,
and just go back to my video manager.
As you see here, it makes it
easy to browse to find things,
so being able to just
look at all your videos
will help you spot problems.
For example, this one
here needs a better title.
I'll fix that later.
And it makes it really simple
to find and browse your content.
Now remember, you do have
the ability to search here,
so I'm going to search
on the word Photoshop,
and press Return.
It's found all of those videos.
In this case, videos where
the word Photoshop appears inside.
If we click here to see the option,
we can be more specific.
Maybe I want to search for videos
that have Photoshop in the title.
I'll click Search.
And that gives me a much smaller list.
So you see, the ability
here works quite well.
Using the advanced search,
you can actually look and
find things quite simply.
And remember, not only
can we search on title,
but we can also search for other words,
or only videos that are
currently publicly viewable.
Now when I click Update here,
it's going to give me better results.
Now what I'm going to do is actually go in
and do a search here for videos
that are currently unlisted or private
that have the word Photoshop in the title.
I want to make sure that
those can be readily found.
So now I see two videos.
Well, I'm going to select those.
I can select just one or
click to choose all of them,
and I want to choose an option here.
I'm going to say that I want to
change the privacy to Public.
And I'm going to submit.
And the change is made.
Now, while the edit is being made,
you'll see pending edit at the top,
but this does make it simple to find
and make changes to
multiple videos at once.
By moving these videos from
Private or Unlisted to Public,
they should get many more views.
Let's go ahead and select those again,
and I'll choose another action.
In this case, I want to make
sure that these are available
with a standard YouTube license.
And I'll click Submit.
And the change is made.
Now, unfortunately, you can't
make multiple selections
before applying it, but
this is still much faster
than going through and editing
each video one at a time.
The ability to use the video manager
puts you in control of your content.
Make sure you take advantage of
some of its batch uploading ability
as well as using it as a tool
to search and find multiple videos
to add them to specific playlists.