- There are a lot of
features for a channel
that you might not yet be eligible for
depending upon how many views you have.
Or there could be features
that are available
that you've just not turned on yet.
Let's talk about the channel controls.
When you log in to your channel,
you'll see that you have
access to different services.
This is where you can also check
the status for your channel
and this is quite important.
You want to make sure that
you don't have any violations
for community guidelines such as offensive
or hateful content or comments,
and you want to make sure
that you have not had
any strikes against you
for copyright violations.
So, let's go ahead and switch over here.
If I log in and take a look
at my channel as a whole,
I'll see information.
For example, I notice that
my account has been verified
and that I'm in great
shape for both copyright
and community guidelines.
Most of my features have been enabled.
However, my monetization has
not been completely turned on.
So if I click on this tile,
I can check the status
and see where I'm at.
I see, for example, that I am allowed
to use the Video Manager
to monetize with ads,
so that's great, but I can
find out more information here
about doing that and enable a few ads.
If I take a look her, I see
that I'm not currently eligible
for sponsorships.
Well, that's because this
is only for gaming channels
and I'm ineligible.
But each tile becomes available.
So I'm available for a custom URL.
It's enabled.
Now, let's switch back
to the newer account
that we recently set up.
You'll see that we're in good shape
for copyright and community guidelines
and that the account is verified.
However, we're not yet
eligible for monetization.
That's because I have certain
steps that I have to set up
and it prompts me.
I have to specify what country I'm in.
I'm eligible for live streaming,
but it hasn't been turned on.
So let's go ahead and click Enable.
In doing this, it tells me that
it's going to take 24 hours
to set up my account, which is fine,
but now it's going to be
enabled for live streaming.
If I go back to channels here,
I'll see a status that says On Hold.
Now, because it's not
enabled for live streaming,
we don't have embedding
yet, so once this comes on,
this option should become available.
I notice that most other
features are enabled
but, for example, I'm not
yet eligible for Super Chat
because I don't have enough viewers
and I'm not eligible for a custom URL
because I haven't
received 100 subscribers.
But I can check the
eligibility requirements here
and I see exactly what I need.
So in order to be eligible,
it says that, currently,
the account has to be 30 days old
with 100 or more subscribers.
Well, this account is barely a day old
and only has one subscriber
because I haven't actually promoted it
or put any content up.
But I do have a photo for the
icon and custom channel art.
So the dashboard here
is a great way to see
where your account stands,
what features can you turn on,
what features are you eligible for,
and what does it take to become
eligible for new features.
Very importantly, you can see information
about if your account is in good standing
and is it verified.
Remember, being in good
standing is necessary
so they don't take your page down.
And if your account is not verified,
the videos you upload
can be only very short.
Google needs to have contact information
to let you allow videos up that
are longer than 15 minutes.
And there are other features
to verify the account as well,
including the ability to
recover a lost password
or other problems that might happen.
Verification is a great way to make sure
you stay in control of
your YouTube account
and these channel controls
give you a lot more options
that put you in control of your content.