- [Instructor] If you've
been watching this course,
you've probably already seen me switch
between the two versions
of YouTube's controls.
If you just jumped to
this particular chapter,
well let's make sure that you
know how to actually migrate
between the two different
versions of YouTube,
but let's start with the simple question,
why are there tow different
versions of YouTube?
Well, YouTube is in the process
of dramatically changing
their user interface
for the backend controls
and that's mostly a good thing.
However, anytime you're
going to take controls
that have been well-established
and around for a long time,
it's going to be A hard, B
bothersome to many people,
and C take a lot of time so
this is a work in progress.
And as such, YouTube is going pretty slow.
They've been at this at
the time of recording
for almost two years
and there are still tons of features
that haven't made it to the new look.
So if you want to use the new studio,
make sure you're using a
newer version of YouTube
by switching first to the
Google Chrome browser.
It is supported in a
couple of other browsers,
but generally speaking,
Google Chrome is going to work the best
so let me show you that.
If you are logged in to Google Chrome
and you're looking at this view,
this is the new YouTube
and the controls for
analytics and comments
are really quite nice
and visually pleasing,
but you might see this other view
referred to as Studio Classic.
This is the view that's much more common
and that we've been looking
at for most of the course
and as you see there
are many more sections
and many more different types
of titles and breakdowns.
If you want to see this view, that's fine.
And when you click on
your channel icon here
and you switch to Creator Studio,
that's what you're going to get.
But near the bottom is a choice that says
use the YouTube Studio Beta
and clicking this will switch
you over to the newer version
which is a little bit more
visually rich and easier to use.
The only challenges you'll notice here
with missing features,
it has a ton of features missing
and so this will help you
understand what's going on.
If we take a look at the
what's new section here,
you'll see a nice breakdown
where they tell you
what's happening with the YouTube Beta
and what features are being added,
how can you comment to add
more, and what's going on.
Additionally under settings,
you can decide which version
you use for a control.
I find at this point that
the Creator Studio Classic
is the one that I have
to use most of the time
to get things done.
But if I just want to take a
look at statistics or comments,
well the new YouTube Studio Beta
is a little bit more visually pleasing
and easier to navigate.
For many, you'll use
Creator Studio Classic
when you're first configuring your channel
and then switch to the new Beta version
for just browsing comments and
looking at analytics later on
once you're established.
In any case, realizing
that there's two versions
of the software is important.
And keep in mind that this is Google
and Google likes change
and I've seen features come
to YouTube and disappear
only to come back later.
I've seen features that
were wildly popular
suddenly go missing
or get replaced with
something entirely new.
YouTube is not terribly consistent
and things will move, will
change, will get added,
and will get dropped.
As such, you need to pay attention
to the core concepts of the navigation.
Use the left-hand panel to find the area
that generally describes
what you want to do
and then look at the
different settings underneath
and be prepared that many features
that you've used for a long
time suddenly disappear.
I was a big fan of an old
feature called fan finder
that made it easier to
connect with your audience.
Well, YouTube decided to get rid of it
or make it available only
to certain types of accounts
that mine wasn't one of.
So in any case, being familiar
with the Creator Studio
or the new YouTube Studio is important
and knowing how to switch
between them will be helpful
so you can find the tools that you need.