- Earlier, we talked about brand accounts
but something comes
before the brand account
and that's the Google ID.
This is the individual ID
that's associated with you, the person,
and most commonly, this is first created
when someone sets up a Gmail account.
Now, these are the types of IDs
that move across all Google services
and you can use them for logging in
on your tablet or mobile phones,
for remote payments or
accessing other Google services
or perhaps you use it when
you log into your email.
But, chances are, you have an ID
that ties back to you
and you probably established it
with a phone number that you verified
and the ability to provide
an additional email
that Google can use to contact
you if there's a problem.
Well, let's explore how this
all ties back into YouTube.
With your Google ID, it's
going to serve many purposes.
Essentially, it's an account
that you're going to use
for access and authentication
to many different Google properties.
So, if you're using Gmail or Google+
to email folks or connect socially,
you're going to use a Google ID.
When you participate in Google Hangouts
for online meetings or
you upload to YouTube
or you go to edit a map on Google,
well, you're going to need a Google ID.
Now, keep in mind that when people go
to access Google properties,
they might not need a Google ID.
For example, if you're just going
to watch content on YouTube,
no big deal.
You can watch as much
as you want, in general
and if you're going to go
ahead and browse Google Maps,
you don't need a Google ID.
But if you want to edit that
Google Map and make a change,
you need a Google ID.
If you want to upload to
YouTube, you need a Google ID.
If you want to watch content on YouTube
that's been rated for adults 18 and over,
well, you need a Google ID.
So, in the case of my 14-year-old son,
he can watch YouTube all he wants
but when he tries to watch a video
that's not appropriate for
a child in high school,
well, it's going to flag it and require
that he logs in with a Google ID
which knows his age because
we, as his parents, set it up.
So he's unable to watch that content
that's been flagged as only
for those adults over the age of 18.
Now, there are all sorts of other things
about Google's community
standards and other things
but do keep in mind that YouTube
does try to protect youth
by making certain videos hard to find
or making it more difficult.
However, of course, this
doesn't counteract for the fact
that people have to self select
that their videos are supposed
to be for this audience
unless enough complaints come in.
So as you get it, the Google
ID is you, the individual.
So if you're going to
have a YouTube channel,
you need a Google ID.
If you're going to be
uploading to YouTube,
to your channel or someone
else's, you need a Google ID.
Now, I probably have upwards of 20
of these through the years
of all of the different
Gmail accounts we've had
to set up for things,
but through the use of Google
ID's and brand accounts,
you can actually narrow down
how many Google ID's you have.
One Google ID can be connected
to many brand accounts
and this will make it a lot
easier for you to manage
without constantly having
to log in and out of apps.
Other things to keep in
mind is that the Google ID
can provide a publicly accessible profile.
This allows other Google users
to learn about you or your business.
Now, generally speaking,
this is going to be you as an individual
so it can include things
about your website,
for your personal website,
contact information that
you choose to share,
some of your favorite photos, et cetera.
But the business or brand can
have it's own profile page
and that's generally different.
A Google profile can also be linked
to other profiles on other
social networking sites.
So Google allows you to connect to things
like Facebook, Tumblr,
other blogging platforms.
And many third-party services
can actually use the Google
ID for authentication.
This can be useful when
people want to sign up
for other websites or login.
For example, I use Basecamp
as a project management tool
and I'm able to simply
login with my Google ID,
making it simpler so I don't have
to set up yet another account,
instead of managing
another set of passwords.
If I can access my Google
device and I'm logged in,
well, that gives me
access to many websites
and not just those owned by Google.
Now, in this case, what you
are seeing is a brand page.
This would be not a Google
ID for an individual
but rather for a company.
In this case, here's an example
of a brand account page.
But let me show you an individual page.
If I'm logged into Google,
any of their websites,
I can click on my profile here.
And you see that I've
got my Google+ profile
which is one way to connect and share
and people can learn about me
and this is where I
control what people see.
So here is my About Me page for Google
and this allows you to
actually see about someone.
Here you can decide what
information is available,
which contact information you share
and, as you can see, you
can also include things
like education and work history.
You can also see where
you've been a contributor to
or custom URLs that you want to share
and other things such
as Google photo albums
that you want to share or archive.
So, this makes it pretty easy
for that content to be distributed.
For example, you can also
let other people know
other cities that you've lived in.
This is currently set to public.
Now that same Google
ID will come into play
when you access other applications.
For example, here I'm
accessing Google Sheets
on my mobile device
and you'll see that several
different spreadsheets here
are available to me, tied
to this particular account.
If I tap the button here, you can see
that I can have access to
multiple accounts on my device.
So the same Google ID
that you use on YouTube
is also used on many other services.
Now, if somebody were to
visit your Google+ page
or any other Google property
and they click the About button,
this is a similar thing
to what they'd see.
Now, this looks a lot like
that page I showed you earlier
for LinkedIn, but you see this
is about me as an individual
and they can choose to invoke things
like contacting me, for a hangout,
calling my cellphone or calendar,
but you see in my case,
I've blocked those out.
While I like getting phone
calls from people I know,
I choose not to let
people call me directly
from Google's website.
But if you don't turn that option off,
and you fill in your phone number,
you're putting that out
there for the world to see.
So it's important that you
take control over that page,
deciding what information is available.
You can have a nice bio,
see additional information,
and in this case, you
can see additional photos
that I've shown and posts
that I've made on Google+.
Here it's tying back to my blog,
some of the content that I've re-shared
on Google+ for people to enjoy.
So, you can see, for
example, that it connects
and starts to let you see
different types of imagery.
All right, this is quite useful
and having that account
profile is important.
This is the Google ID
for you as an individual.
I strongly suggest that you take the time
to clean up your Google ID.
Now, this is a little bit
beyond the focus of this class,
but as you can see, it
contains a lot of information
about you, the individual
and you should decide
what you're comfortable
sharing and showing.
But, fortunately, once you
create a YouTube channel,
this Google ID isn't really
tied to the YouTube channel
so it's ultimately up to you
how present you are as an individual
and how much visibility you take on.