- Another service that
often interplays with your
YouTube channel is going
to be a Google+ account.
Google+ was established to
be a competitor to tools
like Facebook, where people
can share social content,
and brands could connect
with a bigger audience.
Now, the platform has struggled a bit
and has been downsized by Google,
but it still often interacts
with YouTube in many ways.
A couple things to keep in mind,
with a Google+ account, this
used to be a requirement.
Both YouTube and Google+ are
owned, of course, by Google.
And originally, you had
to have a Google+ page
for every YouTube
channel that you created.
They've since gotten
rid of this requirement
because Google+ just did not take off.
Now, YouTube channels are
often connected to a Google+
account, both because this
was a requirement in the past,
and it does have certain
benefits for finding content.
One of the advantages of Google+ is that
it is a social network so you can reshare
your YouTube videos to a Google+ page,
and that content actually gets indexed,
and it improves the chances
of being found because
Google favors its search
results for both YouTube
and Google+ when people
run a generic search.
It will offer up opportunities
for people to explore those sites.
Remember, Google+ posts are
often featured higher in Google
searches, which can lead to
improved discoverability.
And another benefit is that the
Google+ pages are searchable
so people who want to
explore a particular brand
can go there and actually
take a look and find content.
And while Google+ is not as
wildly popular as Facebook,
it does still have a very
broad audience of users.
Other things to keep in
mind, a Google+ profile
is essentially managed by an individual,
and it's accessible to only one account.
So, if you create a Google ID,
you have one Google+
profile that connects to it.
One ID equals one profile.
It's a one-to-one relationship,
and an ID and a profile
page are supposed to be for a
single person, not a company.
On the other hand, if you are working
with a company, or a brand, or a product,
you're going to create a Google+ page.
This is just like a Facebook page as well.
This is tied to a product,
a service, or a company,
and, in fact, multiple Google IDs
can have management over the page.
What you're really seeing
here is that a Google+ page
is very similar to a YouTube channel.
One or more Google IDs tied
to individuals can control it,
and it gives you a way to publish.
Do keep in mind that
the Google+ requirement
used to be in place for YouTube,
so you will find a lot
of documentation articles
that talk about the need and
the connection to Google+.
This connection has been recently severed,
but it is important to
note that there are still
some benefits to using the Google+ page.
So, for example, here is the
YouTube page for Photofocus,
and here is the equivalent Google+ page,
where people can find out
information and browse,
as well as individuals who've contributed
to Photofocus, and a community.
The page features posts
and content from the blog,
as well as any YouTube videos
that we've recently uploaded.
The community is a separate
area that's been set up
that people have to
request permission to join.
And in this case, people are
sharing their photos and video
and giving each other feedback
and coaching and information.
So, this makes it easy for
people who read the website
or view our YouTube channel
to interact with each other.
This ecosystem is important.
A Google+ community tied to
a Google+ page can be quite
useful and a great way to
migrate some of the discussion
off of YouTube to a little
bit more civil platform,
where people can engage and
share content with each other.
But, all in all, how you use Google+
with your YouTube content is up to you.
Some users use it a lot, some
users don't touch it at all,
but be aware that Google+
and YouTube are connected,
and there are certain benefits
to using the two products together.