- Now, we've talked about the concept
of a Brand Account with
multiple managers before,
but I'd like to go a
little bit more deeply
on how you can work together
with multiple people as a team
to manage a YouTube channel.
So first you'll sign in as the
owner of the Brand Account.
Then, in the upper right hand corner,
you'll click the account icon,
which drops down a menu,
and you'll need to select the channel
that you want to manage.
From here you can click the settings icon,
and you'll see the ability to add
or remove managers.
Then you'll simply be switched over
to the Brand Account details page
where it's very simple to add people.
Then you'll need to
click manage permissions.
You'll be presented with a few choices.
You can add an owner,
and this is someone who will have
the ability to actually own the page
and decide what happens to it.
A page can only have one owner,
so this could be useful
if you've sold the website
or had to setup a YouTube
channel for someone else
and then transfer the
ownership over to them
for their turn to manage it.
You can also add managers.
To do this you'll need to enter
a valid email address.
You don't have to know their Google ID.
You then click invite,
and once they accept it,
they'll be connected to the channel.
You can also do this to promote someone
from an owner down to a
manager or vice versa.
Here's how that works.
To start, make sure you're logged in
and then click on the icon here,
and make sure that
you're using the account
you want to manage.
If you don't have the
current one selected,
you can click switch account
and see all of the different choices
for the pages that you manage.
Then click the settings icon.
On this page you can choose to add
or remove managers.
Click the manage permissions button,
and you will see who has access.
For example, we have multiple managers
and someone who's been invited
but hasn't yet accepted.
If I want to remove someone,
I just click the X button
and they are removed
and no longer have privileges.
If I want to add someone,
I simply click the plus button here
and enter their name.
Or, if I'm not sure
that this is their particular Google ID,
I can enter an email address.
From the choose a role you can decide
what they're allowed to do.
You can only have one owner on the page.
Additionally, managers have the ability
to actually make changes
to the page itself
like playlist and upload.
Or, if you just want someone
to be able to send out messages
or reply to comments, make
them a communications manager.
Once they are invited,
they'll be added to the list
as a pending member, and you'll
see their potential role.
When done just click the done button,
and it will update.
This ability to collaborate with others
and invite them to your page
makes it very easy for them
to actually be a contributor.
For example, if you've invited someone
to be a manager, and they're going to use
their mobile device, well,
they can now live stream
directly to the page, which means
that maybe they're at a trade show
and they want to do an on
the show floor interview,
or maybe they need to do a live event.
Well, if you've added them as a manager,
they can do that.
So this is a very useful way
to give people access
to a particular channel
without actually worrying
about giving them the keys
to the castle.