- We've talked pretty
extensively about the concept
of having different people connected
to a channel or a brand account.
And that's very important,
but I'd like to take a moment to reiterate
the dangers of handing
out your YouTube login.
Under no circumstances
should you be sharing
your personal Google ID
or passwords with people,
there's no need to.
Do not give out your personal Google ID
and login information to anyone else
because it ties to a substantial
amount of personal data
and potential financial information.
There is a major security risk here
by allowing people to have access to
so much information about you,
where you've lived, where you've worked,
what phone numbers you have.
Instead, add those individuals
as account managers or
communications managers,
this will allow them to
publish to YouTube as needed,
without having to worry about this.
Additionally, if you add
them at the brand level,
they can actually do other
things on other properties,
like your Google+ pages.
The account owner can ultimately
revoke managers as needed,
so if someone leaves the company
or starts to act
inappropriately on your behalf
posting content to your YouTube
channel that you don't want,
you can actually remove
their access to the page
without having to change
a username or password,
you simple revoke their access.
Remember, if needed account ownership
can be transferred to another manager,
this can come in handy if
you actually sell a property,
or perhaps, you work for the IT department
or the marketing department,
and you've built out the YouTube channel,
once it's established and properly set up,
maybe you're going to hand it off
to a different department to run.
Well in any case, the
ability to transfer ownership
is very important, and this is in place
both for contractors and employees.
It's very important that the account owner
isn't going anywhere.
Now if you are the account owner,
and there's a lot of
things tied together here,
you may want to make one
careful consideration,
if you are the account owner
there is a certain value
to having the username and password
written down and secured somewhere
that if you are incapacitated
due to health reasons
and someone else within your organization
needs to take over an ownership role,
you have a mechanism in place to do that.
But be extremely careful
with that information
because it ties to a plethora
of personal data that you
don't want casually shared.