- You might have noticed on
some of my log-in screens
that I have access to
multiple YouTube channels.
That's because I create
content for YouTube for a
handful of different software companies.
And I also have some personal pages
and some professional pages
that I maintain or contribute to.
As such, it's easy to access
multiple brand accounts.
Now, do keep in mind
that generally speaking,
you're only going to
have one Google account.
You might have a few Google
IDs that you've set up
for very specific purposes,
particularly if you've set-up
separate Gmail accounts
in order to manage your email inbox.
Each of those Google IDs
might end up having their own account.
But not every Google ID is
going to be connected to a brand
or a YouTube channel.
Also, remember that you can have
multiple connected Brand Accounts.
In fact, you can have almost
a hundred of these if needed.
In order to access these, you simply click
on your account profile to switch.
You may need to make sure that
you've successfully
connected to a brand account
if you don't see it in the switcher.
You'll notice the Google ID,
and below it, the brands.
You might switch to another Google ID.
For example, that new account I set up.
And you see that it has one brand account
associated with this YouTube Channel.
If I go to switch accounts though,
you'll see that the others are available
in the More Accounts section.
So you can be logged in with
more than one Google ID.
You do that down here with
the Add Account button,
which prompts you to
sign in with a different
Google Account that you
might have access to.
In this case, I have multiple ones
for other members of my family
and children that we maintain.
To control Brand Accounts, simply visit
youtube.com/account_advanced
Under the account information area,
you can look for some of the following:
If you see the message,
"You are the owner of this channel
and the connected Brand
Account," this means
that you've already
set up a brand account.
Which usually happens when
you first create a YouTube channel.
If you don't see a note,
then you're going to need to
create a new Brand Account
or associate your channel with
an existing Brand Account.
Let's visit that page.
You'll see for example, it tells me that
I'm the owner of the channel,
and the connected brand account.
It tells me that I'm
signed in as a YouTube user
with a user ID and a channel ID.
If I click the link here,
I can actually move things around.
Now, you may be prompted to
log back in to your account
and validate your password.
But this allows you to move a channel.
So, for example, right now
my YouTube user channel
is connected to the
Photofocus brand account.
But if I wanted to move
that to a different channel,
I can do that and connect
it to a new Brand Account.
Or in some cases here,
you'll see other accounts
that already have YouTube channels.
So if I click this here,
it's going to get rid of
and permanently delete an
existing channel and replace it.
As such, absolutely
positively do not click
the delete channel button
unless you want to lose
all of those videos.
So I'll click cancel here.
Be extremely cautious when
moving a YouTube channel to
a different Brand Account.
Each Brand Account can only
have one channel on YouTube.
So as such, you might want to move
to a new Brand Account that
doesn't yet have a YouTube channel,
or be absolutely certain that if
you're connecting it to
an existing Brand Account,
that you'll want to blow away
another YouTube channel
and replace it with the one you're moving.
Remember the Google Brand Account
is used across multiple services,
including Google+, Google My Business,
Google Photos, and YouTube.
This is different than the
Google ID that you use to sign in
to other services, such as Google Docs,
and Sheets, and others.
And remember, if you've already
created a channel on YouTube,
it should already be
connected to a Brand Account.
But what may often happen,
is that you'll find yourself
needing to create a new Brand Account.
Maybe a company rolls out another product,
and as such, you might want
to move a YouTube channel
to another Brand Account
to free up a slot.
Remember, one YouTube
channel to one Brand Account,
but many Brand Accounts can be shared
by one or more Google ID.