- While being connected
on Google is a good idea,
putting all of your brands together
and organized and connecting multiple
Google services together, there are,
of course, other social networks.
Now, YouTube itself supports a
connection to Twitter, and in the past,
they've supported platforms like Facebook.
What this allows you to do is to tie
the services together, so as you put a new
piece of content up on YouTube,
it triggers a tweet on Twitter.
Now there are really two different
ways to connect accounts.
One method is using the Connected
Accounts section in your profile.
This will currently allow
you to connect to Twitter.
You do this under
YouTube.com/account_sharing.
Additionally, you can control what
is shared by adjusting
your privacy settings,
and you can use other third-party tools
if you want to share to other websites.
Tools like Hootsuite
and dlvr.it can actually
take a YouTube URL and
redistribute to other pages.
Let's start with that first page.
You'll see here, for example,
that I can choose to connect it.
Right now, it's connected to my personal
Twitter page and not my
Photofocus Twitter page.
I'll click the Edit button
and disconnect the account.
Now, when I click Connect, it's
going to bring up a new dialog.
Once I log in, I can choose
to authorize the application.
And you'll see that it's now connected.
I can tell it to automatically send up
a tweet when a video is uploaded.
Or, if a video is added
to a particular playlist.
What happens is that any of these changes
will only affect new videos going forward.
If I check Upload a video,
and Add a video to playlist,
it's not going to go through my library
and suddenly send out hundreds of tweets
for all of my existing content,
rather, it will trigger only new content.
Now, if you want to control what's done,
you can also take a look
here at your Feed settings.
This is where you can decide under Privacy
of what sorts of things
you want to have happen.
You can decide if you're going to share
information in the feed for the activity.
Make sure you visit
these privacy controls,
so you know what's going to be shared.
I generally decide to keep my views
and my subscriptions private.
I spent way too much time watching
fan videos about Star
Wars, and I don't need
to share that with the
Photofocus community
who's interested in photography.
What you want to make sure of is that
your habits of viewing or perhaps
if your 10-year-old daughter
gets ahold of your iPad,
all the sudden you're not sharing
toy unboxing videos with
your professional audience.
So, make sure you turn on
these privacy settings,
so you're in control of what gets shared.
Additionally, you can
also have connections
to other social networks
displayed on your profile.
To do this, you'll click the Edit button
in the top corner of the channel artwork.
This will allow you to
add links on the page,
and you can specify up to five
links that will appear as icons.
In fact, you can actually add more links,
they just won't show as
icons on your navigation bar.
You can also choose to add a
Google Plus link as a sixth link.
If you don't use all five slots,
then the Google Plus link will still show,
but you can have up to five other
links and a Google Plus link.
Remember, to edit this just click
the top button and choose Edit links.
Then those will be displayed
to folks as a series of icons.
All right, let's take a
look at how this works.
This will take you to a
page where you can actually
edit information and decide
which links are shown.
All right, let's take a look at this.
I'll log in to YouTube and click
my icon and choose My channel.
Then I'll click Customize Channel.
Now you'll see that you have the ability
to update your artwork,
and we'll talk more
about this artwork in a later chapter.
If you click on the Edit button
here, you can edit the links.
If you scroll down below your description,
you'll see the links that are present.
If you want to customize
these, click Customize Channel.
Now, you'll see all of the controls.
You can decide to
display up to five links.
However, you can add additional links,
and these'll be shown below your bio.
Add the key information you want
along with the individual links here.
For example, I don't need to show the
YouTube page on YouTube,
but I might want to
point people to my iTunes
podcast and my SoundCloud page.
Maybe we want to connect
on Twitter and Facebook.
Well, I can do that.
The Google Plus link is going to be
automatically filled
in, and you can decide
whether or not you want that
to be displayed to people.
If you have a Google Plus page
but don't maintain it, uncheck that box.
If you want to remove a link,
just click the trashcan.
Now if you decide to reorder links,
there is no way to do that other than
copying and pasting the information.
Simply add a new field and start copying
and pasting to move the content around.
Let's go back a level here.
You'll see that those
appear over here overlaid.
This makes it easy to see
that content and to connect.
In fact, it'll often try to pull
a relevant piece of artwork.
Let's make that a little
bit bigger so you can see.
You'll notice that it pulled
different types of artwork
for the different areas,
Google Plus, Facebook.
Now certain content here,
it's not going to necessarily
know what icons to
show, so it will depend.
This same view is available
on a mobile device as well.
If the user connects with a page,
you'll notice a few things.
First up, the artwork
buttons weren't overlaid
on mobile, but if they
go to the About page,
you'll see that those
links were available.
Now the user can choose to jump over.
If I want them to go right to my website,
with one click, they will
leave the YouTube app
and switch over to Photofocus.com.
When the viewer is done and
they click the Done button,
they are returned right
to the YouTube page.
So, this does work quite nicely.
I would like to see that those
same buttons become overlays
here, but different devices
will show this differently.
YouTube continuously improves its
mobile apps for iOS and Android.
Taking the time to customize these links
and build them in will improve
discoverability for your content.
One of the things I'm
going to let you know
is that you want to get people off
of YouTube and onto your website.
In fact, YouTube is designed from
the ground up to pull people into it.
When a YouTube video finishes playing,
even on your website, by default,
it shows other videos that
the viewer might like,
usually having nothing to do with your
content, maybe even from a competitor,
and it pulls them back to YouTube.com.
They click the YouTube icon,
it's pulls them to YouTube.com.
This is fair play, this is ability for you
to pull people off of
YouTube back to your website
where it's much easier to engage them,
keep them as a customer, and
potentially monetize them.