- [Instructor] This course deals,
with the concepts related to change management
in an agile new product development environment.
I'm a strong proponent in viewing challenges
like this in a holistic manner,
ensuring that the people, the processes,
and the technology challenges, are addressed.
This means we're striving for an environment
in which all three of these factors
are optimized and maximized.
So how do we get there from here?
Well we get there by creating another Venn diagram
of course, well no, not really,
but a Venn diagram's helpful to discuss the path forward.
To maximize your learning potential for this course,
you should have a solid understanding
of the agile project management methodology.
There are many fine courses available
on the subject of agile project management,
and in addition, my course on
agile project management for new product development
can provide a good foundation for this course.
You should also be comfortable
with the new product development processes,
and particularly, the change management
processes and techniques used for new product development.
Lastly, this course will integrate
organizational leadership concepts into your learning,
so we'll pay particular attention
to a few key areas around organizational leaderships
and the soft skills necessary
to successfully implement these techniques.