- Now, you might be feeling
a little bit confused
because there's a whole lot
of different things happening
when you log into YouTube.
Multiple people controlling one page,
with one name on one thing,
and one name on another.
And, you're in charge.
Now, there are some benefits
to setting up a channel,
and there are some drawbacks.
So, let's get these out of the way,
so you know why you
might want to go through
all of this effort
and what you need to
really keep an eye on.
The benefits of setting up a channel
include an increased presence.
This gives you the ability
of keeping all of your content
organized in one place,
which makes it easier to find
and easier to brand.
This will make it a lot simpler
for people to find content,
and to remember where they saw it.
Now, a lot of people end
up just watching videos,
particularly because YouTube
starts to auto suggest videos
that are similar from
one topic to another.
This is a very common phenomenon,
and people will spend hours
watching video after video.
But, maybe you break through.
Maybe you find something
of interest to them
and you capture their attention.
Well, then that works out pretty well
because you're able to actually take that
and pull them back to
a central landing page
where they can see more videos.
What's also nice is that a channel
can be shared with multiple
contributors or managers.
I mentioned Photofocus earlier,
and in this case, what happens is
we have multiple people
that are publishing content.
I've gotten authors, and editors,
and people who host podcasts and webinars,
and they all need access to the page.
I'm able to give them the
ability to post content
or the ability to moderate comments,
and that makes it easier
to manage a brand.
I can't keep up on every single
thing that needs to happen,
nor do I want to be a bottleneck
every time somebody needs
to use a video or upload something.
So, this makes it a lot easier
for multiple people to
have access and control.
I also like that this gives
you the ability to monetize,
and this can be done
through the partner program.
Now, this monetization means
that YouTube is going to serve up ads
that it thinks are
relevant to your content.
And we'll talk more
about advertising later.
However, it also means that you are able
to link to your own website,
and I have found that
this makes it possible
to link to products
that you have for sale,
or to use this to trigger
links for affiliate products
that you also promote on your website.
This really opens up
a lot of great options
so you can monetize your
content in more than one way.
And, by using playlist, content
is a lot easier to discover.
Rather than YouTube just serving up
video after video on a topic,
you can actually decide
what is shown to people,
and those playlists can even
be embedded on a website,
making it easier for
people to watch the content
on your website or in another location.
There are some potential
drawbacks to having a channel,
and it really comes down
to two simple problems.
First up, this is one more social network
that you're going to have to manage.
And, one of the things that I
find frustrating about Google
is that they always change things.
The artwork requirements change.
Features that you have suddenly go away.
The requirements to be a member
of the YouTube partner program
dramatically changed recently,
pushing a lot of people
out of the program.
So, you have to be careful,
and you can't put all of
your eggs in one basket.
Additionally, YouTube has
a lot of copyright issues
that you need to be aware of,
and we'll talk about those more later
when we look at Terms of Service.
The other problem to be mindful of
is that this is one more
set of messages to track.
You're going to get additional
comments from people
that you might need to
moderate or reply to.
You're going to get people
who use rude language
that might need a response.
And, you'll find that there
are so many different places
where people can send you a
message or leave a comment,
from your entire channel
to a specific video
to a playlist to your Google Plus profile,
that all of a sudden you're
missing opportunities here
for business or for
customer service needs.
So it's important that you have
somebody in charge of this,
and you pay attention to your channel.
Now, this just means that
there's more work to do,
but I generally find that the risks
and the negative parts of having a channel
are outweighed by the positive aspects,
but do keep in mind that
this is something else
that needs to be maintained and run,
and that somebody needs
to be in charge of it.
As such, while it's relatively simple
to put a YouTube channel together,
there are many different components,
and lots of different
interconnected services.
Wanna take advantage of advertising?
Well, you have to take advantage
of setting up Google AdWords.
Wanna make sure you're monetizing things?
Well, then you need to start
setting up different accounts,
and all of a sudden,
it becomes a whole mesh
of Google Analytics plus artwork
plus third party applications.
So, while just posting a video
to YouTube is pretty easy,
setting up and maintaining
a channel is not,
and that's why this course
has so much detail in it.