- Before we start getting
into some specifics,
let me provide a little bit
of motivation in context.
Just how, exactly, is YouTube doing?
Well, I took a snapshot of some statistics
at the time of the
recording of this class.
And I'll tell you this much.
YouTube is still growing,
so chances are these numbers
are just going to keep going up.
Some relevant things to keep in mind,
YouTube has about 1.5 billion
logged-in monthly users.
That's a lot of people.
1 1/2 billion people log
in to YouTube each month.
This breaks down to
about 180 million users
in the United States, but in
other more populated countries,
for example, India, there's
400 million people watching.
Do keep in mind that services like YouTube
are officially blocked inside of China.
Otherwise, these numbers
would be even bigger.
Now, some folks within
China might access YouTube
through a VPN, but officially,
YouTube is not authorized
to be in certain countries.
Now, of those 1 1/2 billion people
that log in on a monthly basis,
that translates into a lot of views.
In fact, members of Generation X
log 1 1/2 billion views a day on YouTube.
That's a lot of content.
In fact, each day people
watch a billion hours
of video on YouTube.
Every single day a billion
hours of content is consumed.
That's a lot of bandwidth, a
lot of potentially wasted time,
but a lot of entertainment,
education, and news as well.
YouTube is currently offered
in 76 different languages,
which covers approximately 95%
of the world's internet population.
The fact that so many different
languages are available
makes it easy for people
to discover local content
using a localized UI.
And even for content that they
might not be familiar with,
oftentimes people will produce
captions in other languages
and allow you to embed
those into your video.
Additionally, YouTube has been localized
for 88 different countries currently,
which means that almost
every country on the planet
can access it.
Couple other statistics to keep in mind,
91% of US internet users,
aged 13 to 17, are using it.
So the teenage population
of the United States
is on YouTube, a lot, in fact.
About 81% of millennials use YouTube.
And as we keep going up you'll
see that it drops a bit,
with about 58% of Generation
X in the United States.
And about 43% of all baby boomers
in the United States use YouTube.
Why use YouTube and take the
time to set up a channel?
Well, truth is you're going
to reach a lot of people.
So while there are some hassles
and some potential drawbacks
tied to the rights to your content,
YouTube is the easiest way to
reach a worldwide audience.
And as such, it means
that if you take the time
to do it right, you
can hit a lot of people
with your content and
reach a lot of eyeballs.