- There's a key area
where you will control
your YouTube content
as a YouTube creator
and it's often referred
to as the Creator Studio.
This is a suite of tools
that gives you access
to different controls over your content
and different ways to
manage it, analyze it,
and engage others.
Now currently, YouTube
has been in a beta process
of rolling out a new Creator Studio.
And at the time of this recording,
they have not yet fully implemented it.
It's only about half done.
I'd like to show you each for
a moment and help you realize
that you're going to be using
both versions for a while
and even after the beta version
becomes the new version,
there's a good chance that YouTube
will keep the other one around
because people know how to use it.
So let's show you what these
look like at a high level.
The current YouTube Studio
is a simple dashboard
and if you're logged in
to your YouTube account
and you visit youtube.com/dashboard,
you'll see this.
However, there's a very different version
that's the beta version
and this version only works
with Google Chrome currently
and this is the Studio version
that has similar controls
but many things are missing.
Well, let's take a look at that first one.
Let me switch to one of my
accounts that's populated.
Your account may have
nothing in it like this one
when you first start.
When I switch to another account,
you'll see that I have
the ability to choose
how I want to use YouTube
and I'm going to select as
Photo Focus in this case.
But again, only I have access to this.
You would not.
This is the classic version
and you'll see that on the dashboard here,
I get some useful tools.
I have the ability to see different videos
and these are two
playlists that I've setup,
the ability to see my published videos
and the ability to see
all of my private videos
that have not yet been published.
I can click view all to switch
to seeing all of the videos.
On the right here I have some
basic analytics and details
and they'll provide some
additional information to me here
with ads about other changes
that Google has published
that might affect me as a YouTube creator.
Now you can see recent
comments from people
and these are comments
across multiple videos.
So instead of having to go video to video,
you can see all of your comments
and reply to them from your audience.
On the left-hand side,
there are different tools
and I'm not going to go
through all of these now,
but we will explore them in depth.
Essentially, it's the ability
to see an overview of the dashboard,
the ability to see all of your
videos in the video manager,
live streaming to put on
webinars and live events,
community to engage with your audience,
controls over how your
channel is presented,
the ability to learn about your audience
and their consumption,
the ability to see language translations
as well as transcripts for a video,
and the ability to create
additional content.
If you click on one of these,
you'll see that it starts to expand.
For example, YouTube has
an audio library here
and policies about how you can use music.
And you can also lastly
see your contributions.
If you want to see the beta studio,
you can click here on YouTube Studio Beta.
However, as you see here,
it's going to warn you
that it only works with
certain web browsers.
The best experience is going
to be on Google's own Chrome.
Let's go ahead and switch
over to Chrome for a moment
so you can see this and you'll
see a dramatically different
more modern user interface.
However, there are many things missing.
Right now, we only have
access to our video library,
analytics or information about
the library, and comments.
If I come down here to missing features,
you'll see that there are
quite a few other choices
that are still missing.
For example, if you
want to make a playlist,
well when you click that,
it's going to open a new tab
and take you back to
the old user interface.
As such, we're not going
to spend as much time here
on the new user interface,
but I will say that eventually,
this is where things are going
and as you log in to YouTube,
you may see one or the other.
You will see at the bottom
here that you have the ability
to use what they refer to
as Creator Studio Classic
or to use the new
YouTube Studio interface.
Right now though, this
is very much in beta
and many of the features and
functionality are missing.
However, this beta has
been going on currently
for almost a year and a half
and will likely continue for some time.
YouTube is a sizeable website
with hundreds of features
so making the migration is
going to take some time.
Where relevant, I'll make sure to show you
both user interfaces,
but just remember this.
The general functionality
is going to be the same.
So if you know that
it's called a playlist,
you can look for playlist
and while the button
might have moved slightly
or something that you used
this week can be gone next,
just realize that the general
concepts stay the same.
So what you're going to use in this course
and what you're going to
learn is going to be relevant
and really stay the course
as you start to build
out your Google Library.
As you build out that YouTube channel,
what you'll see is that the exact buttons
and tools that you use may change slightly
and it might move from the left column
to the upper right
corner to a dialogue box,
but as long as you know what to look for
and you're not above
clicking the help menu,
you will find where
Google moved the cheese.
All right, let's continue
and start to look
at some of the specific tools
that you'll need to use.