- [Instructor] In this section on tools and technologies,
I want to start with a few observations
about the maturity of the tools
that I see being used by manufacturers every day.
As a practicing professional, I've noticed
that almost every manufacturer has experimented
with a PLM at some level, and in fact,
I can even say that most manufacturers
have some sort of a data management system in place
whether that be a PLM system or a PDM system.
I can also say that most PLM systems
are being used to really just manage data.
In fact they are being used as PDM systems.
Now the distinction between the two
could be slight or could be great,
but it depends on the breadth of the products.
But what I'm getting at is that many PLM systems
are less than optimally implemented.
And I think therefore we have a great opportunity
to enhance how we use them and improve
the change processes that these manufacturers have.
Now thinking specifically about the information
and the systems that are in use.
As a design professional, you know that a lot of information
is coming in related to the product.
It could be coming from requirements from customers.
It could be design and analysis information
from your engineering team.
It could be supplier and service information.
And you intrinsically know that it should be
put in a vault or a central repository
where it can be managed and kept under revision control.
This is the first level of maturity
that many organizations plateau at.
A very mature system will have different facilities,
for example, a library.
The library segregates information,
and that's a core tenant of Agile
in which every stakeholder should have access
to the information they need at the time they need it.
Library information should be the type of information
that's widely consumed but created by few.
This is differentiated from product information
which the product information container
should hold information related to the sellable result
of the new product development process.
And there should be a projects facility, or container,
that holds the time-related information
about the new product development process.
You can think of it as the project manages time,
and the product manages information.
Having these facilities segregating the data
allows stakeholder access in a most optimal fashion.
And that's really what Agile is all about.
Similarly, if we think about digital collaboration
in a maturity state, we need to consider
that different stakeholders use different vocabularies.
For example, in the design world,
the engineering professionals often talk
in terms of lifecycle states, or maturity states.
They will talk about a part being in draft state,
or prototype, or stable where the design is stable,
and it can be sent out for production.
And then released is the actual finished product.
Of course, as we discussed earlier,
rigor increases as the design moves along
and you use the appropriate tools to manage it.
Conversely, the production or manufacturing stakeholders
speak a different language.
They often refer to things in terms of effectivity
which could either be based on a date,
or it could based on a serial number or a lot number.
So to a manufacturing professional
a component is either good to use or not,
and there's no in-between.
As I work with these various stakeholders
the manufacturing professionals often tell me that they'd
like visibility about what's coming up from engineering.
They'd like to know about the projects
that are coming so that they can plan for them.
This is a level of collaboration
and a level of maturity that we should strive to have
to fully support the Agile new product
development methodologies.
Similarly, the engineering stakeholders
often tell me that they'd like
more feedback from manufacturing
so that they could improve the design
or they could incorporate the feedback
into future sprints or even into
other products related to it where they can
fully utilize the lessons learned.
By taking advantage of this information
and leveraging it properly, you can achieve
the Agile new product development process.