- [Instructor] Manufacturers are constantly being asked
to produce more complex products
in a shorter period of time, and this puts a lot of pressure
on manufacturers, as you might expect.
The market research firm Tech-Clarity found
that in one of their surveys, 42% of manufacturers
cited increasing design reuse as a top priority.
The research firm CIMdata did a similar survey
and found that the number one effort
that manufacturers are undertaking is to improve
engineering to manufacturing exchange
for a more efficient production process.
And another similar study by Tech-Clarity, again,
found that 49% of manufacturers say that designing
platform variants is a top challenge for them.
The response to these pressures has been to seek ways
to reduce complexity and create logical relationships
between different parts of the product's body of knowledge,
which led to the design, or led to the creation
of model-based design paradigms.
So, if we're going to discuss change in an Agile
environment, we really ought to include some level
of discussion on model-based design in the conversation,
though many organizations have shied away
from model-based design because of the perceived
complexity and the effort required.
And to be clear, there is some effort required
to set up a model-based design paradigm.
But in my view, a model-based design
paradigm can start simply.
It's, after all, a set of related product information
that helps to define, design, and document
the new product being developed.
To support change management in an Agile environment,
all the related information needs
to be together and accessible.
So, really, a model-based design paradigm
supports Agile change very well.
Now, with this streamlined or pared-down view
of what a model-based design is,
we can take a look at some of the components
that would actually go into the model itself
and the model definition itself.
To be sure, as you would expect,
3-D CAD models fall in the definition.
The 3-D CAD model designs the geometry
of the actual part when it's complete.
There's also geometric dimensioning
and tolerancing information.
GD&T information is often read right from the model
by the manufacturing processes, so it makes sense
to include it in the model, as well.
There certainly should be a bill of materials,
which is what is ultimately produced.
There may be other technical data packages
that go together to help refine the understanding
of the model or capture other intellectual
property aspects of the model.
Interestingly, some organizations have called this
digital product definition in an effort
to the the streamlined model-based design
and separate it from the much more complex
model-based enterprise definitions that cause people angst.
If we take a look, then, at what a simplified
model-based design could be, it could be something as simple
as our project plan that we've
discussed in this course already,
which contains the information about what's going to be
built and who is going to build it;
the actual CAD model and related geometry,
including all the metadata on the attributes, of course;
and other supporting documentation,
such as the specification;
And all of this would be tied together
in some sort of a system that allows you to efficiently
surf from one piece of information to the next.