- [Instructor] A few times already in this course,
we've talked about digital reviews or design reviews
done in the digital environment.
I wanted to take some time now
and discuss the importance of design reviews,
the importance of doing them in a proper fashion,
and how they can support the agile methodology
and the agile change methodologies that we need to use.
To begin with, I want to point out
that a design review is not an examination of a prototype.
Design reviews should be done
well before the prototype is complete.
Now, of course,
there is an examination of the prototype,
as you would expect.
That certainly should be done.
So, how do these design reviews contribute to being agile?
Well, I want to take this back to very simple terms.
A design review, when done properly,
and a series of design reviews really is what it is,
compresses time,
because what you're doing
is you're reducing the documentation,
you're reducing the magnitude of the changes,
and you're getting more feedback earlier on in the process.
It contributes to better change management by,
as you would expect from an agile tool,
providing better information to stakeholders
and allowing the stakeholders
to make more knowledgeable decisions
at the time the decision needs to be made.
Similarly, as I mentioned just a moment ago,
design reviews reduce the magnitude
of each individual change.
Now, what this means is, there still will be changes,
and you may actually do more changes
than you would in a traditional waterfall method,
but each change will be smaller.
The design reviews help most
when they're done well before costs are frozen.
In a new product development environment,
you know that, generally,
the costs are frozen when the design
is maybe only 15% or 20% along.
So, the design reviews should be done very early.
A recent trend, and I think something
that every manufacturer should investigate very thoroughly,
is using augmented reality for design reviews.
In the past, a design review was generally done
by printing out a drawing
and redlining it with red pens.
As we moved along in our digital world,
we started doing design reviews in PowerPoint,
and I used to see many organizations
spend many hours preparing PowerPoint slides
for design review.
As we continue to progress in our technology,
the ability to redline actual CAD models on the fly
became very prevalent.
The next frontier or the next threshold we will cross
is using augmented reality
for a very immersive experience
to provide that feedback from the design professionals
during the design review.
As a manager of the new product development process,
there are several things that you can do
to improve the design review effectiveness
and to improve the experience
of the project team doing the design reviews.
First, make each review session effective.
Make sure that you have a proper,
well-documented agenda for the session.
Make sure that you have the particular goals and objectives
for the session identified,
and make sure that the feedback mechanism
is well identified as well.
To that point, design reviews are most effective
when there's a standard method
for providing meaningful feedback.
This allows the teams to leverage the design review
and to truly be empowered by the review activities
that are happening.
Now I'd like to spend just a few moments
talking about the disruptive technology that is 3D printing
and how it impacts the design review process.
3D printing technology, as you know,
is advancing rapidly.
In its current state, 3D printers can produce
almost production-ready parts,
and we know intrinsically
that in a generation or two of 3D printers,
we'll be making production parts with 3D printers.
This will completely change the market expectations.
Manufacturers will be asked to provide
production parts from a 3D printer earlier and earlier.
As such, remember the design review
cannot be an analysis of a production part,
or even a prototype part.
It should be done well before that.
What you need to do is build into your process
early design reviews.
I contend that 3D printing will also be an impetus
to adopt augmented reality that we just talked about,
because what augmented reality will allow you to do
is compress that early time
and get a more immersive experience
before the design is ready to even be printed.