https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] Setup.py is Python's way
of defining a project.
We import setup from functools
and then we read the description from the readme file,
and we load the requirements from the files.
Requirements-dev and regular requirements.
And we also have a utility function
to read the version from _init_.py.
The final step is calling the setup function.
We say the project name is nlp,
the version we read from the _init_,
the package is nlpy.
Entry points which will create a script called nlpd,
then what is required for installation
and what is required for tests.
We have description, a long description,
what is the license for the package,
and then some information about the project.