https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] Developers are impatient,
which according to Larry Wall, the creator
of the Perl programming language, is a good thing.
Developers won't run the tests as often if they think
they are taking too much time.
Also, in some cases, tests will require
a complicated environment that is not available
on a developer machine.
Say a big database, special hardware, et cetera.
To solve this problem, we have two ways to skip tests
in pytest, skip and marks.
Here's an example of how to skip test.
I'm going to check if CI is found in the environment.
This is a common environment variable that a lot
of CI, continuous integration systems,
are setting prior to running the tests.
And now, I can run python -m
pytest -v test_skip.
And this test is going to get skipped,
because CI is not set in the environment.
If I'm going to set the CI environment variable,
CI=, let's say circle CI and now, the test is going to run.
The other solution pytest gives us is marks.
You can mark tests and run only the test
that are marked with a specific mark.
For example, here, test anytime does not have any mark.
But test slow has a mark called slow.
So now, if I'm going to run python -m pytest
- v test_marks, it is going to run both of them.
But I can tell pytest -m slow,
and now, it's going to run only the slow test,
the test that has the slow mark.
I can also say run not slow, meaning all the test
that do not have the slow mark.
In this case, it will run only test anytime.
You might see a warning about unknown marks,
you can just ignore it, or use pytest.ini
to define your own custom markers.