https://git.ir/
(upbeat music)
- Here's my solution to the problem.
The client seeks I define a variable called "here",
which is the absolute path
to the directory of the current test file.
I know that the test case's file is next to this file.
In line nine, I define a function called load_cases.
To get the file name,
get the absolute path to the file name in line 10,
and then, for every line in the file,
we'll use json to decode the line into a Python dictionary,
and yield the object value, output, and error.
Then in line 18, I define test_sqrt,
which gets the value, expected, and error.
And as you can in line 17,
this is a parametrized function with these values
getting the test cases by calling load_cases off our file.
In the function code, in line 18,
if the function should error,
we using the raises context manager to check that it does.
Otherwise, in line 24, the computer output on the value
we got from our test case,
and in line 25, we checked that we got the right value.
Again, error messages are important.
And now, python -m pytest -v tests,
and it's going to run all of our test cases from the file.