https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] We work better as a team
and a good team is more than the sum of its parts.
What helps us work together is a process.
I see the development process as a set of rules we follow
when working together.
These rules help us collaborate,
save us from making mistakes,
and help us see the work progress.
There's no one true process.
In consulting and working with
many companies and many teams,
each of them have their own process
that was shaped and reshaped over time.
The process should serve the team
and it's not a static thing.
You should tweak the process to your needs over time
and when the environment, say the group size, changes.
We're going to talk about several common practices,
such as source control, issue tracking, feature branches,
code review, and retrospective.
You might have most steps,
but I highly recommend to have at least these steps.