https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] Source control,
sometimes known as VCS, version control system
is what keeps the history of the code.
But far more important to that, it lets several developers
work together on the same code base.
There are many source control systems,
Git, Subversion, Mercurial, Perforce,
Team Foundation Service and others.
The one that currently have the most launcher is Git
and we're going to focus on it.
However, the principles we'll talk about apply to other
source control systems as well.
Git has a lot of tooling around it and most IDEs
such as PyCharm or Visual Studio Code
have built in integration with it.
I'm going to use Git from the command line.
With your IDE, read documentation on how to use it with Git.
Git is a decentralized version
control system, known as DVCS.
This means that everyone who have a Git repository
on their machine have all the project history there,
and can work without network connection.
We're going to use GitHub, which hosts Git repositories
and provides project management features and more around it.
Most of the time, you'll join a project
and then you'll clone a repository.
Here's our project called nlpy on GitHub.
You don't have write permission to this repository.
I recommend that you fork it, create
your own copy and work with it.
You'll need a GitHub user for that.
To know what we need to clone,
we click on the clone or download button and copy the URL.
If you don't have write permission,
you can use HTTPS instead of SSH.
Once we copy it over, we can go to the command line,
and do Git, clone,
and the repository.
And Git is going to clone it to the directory called nlpy.
We can move to this directory,
and see that we have the files there.
Once we have the repository on your local machine,
you can make code changes and then
push them to the main repository.
One thing you need to make sure
is not to accidentally add the wrong files to Git.
Python creates standard Py cache and PYC files.
PyTest create a .pytest cache directory, et cetera.
Make sure to exclude these directories
or files in your .gitignore file.
Here's the one we have in this project.
Cat .gitignore and we see we ignore
PYC, hypothesis, pytest caches,
dist, nlp virtual environment and more.