https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] Every piece of work you do should be tracked.
It can be a back fix, a feature to implement,
or a maintenance task.
The seven issue tracking systems,
such as Jira, Trello, Asana, and more.
GitHub has its own issue system, which is good enough,
in my opinion.
So if you to our project, we see we have an issues tab,
and we can add issues here.
A good issue has a good title and a good description.
Imagine yourself in a couple of months
getting back to an issue to implement it.
Be kind to your future self or fellow developers
and invest time in creating a good issue.
Some themes have templates for an issue
with item such as these.
Here's the pandas theme new issue template.
So when you create a new issue in pandas,
you get a template and you need to put in the code,
the problem description, expected output,
output of the version, etc. etc.
Think about the checklist for your issues.
Looking at our code in _init_.py, we see
that in _init_, the tokenize function is not documented.
Let's create an issue for it.
So, we go to nlpy, we create a new issue,
we write "Document tokenize."
And here we could write in markdown format
the description of the issue.
"The tokenize function
"in nlp._init_.py,"
which lets people know where it is,
"is not documented.
"Add a docstring to the function."
I think this is clear enough.
You can hit the Preview and see how it looks.
And once you're satisfied, you can submit the new issue.
Other things we can do with the issue,
we can assign it, so I am going to assign it to myself.
We can add labels to issues for easier searching,
and we can add milestones to issues saying,
"This issue belongs to release 1.0.6."