https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] There are many ways to work together
on the same code base.
One of the common ones is to use feature branches.
A branch is a part of development path
on the same code base.
A feature branch is a part development path
that is dedicated to a specific feature or an issue.
Once you start work on an issue,
create a feature branch for it
and work on this branch.
A nice convention is to call the branch
with the name of the feature.
We have our issue to document the tokenize function.
So we'll do git checkout -b,
meaning create a new branch,
and then call it issue/1-document-tokenize.
And now we're working in the document tokenize branch.
Now we can go to our code,
and add a commentation string
to the tokenize function.
Once we save our code,
we're ready to go.
We can do git status
to see what has changed.
And we see that we have one modified files.
Then do git add nlp/_init_.py.
And then we do git commit,
and we'll give it the message document tokenize.
Now the branch is still local to our developer machine.
We need to push it to the server.
So we do git push -u, meaning track.
And then origin, which is where the repository came from.
And the name of the branch,
which is issue/1-document-tokenize.
And now this branch is being sent to github.
If you go to the code now,
we can see now that we have a new document tokenize branch.
The main branch might get updates
before you merge your feature branch into it.
Make sure to merge early and often.
And once the branch is approved,
you should be in a code review.
Merge and squash it to the main development branch.