https://git.ir/
- [Narrator] Linus, the creator of Linux,
has a law named after him,
"Given enough eyeballs, all bugs are shallow."
It means that the more people view the code,
the more chances are they'll find bug
and they'll find a solution for these bugs.
The Linux system is a living proof of this law.
In every team I work, we do code reviews.
They are highly effective and a lot of times we find bugs.
It's also a great way to share knowledge.
You can see what other people are working on
and learn cool new tricks.
In GitHub, once you push a branch,
you have a notification and a button
to compare and pull request.
The other thing you can do is you can do
to the Pull request page and then, click
on New pull request.
And then, we say that you want to merge to the master,
some teams use a development branch.
And then, we want our issue to be there.
And GitHub will show us the change that it whirl
to the code and we can create the pull request.
The pull request now is open.
We have a title.
We can change it to uppercase, D for Document tokenize.
We can add a comment that this fixes
and we can add a link to the number one issue.
We can ask for people to review
and we can assign it to people.
And then, we can do a Create pull request.
Once the pull request is created,
people can go to the Files change and add comments
so we can hit on the plus button here and write a comment.
And we do a back and fourth conversation until the reviewers
approve the review.
Once the PR is approved, you can merge the pull request.
There are several ways to merge a pull request.
I usually use the Squash and merge option.
And I click Squash and merge.
I can add some optional comments and then, I confirm.
And now, the code review process is done and our code
is merged to master.