https://git.ir/
- [Instructor] A retrospective,
sometimes called postmortem, is a meeting you do
at the end of a period or a sprint
to discuss how you can improve.
Retrospectives are very effective.
Sadly, people tend to skip them
and they have a low priority in many teams.
You should always allocate time for retrospectives.
You can do retrospective in physical meeting
or in asynchronous way in a chat room
or a shared document.
I highly recommend to document these retrospectives
since they common knowledge
and represent organizational memory.
Retrospectives can get long and tedious.
Here's a template for making them short and effective.
Everyone writes or talks about three things
that went well and we should keep
and three things that didn't go well
and how to improve them.
During the meeting if there are things to do,
known as action items,
make sure to add them to your issue tracking
and allocate time for them.