https://git.ir/
(energetic music)
- [Instructor] We start by going to the issues tab
and clicking on your issue.
Let's say create sentencize function.
And here we write a description.
Create a sentencize[text] function
that will split text to sentences.
Splits on the dot, exclamation mark, and question mark.
I can have a look at the preview.
This looks nice.
I will assign it to myself.
And I will submit a new issue.
This is issue number six.
So now I can go to my code
and git checkout -b issue/6-sentencize
and now I'm writing my code.
Adding new code, changing code.
For example here, I'm going to add the new code
for sentencize and save the file.
I can do git status to check and see
that I have one modified file, and two new file.
Before I'm going to commit, I'm going to run the tests.
And once the tests are passing,
I can do git add nlp
init nlp, sentences, and test, test.
And sentences.
And then I do git commit -m
add sentencize function
And these changes are still local,
now I need to do git push -u origin which is to github.
And we're saying that this is issue/6-sentencize.
This is going to push it to github.
Now I can go back to github.
I will click on pull requests.
I see that I get a notification under new pull requests.
So I can compare the pull request.
Change the add to capital A, so it will be nicer.
And create a pull request.
Now I have a pull request,
I can look at files changed,
and see that these files are there.
And I can collaborate by adding some comments.
And once everything is fine, I can approve that,
I can do a squash emerge to get the new feature in.
And that's it.