https://git.ir/
- [Miki] In this course, I tried to show you
how I work in Python Projects.
These are lessons from more than 20 years of doing so.
I hope it will save you time and make you more efficient.
As you go back to work,
try to think of what you've learned here,
and, little by little, implement it.
Structure your code better, write down your dependencies,
write better tests.
In time, you'll find out that your code is in better quality
and the overall productivity of your team has improved.
If you'd like to learn more about Python,
we have many courses at all level.
And also feel free to reach us out at 353solutions.
We'd love to hear from you and help you get better.