- [Instructor] Let's take a moment now
to discuss the solutions framework.
You recall from the beginning of this course,
we had the three main factors of people,
process, and technology to consider
as we put together how change management
is performed in an agile
new project development environment.
Let's take a look at each one of theses in turn
through the lens of what the solution looks like.
First, from a technology standpoint,
we know that we should have model
and drawing viewing capabilities.
This is easy to implement
and the solutions are readily available.
Next, we discussed model-based design.
Model-based design is a way to incorporate more information
into the design documents that are being created
so that the stakeholders have easier access
to information in a central repository.
This is a good thing to do
and it supports the agile methodologies.
We also discussed using digital design reviews
and the importance of capturing information
that happens during a design review
and incorporating it back into future sprints
or future development efforts through the backlog.
I discussed augmented reality.
Augmented reality, I believe, will be a key enabler
to keeping up with technologies
and new disruptive technologies like 3D printing.
Augmented reality is beginning to be used
in industry for design reviews
and I think it will be used much more widely
in the very near future.
And of course, we have data management tools
like libraries and discussion forums.
I firmly believe that communication
is one of the most important aspects
that you as a project management professional
in the new product development environment can foster.
And the ability to capture information
in a way that can be shared is important
and the way to capture and facilitate discussion
is very important.
Particularly, in our modern world
where we have geographically dispersed teams
and many stakeholders who work
in very different geographies and timezones.
Now we can discuss process.
From a process standpoint,
we've gone through a few of these already
and we'll talk more about them
in the case study at the end of this course.
But really model-based design is important.
Model-based design, you could say it's a technology
but it is also a process in the way
you capture information and reuse it.
Of course, digital design reviews
are a technology and a process.
We discussed a little bit about
how they can be optimally used
and how with the new disruptive technologies
they're coming in the form of 3D printing,
we need to do more digital design reviews
even earlier in the process.
Of course, library management is important.
One of the core tenets of agile is that artifacts
are stored in a fashion that lets them be easily reusable.
And this is also very similar to the lean concepts
which put a premium on making sure
that things are orderly and things are categorized properly.
And then we get the people.
People, I believe, is the most important component
of the three that we discussed so far.
We know intrinsically that a team
that communicates effectively functions well.
So as a professional project manager
in this new product development world,
you should do everything that you can
to make sure that the team is communicating
in a way that supports the new product development efforts.
Motivational speaker, Tony Robbins, said,
"To effectively communicate, we must realize
"that we are all different in the way we perceive the world
"and use this understanding
"as a guide to our communications with others."
I found as a practicing professional
that the agile mindset and the velocity
in which decisions need to be made to support
the agile methodologies can be very challenging.
So what you need to do is ensure that all the stakeholders
understand the communications efforts that are going on,
who to communicate with, and how to get things done.
Similarly, in a quote from Stephen Covey,
he said famously, "Two people can see the same thing,
"disagree, and yet both be right.
"It's not logical, it's psychological."
In the early phases of agile new product development,
when changes are happening very rapidly,
this psychological component often rears its head.
You need to ensure again that communications
are happening clearly, that information is available
simply for the stakeholders to make the decisions
that they're being requested to make
on a very short time period.