- [Instructor] Let's take a moment now
to discuss team dynamics,
particularly related to communications
amongst the new product development teams.
I'm going to be referencing a wealth of information
that's available through
the International Journal of Business Communication,
who has done many studies related to this,
and has provided a lot of guidance
to international teams.
One of the interesting components of communication
that the International Journal found
is that the manner of communication used by team members
becomes more asynchronous
as their geographic separation grows.
Now, this makes perfect sense,
because as the geographic separation grows,
their time separation probably grows, too,
so, if they're in different time zones.
What they also found was that, as the graph shows here,
communication mediums like phone and instant messaging
become less important as geographic separation grows,
and things like email and discussion forums
become important.
Many of the collaboration and data management tools
that we have available on the market
have built-in discussion forums.
I encourage you to leverage those and use those,
because that's a great way to incorporate
discussion about the project and the product
into the actual body of knowledge
captured and stored in the central repository.
This, of course, facilitates agile
by helping provide direct information
to the stakeholders at the time and place
they need to make a decision.
The International Journal also found
that this asynchronous communication
produced a lot more discourse on the functions related
to the question types and strategies.
What this means is,
the stakeholders were talking about
what they actually needed to be talking about,
which is kind of curious.
What we need to do is provide them some guidance
on how to address these challenges
and how to most effectively communicate.
Also, the International Journal found
that the preferred language for international projects
with multicultural teams is international English.
As a practicing professional,
I can vouch for this, that most of the time,
the fallback language for international
and multicultural teams is international English.
So, what we need to do is train
the geographically dispersed team members
on the language and grammar used in international English.
The scope of that is certainly beyond this course,
but there are many fine sources
for training on international English.
What you should also do
is train your team members to speak specifically
and write in unambiguous questions and feedback.
This helps as the teams are struggling
to overcome the distance and time separations.
The International Journal also pointed out
that intercultural teams perform best
when each culture is informed
of the communications and engagement method and format
preferred by the others.
It's very good at the beginning of a project
to establish some ground rules and set some expectations
about how communication happens.
To that point,
the team's communication should be based on a standard.
In the standard,
you should have things
like the granularity of the discourse,
explaining that short questions or short answers
are not necessarily appropriate
unless they're the only option available.
You should also explain the cadence,
how frequently communication should happen,
how quickly responses should be expected, and so forth,
so that the entire team can perform
to the set of expectations,
thus improving the agile new product development process.