- [Instructor] At this point in the course,
we've gone through a number of the components
of what Agile change management in a new
product development environment actually is.
So, let's take a look at a hypothetical case study,
where we combine many of these elements together
and go through a new product development
example in a greatly simplified form
describing the setup of the environment
and how the intellectual property is moved around.
This is an internal or innovation-driven change,
which essentially means we, as the manufacturer,
want to design a new sensor or a new product
because we believe we have an idea for improving the design.
So, let's take a look at how that would be set up.
We discussed earlier about containers
and data management systems that hold the information.
I'm going to begin with what I would call
an innovation container.
An innovation container, and again,
I'm showing it as a file folder,
but it's much more than that, is an area,
generally in a PDM or PLM system,
where a limited number of users can create
what are called commodity parts,
or basically parts that can be reused again and again.
The access to the container itself
is limited to the innovation team.
Now, in an Agile new product development environment,
where you have rapidly changing teams,
you can simply add or remove people to the team.
But keep in mind it's always being kept small.
And there is a reason for that.
The output of what this group creates
generally goes in the library.
A library container is, again, limited
to a number of users that can create parts.
So, it's very, very restricted for who can create things.
But it's meant to be open to everybody
for searching and sharing and reusing,
so it ensures that there's a quality check
before tools or products or parts are added to the library.
And then lastly, we would have the product container,
which is where the actual saleable product would go.
In the product container, many users can create
product parts, and users cannot create commodity parts
because those should be in the library.
So, what we have is a set of rules established to ensure
what types of parts can be created in which system.
Every PDM and PLM system is a little bit different,
but from a system-agnostic viewpoint,
they all support roughly the same capabilities
for managing the different part types
and creation methods and access controls.
So, if we take a look, now, at the next step,
how do we actually model the part, and what really happens?
Well, using good change management practices,
we would generally first create a change request
and its associated change order to approve the design work.
Now, this may be done in a number of different ways.
It may also include a project plan.
It may include some sort of a justification,
or a lot of other paperwork.
But essentially, the change management
technique starts it all.
And then, of course, once the work is approved,
the design work continues, and the second step being
is to design this new sensor that we've been talking about.
So, it exists, now, in the innovation container.
What we want to do next is we want to release that part
into the library, so that we have a set
of democratized technology in the library
that everybody can use and reference.
So, what this means is we've got a situation set up
where we have a lot of core, fundamental,
Agile-supporting paradigms in play.
We've shown how we can leverage increasing rigor
by moving along from an innovation container
to a library container, which is much more restrictive.
We've discussed the library at high level,
which supports design reuse.
And, of course, this fosters closed-loop feedback
because we have the quality checks
as parts are checked into the library itself.