- [Instructor] In our last case study,
we examined an internal, or innovation-driven change.
Now, what we're going to do is extend
this thought a little bit and include
an external, or customer-driven change.
Essentially, in this case study,
the customer wants us to design a new product
using the sensor design that we
created in the last case study.
So, let's take a look at how that might work.
Here, again, we have our containers,
we have the innovation container,
the library container, and the product container.
And notice that I have the new
sensor design in the library already.
So, the first step would be to create a change request
and associated change order to approve the design work.
Again, there could be a lot of other collateral
or paperwork that goes along with this.
There could be communications with the customer, et cetera.
But generally, the change request
and change order start the process.
Notice that I've created the change
order in the product container.
Last time we created the change
order in the innovation container.
By creating the change order in the product container,
we are, again, segregating information
into the appropriate buckets, so that it can be
found later and referenced or reused.
The second step, as you might expect, is to design
the deliverable around the newly created sensor.
So, here is our product as it's been designed in CAD,
and we have a reference link back to the library component.
So, it's important to know that the sensor's
referenced from the library, not copied.
So, in this scenario, we have the advantage
of being able to freely reuse intellectual property
as many times as we want, but not propagate duplicates
and propagate information around.
Again, that supports the Agile mindset,
where you create as little documentation as possible,
you reuse as much as possible,
and you make things as efficient as possible.
So, in this scenario, we have this design that is evolving
or perhaps is even completely evolved.
And we find out that there is a problem with that sensor.
There is either a problem report from the customer
or some quality check, or something
that causes us to take action.
So, what do we do?
Well, continuing our thoughts about the Agile
change management methodology,
what we do is we go back to our innovation container;
we create a change request to define, again,
what we're going to be changing
about that design that's not working;
we revise that component, so we make
the CAD model changes and the design changes.
There could, of course, be a lot of loops in here,
a lot of iterations as we set up our sprints
and go through the design work.
So, this could be days to weeks of work.
I'm showing it just as one simple step.
Once the work is complete, and we're sure
that the sensor has been updated properly,
we release that sensor again back into the library.
So, we make a new version of that sensor in the library.
In such a fashion, we're controlling
the official version or the central version of truth
that's available for this sensor.
The fourth step is to perform a where used search,
so we can get into change impact analysis.
And here's one of the real beauties of this scheme.
When we do our where used search,
we may find that there's multiple products
that reference that same sensor.
Now, our new product development team
can do a very knowledgeable change impact analysis
and make knowledgeable decisions
about what they should do, whether they should
revise the sensor or revise the product,
or create a completely new variant of the sensor
to be used in the different product.
In such a fashion, we have a lot of flexibility
in the new product development process.
So, if we take a look at how does this
support Agile change management,
well, again, showin' how it supports design reuse.
It certainly fosters closed-loop feedback
because you have links, and you have related information.
A lot of this could be rolled into what we've called
the model-based design paradigm,
and we're using it very simply.
And lastly, we've shown how we can fence in change,
which is something we discussed
early in this course, as well,
to where we're fencing in the change to what's happening
on that sensor and then making knowledgeable decisions
using our change impact analysis processes
of where those changes should be applied.