- [Mark] As we come to the conclusion of this course,
let's discuss a few next steps
that you could potentially take.
First, continue expanding your use of agile.
Remember the techniques and tools
that we discussed in this course,
but also remember the human factors.
I find that the human interaction,
or the soft skills necessary to work together
as a functioning agile team,
are very important to train and to stress.
So as an organizational leader,
you may want to put additional focus on the team aspects of
your new product development processes.
I found in my life as a practicing professional
that we can always make the technology work,
but getting your teams to function
is much more difficult sometimes.
That being said, technology is an important
component of what we've been describing here.
Examine your PLM investments,
and examine how your PLM system
has been configured and set up.
In the case studies that we just went through,
we examined how we can use libraries
and model-based design and basically
put together a very efficient data management solution
that's using some of these containers in different ways.
This is all done to foster
the agile change management methodologies
that you need to become very good
at using agile in your new product development processes.
I encourage you to look at how your systems
are configured and how you're using them,
and tie it back in with things like training
and learning and adoption,
to make sure that you're using them
to their fullest potential.
Please follow me on LinkedIn,
I tend to worry more about the
organizational leadership aspects
of what we've been discussing on LinkedIn,
and that would be good supplemental information
for you as we move along.
And lastly, thank you very much for attending,
I hope you enjoyed it, and found it worthwhile.