- Now that you have a
destination ready to receive it,
let's talk about uploading video files.
There are many different
video formats out there,
and it's important that
you know which ones
work with YouTube, and
which ones work well.
A couple things to keep in mind.
That there are many different formats
that YouTube will support.
That's because many different
applications create videos
in different ways.
You have formats like MOV and
MPEG4 that are very common,
and MP4 is just another variation of that.
Or the newer HEVC, the
high-efficiency video codec
which is h.265, which the
next generation of MPEG4.
There are older formats,
like AVI and Windows Media,
as well as the Flash video format.
And these are formats
that are not very popular.
You've also got professional formats
like DNxHR from Avid and ProRes from Apple
and CineForm from GoPro,
also used by Adobe.
But at the end of the day, what
you really need to consider
is that uploading a high-quality
MPEG4, MP4, or h.265 file
will give you some of the best results.
That's because these are
the files that are optimized
and ready for upload.
So you want to make sure
that you're having to do a
whole lot of recompression
or extra thought about the file.
Now if you have the bandwidth,
and you want to upload
the ultimate-quality file,
things like a ProRes
movie or a CineForm movie
will go a long way
and you can actually use
those professional assets
and let YouTube make all
of the encoding versions
for the different bandwidths and streams.
Other things to think about
is that it needs to be
progressive scan.
This means no interlaced video.
If you do have interlaced content,
the content should be deinterlaced
when you do the encode.
Ideally, if you're shooting
video specifically for the web
or YouTube, you would
turn interlacing off.
Other things to think about
is that if that material
starts off as interlaced, such as 1081i60,
well, you're going to end
up deinterlacing that,
taking it to 1080p, 30 frames per second.
Now this is not mandatory,
but you will get
substantially better results
if you do this conversion
on your local machine
before you upload to YouTube.
Other things to think about
are the general aspect ratio.
Most versions of YouTube are
going to use a 16 by nine
aspect ratio player.
This means that if you put up a video
that's not 16 by nine, it's
going to get processed,
and there'll typically be black bars
either on the left or right.
This is referred to as pillarboxing
because of the vertical bars,
or if it has an aspect
ratio that's widescreen,
but maybe more cinematic, well,
then it'll be letterboxed,
with black bars on the top and bottom.
Now if you are on a mobile
device, such as iOS devices,
it is possible that
vertical video can work.
That's because a lot of folks are shooting
and streaming vertical video,
and they're experimenting with
this on the mobile platform.
So if you do have mobile content
or you're doing a mobile
stream vertically,
it is possible that that can show up,
but this is really being targeted
to mobile devices this way.
Now, as far as the overall quality,
YouTube supports pretty
much every known recognized
video resolution.
And as you can see here,
there's a whole bunch.
You can go all the way up to
4K or Ultra High Definition,
which is the 2160p.
Below that, 1440p tends
to be a common resolution
used for screencasting.
And you'll see the very
standard high-definition sizes
of 1080p and 720p.
The other sizes you see there
are standard definition,
generally not a good idea.
Now YouTube will make lower-res
versions for mobile devices
and low bandwidth situations,
but for the most part,
it's an extremely good idea
to upload high-definition
content or higher to YouTube
so that people can enjoy
it on most modern devices.
Now if you take a look,
there are not bitrates,
and bitrate is a little bit confusing,
but this deals with the
quality of the file.
So you'll see here the ability to set this
in megabits per second,
and what it comes down to
is that the higher the frame size,
the higher the data rate size.
So 4K video really starts to
get pretty high data rate,
and so it's important
that you put this up here.
And what you see is for
your standard framerates,
you're looking at anywhere
from about 35 to 45 megabits a second,
if you're dealing with 4K,
but that number almost doubles
if you're gonna be delivering
with higher framerates.
That's because more frames
per second is going to need
more information.
Now that's for standard dynamic range.
YouTube does also support the newer,
high-dynamic range video.
This is more for delivery to things
like high-dynamic range television sets,
although we are starting
to see mobile devices
having a wider gamut than traditionally,
and more screens will move
towards this standard.
If you have produced video
in high dynamic range color,
very few of you will have,
but this is something that,
content that's aired for
television or for produced films
are starting to do, well,
then the data rate requirements go up.
As you can see here, it's
important that you have
a little bit more extra information
to accommodate the high
dynamic range video.
So in this case, the
overall data rate does go up
a little bit, by about 20 or 30%
on each of these common sizes.
Now that's a lot of specs,
and I expect that you might
want to go back through
and watch that video again to pause.
If you upload video that
is below these specs,
what you'll generally find
is that the quality suffers,
particularly for the consumer.
One of the things that
YouTube likes you to do
is to upload a higher-quality file.
This way, it can make
additional compressions
for the smaller sizes
and lower-quality streams
that it will serve up to mobile users
or people on slower internet connections.
If you don't start high,
it's hard to make all of
those other sizes available,
and it really drops in quality.
And do keep in mind that
if you upload a video
that's only HD, YouTube
won't upres the video to 4K.
So if you want to take advantage
of those larger frame sizes
and higher-quality delivery
methods, you need to start
with a high-quality source.
So go with the best you have,
optimize it as a high-quality
h.264, h.265, or MPEG4 file,
and you should be able to
upload this pretty easily.
Most video-editing tools and
their compression software
will also have presets built in
to make this significantly easier.
And if you need to learn
more about compression,
we do have several courses
available in the online library.