- One of the next choices you have
is how a video's privacy is set.
This is pretty straightforward,
but it comes down to
how do you want people to find your video
and you'll find a couple of
choices available in YouTube
depending upon if you're a member
of the Partner Program or not.
So first up is a public video
and this is a video
that everybody can see.
It can be embedded freely,
but you do still have the
option on public videos
to turn off embedding,
but public videos can be
searched and found by anybody
using a standard search on YouTube.
Another category is
unlisted and what this means
is that only people who
have the link can view it.
Now they can share the link freely.
They can send it to a friend.
There are no password protection on it,
but it is essentially like
an unlisted phone number
which means that if people
pass it around or share it,
well it's there.
Some folks will do unlisted videos
so they can test out how
effective their blog is
or to see if social media
can drive traffic to a page.
And if you really only want
people to find the video
because they've been told about it,
well then unlisted comes in handy.
With unlisted videos,
do keep in mind that they will not show up
on your channel or page
and they don't show up in search results,
but other people do have the ability
to put an unlisted video into a playlist.
So what this means is is that
it doesn't show up in search
and it doesn't show up on your page,
but it still can be shared by other people
or embedded or added to a playlist.
Now another style is a private video.
A private video is a video
that only you can see.
Now with private videos,
they're not going to show
up on the channel page.
They're not going to show up in search,
but they're not going to show
up for other people either.
If you want somebody
to see a private video,
you have to invite them via email.
Now typically what will happen is
they'll receive the message
and then when they click
to log into YouTube,
it will make sure that
they're logged into YouTube
or ask them to create an account
and then they're going
to be able to see it.
So you can't just forward
this message to somebody else.
Typically it's a one-time link
that's going to tie back to
the person's email address.
There is one other type of video
and that is a scheduled video.
This is a video that you upload and queue
for future release.
So you have the ability to set the date,
the time, and the timezone.
Scheduled videos are quite useful
because maybe you have a product launch
or a big campaign that's starting.
You can upload the video and
set it to private initially
and then when you know the release date,
exactly set it for when
it's supposed to go live.
These controls are accurate
and allow you to really tie
these to marketing efforts.
Now a couple more pieces
of practical advice.
First up, both private and unlisted videos
could be quite useful for team review
and are great if you need
to pass something around
to get feedback,
but do remember that
anything on the internet
is never truly private.
So even if you have a video set to private
and you've set it so that
it can't be embedded,
well people might still be able
to run screen capture
software and capture the video
or take their cellphone and
point it right at the screen
and record it and upload that.
So if privacy is a concern,
don't use YouTube because
no matter what you do,
once it's on the net, somebody
can find a way of sharing it,
but these privacy controls do help.
Lastly, remember that there
are more secure methods
available to you,
password protected sites,
digital downloads that are encrypted.
There are lots of solutions
if you truly need to
deliver something securely.
All right, let me show
you how to upload a video
and choose these settings.
It's really pretty straightforward.
When you're logged into YouTube
on whatever page you're on,
you'll notice in the top
toolbar an upload button.
Make sure that you're
logged into the account
that you want to upload to.
Click the upload button
and a new window pops up.
Now what you can do is
click to select a file.
Now let's select a video
here and I'll click choose.
You'll notice that it starts
to upload automatically
and from the popup list here,
we can choose how that video is uploaded.
That's quite useful.
Let me cancel for a second here.
You'll also notice on the upload button
that you have the ability
to set that beforehand.
So if you intend to
upload multiple videos,
you can change that so
the same privacy setting
is applied to all videos.
Now we'll revisit this
screen in just a moment,
but it's a simple popup
whether you want to set it for all uploads
before you add them in or
individually movie by movie.