- When you upload a movie,
it's important that you give
it some basic information.
This makes the file discoverable
so people can actually
learn and find your content.
This makes the video
discoverable so people
can actually find your content.
While the video's uploading,
you can actually load this information in.
You don't have to wait for it to complete.
The basic info's pretty simple.
What you're looking for
is to fill in a title.
So make sure you think about
search engine optimization,
giving it a descriptive title,
and that you keep this
title below 100 characters.
Also, in the description area,
enter a detailed description.
You can also put a website or a URL here
so people can go and
find more information.
But this is a great opportunity
to include key information.
And remember that it's not just the title
and the description that
helps people find it.
They're gonna rely on
both of those properties
and another one called keywords or tags.
These tags can be put below the video.
And what you're looking for
are topics that are similar.
So you can tag a video with keywords
and this is gonna be helpful.
Additionally, what you'll find is that
the system may suggest these
tags as you start to type.
So consider using the auto-suggested tags
as they're more common.
Additionally, thumbnails are
going to be presented to you.
You'll have the ability
to choose from three
randomly selected thumbnails
or if you have a verified account,
you'll be able to upload
a custom thumbnail.
Let's go ahead and upload
a video here for a moment.
So you can see the general process
of tagging the information.
I'll choose this Aurora video here,
and you see it begins to upload.
The name has been pulled out of the file,
but I can actually go ahead
and modify that if needed.
Or enter a description here below.
Let's go ahead and describe this video.
Now you'll notice in that description
I've mentioned the name of the software;
I'll actually specify
the version here as well,
the 2018 version of the software.
I've included the name of
the company that makes it.
I've also taken advantage here and put in
my name and worked in the word photography
and photographer into the description.
Now, I'm using a service called Grammarly
that makes it easy to
click and check the grammar
if there is any issues.
That's a third-party add-on,
but not a bad idea as you're writing.
Now below, I have the
ability to enter tags.
Let's go ahead here and
set some information.
And I place a comma between each tag.
If you want to remove a tag,
just click the X box there.
Now, I can choose the
status for the video here
and I'll click on the pop-up
list and set this to Public.
And if I wanted to share on Twitter,
with a single click here,
I can go ahead and connect.
And you'll see that
it'll give me the ability
to authorize and connect the account.
Now I'm gonna uncheck that for now,
but remember this does
give you the ability
to generate a tweet if you've connected
your social network to
your YouTube account.
Additionally if I want
to, I can make a playlist.
Now I'll click this for right now,
and make a new playlist
called Skylum Software.
And click Create.
Now what you'll notice is that
it's almost done uploading
and I can see information here.
The upload has finished,
that's what the first bar is,
but the processing is the
evaluating of the file
and getting it ready for compression.
Now I have the ability here if
I'd like, to check the link.
So if you're in a hurry
or you need to share
the link with someone,
you can actually put
this link onto a website
or email it to someone,
and when it's all done processing,
the video will be there.
If I go to that page early,
you'll see that it might
not have the video yet.
It says that it's being processed,
but the description and the
general information is there.
If we go back to that page,
you can see that it's almost done,
and you can track the
status of the processing.
Once this processing is done,
video thumbnails will
appear at the bottom.
And speaking of thumbnails,
let's talk about those for a moment.