- To add or change a thumbnail,
simply login to YouTube and
then, under your Video Manager,
you can easily access all your videos.
Just click the Edit button
for an individual video.
If you're also uploading a video,
you can change the
thumbnail at time of upload.
Now, on the screen itself,
you'll have the ability
to choose a thumbnail or click
to load up a custom thumbnail.
And then, once you've
done so, you can hit Save.
Now, you'll notice that, by default,
sometimes just single shots
of people or software screens
may not be as compelling
as a graphic identity
that helps you better understand
what you're looking at.
Here, for example, I
relied upon stock imagery.
Since this was a bootcamp to teach you
about new software, I
found a shot of a person
exercising with a bit of
military type clothing.
And it seemed to convey
the appropriate style.
With those custom thumbnails, remember,
the images need to be
16:9 and you really have
a minimum resolution of about 1280x720.
It will accept 640 thumbnails,
but the larger thumbnails are
going to look a lot better
on high resolution screens or televisions.
It should be a JPEG, a GIF,
a bitmap, or a PNG file,
but JPEG being the most common.
And you need to keep the file
size below two megabytes.
Now, here's another example,
working in the logo of a product,
a photo that's colored and tinted to match
and nice big text, making
it easy for people to know
what the video is about
as they're browsing.
If you take the time to put
those custom thumbnails in,
you'll see that they have
a nice impact on views,
and generally speaking, custom thumbnails
will help drive traffic.
The thumbnails do need to
follow the community guidelines
that YouTube sets up.
What this means is that they
can't be sexually suggestive.
They need to be PG rated and,
really, not offend folks.
So the thumbnails need to be really rated
for anybody to see it.
If you do put something
too racy into a thumbnail,
it's going to cause problems.
They might flag it and take it down.
Or if you get too many of
these hits against you,
they'll actually block you
from having this ability.
So, what it comes down to, is
make sure that the thumbnail
doesn't cause your video
to be age restricted.
If you do have an age restricted video,
then ads are not allowed
to appear on your video
if you're hoping to monetize it.
Additionally, if you upload
thumbnails that are too racy
and you are consistently
abusing the privilege here,
putting up things that
are sexually suggestive
or copyrighted images that
you don't have rights to,
then what's going to happen is
that your thumbnail privileges
can be revoked.
And if YouTube revokes them,
they will not give them
back to your account.
There is no appeal.
There is no asking nicely.
There is no promising to be good.
You have lost that privilege.
So, how do custom thumbnails work?
Well, it's pretty simple.
I'm going to show you inside
of the editing dialog box
and then we'll take advantage
from the Video Manager as well.
So here, we've got the ability
to modify the description of the video.
You'll see that, what
it's done, is it's pulled
three suggested thumbnails
from the video itself.
And if I click on one of these,
it's going to change
that to be the thumbnail.
So let's go ahead and set
it to this for a moment
and I'll click Publish.
Well, what happens is
that video goes live.
So if we go to the product
page for that video
and hit refresh, you'll
see that, in a moment,
the video comes up and it starts to play.
And that's easy enough,
but you might be wondering,
well, where is that thumbnail?
Well, the thumbnail is what shows up
on the page itself or in search.
Now, if you decide to,
under your Video Manager,
you can also edit it there.
So this video is currently set to public.
It may take a moment to hit my page.
But if I want to change the thumbnail,
I can click on the Edit button.
And this will take me
back to the same dialog,
or at least one that's very similar.
You can now do additional
editing to the content
if you'd like, or change the
thumbnails here as you see fit.
If you want to upload a custom thumbnail,
simply click the Custom thumbnail button.
And now, you can navigate to a JPEG file.
Select it and click Choose,
and the custom thumbnail will upload.
Once that's done, you'll see
that it's added to the list
and you can click to set
that as a custom thumbnail.
Now, by default, when you
upload the custom one,
it's going to be selected with a border
and it will say available.
You can click on other
images here to change them,
but clicking back here
will set that image.
If you want to change it,
just click again on Change image.
Now, when I click Save
changes, it will update
and that becomes the custom thumbnail.
Now it may take a moment,
but once it hits your channel or page,
that should be available
and you'll be able to see your video.