- Besides the basic
information about the video,
there is an advanced settings tab
that has a lot of useful controls.
This will allow you to
change many properties.
Now when you're uploading,
you'll see this as another tab
or you can access this by
going to the video manager.
What it comes down to
is choosing the settings
that matter to you.
So you can decide to
allow comments or not.
I generally choose to allow
only approved comments.
You can also decide if you want
to allow videos to be rated.
Now the ratings can be rated by the users
so you can see what people
think of your content,
but you can decide whether or
not you want to share those
and let other people
see the average score.
Now there's pros and cons here.
Many people believe that
YouTube is a social platform
and you want to let everybody see it.
Other people feel like this
is more like television
and why do we need to put the
reviews in front of people
before they watch it.
Let them make up their own mind.
Well, it comes down to who
you're trying to target.
Many people will decide
whether or not to watch a movie
based upon the reviews
and this is why scores
like Rotten Tomatoes
and others have become popular,
but there is something to
be said of not giving people
too many opportunities for
feedback so you need to decide.
Additionally, you can assign
the license and rights.
There is the Standard YouTube License
which we'll talk more about later
that gives people the ability
to often reshare your content
or you can specify the
Creative Comments License.
If you're interested in Creative Comments,
be sure to visit their
website to learn more
about how the system works.
Other settings that you can
choose include the ability
to certify information about the captions.
So if this is content that's
already aired on television,
particularly the US market,
well then you might actually
be subject to regulations
and so you might be asked
to provide information
about the captions if this
material has them or does not.
Also, you can decide
how the video is allowed
to be redistributed.
Is embedding allowed?
Do you want to make sure
that your subscribers know
that the video went up?
So this is pretty important.
Additionally, make sure you
take a look at age restrictions.
If you are concerned
about who can access this,
you can actually set
a restriction for age.
This means that only people
over the age of 18 can view it.
You can also assign a category.
Now I find categories frustrating
because YouTube's category
system is very limiting
and a lot of videos don't
cleanly fit into a category,
but trying to make the best
match is going to help you
get the broader audience
and will help suggest your video
when people are watching
particular genres.
I really think that the categories
need to be revisited by YouTube.
The only system worse than
YouTube's is Apple's Podcast.
They really have not kept
up with the type of content
that's frequently published.
Additionally, think about
if you want to allow
community contributions.
This can allow other
people to upload captions
or other things to it
and do you want to see any statistics.
Can the public see
these stats or only you?
Additionally, you can
tag relevant information
such as where was the video captured,
what was the date it was captured in,
is it 3D and what's the language.
Choosing the language is very important
because this will help
generate the auto captions
that YouTube will create to
make your video more accessible.
We'll talk more about
those a little bit later.
And if the video is 3D,
YouTube does support 3D content
so you can upload that
and people can watch it
with special glasses or viewers.
Lastly, make sure you
identify if the video contains
any sponsored paid placement
and this is very important.
YouTube got itself into a bit of trouble
as well as blogging in general
where people were
getting paid by companies
to pitch products and talk about them.
So if I were going to in this video
talk to you about how
much I love this remote
and why it was awesome,
well if the company that made it
actually paid me to do
that, I needed to tell you.
Now if I generally like
something or I bought it myself,
I don't have to tell you about it
and say that I was paid to
give you this information,
but those hosts or those making
videos that have products
that had been given to them
for promotional purposes
or they've been paid to talk about them,
well they're asked to disclose that here
so that is in the system and
not hidden from the public.
Remember, if you are on a video
and you want to modify
it and you're logged in,
you can get those same controls
for the advanced area under edit video.
Just scroll down and
these are very similar
to the upload controls and
go to the advanced settings.
All of the different areas
we talked about are here.
So for example, I can say
show only approved comments
and show the most popular comments first.
I don't want to let users see the ratings.
I don't think it's needed
and I'm going to apply a Creative
Comments Attribution License
so people know that this
could be freely shared.
There are no captions here
so I'll say that this has
never aired on television,
but I will allow this to be embedded
and I will allow it to be published.
There are no age restrictions.
In this case, the category
is science and technology
and the language it was
produced in was English.
Now if I want to allow people
to put extra captions up,
maybe they want to translate
this into another language,
I can click to allow that.
You don't have to put in a
recording date but you could.
I'll turn off the statistics
because I don't care to share those
and this is not 3D content
nor was it paid placement.
So now I'll click save changes
and those changes are
now written to the file.
Now for the most, this is going
to be handled under the hood.
Not all of this information
is shown to the viewer,
but this will control how the videos
are searched and discovered
and affect what information
is displayed on the page.
So now if we go ahead and go
back to that page for a moment,
you'll see that while
the viewer can like this,
there are no stars shown on this video.
And while they can post comments,
if somebody logs in to post a comment,
I'm going to have to approve it
before it appears on the page.
So these types of controls
can be quite useful.