- If you're going to publish to YouTube,
you probably want to get
a good number of views,
or at least make sure that your audience
can find your video.
This is where SEO or search
engine optimization comes in,
and I'd like to share with
you a few practical tips
to make your videos more discoverable.
First up, make sure that
you put the important
keywords up front.
So if there's a particular
keyword that's most important,
put it first.
If you're just adding a few extra things,
put it at the end.
Keywords should not be alphabetized.
Rather, put the most important ones early.
Those keywords get more
weight, because they're deemed
to be more significant to the content.
Also, make sure that you
can go ahead and do a search
for those keywords.
So you can do a Google
search or a YouTube search
on a particular keyword
and see if a lot of videos
like yours come up.
By using keywords, it's going to be easier
to find something, so you
should find what works.
So maybe it's HDR or maybe
it's high dynamic range.
Well, see which generates
more hits like the one
that you're trying to get.
Also, the description is critical,
and you have up to 5,000 characters.
With those 5,000 characters,
you can decide how deep you want to go,
but it's generally a good
idea to be descriptive.
Now remember, on mobile devices,
or if the video description is collapsed,
only the first few sentences show,
so put the most important
information where it's
easy to view, but the whole
description does get indexed,
and this will affect
how things are served up
when people search on phrases or keywords.
Additionally, make sure you
consider repeating keywords,
as well as accurately
describing the content
and who's involved.
If you have a particular
host in the video, name it.
If it's a particular
software tool, identify it.
That's what I did.
I named the host.
I named the product.
I named the company behind the product,
and I repeated keywords in my description.
Now, other things to think about include
making sure that the tags can be longer,
so each tag can have up to 120 characters.
What this means is that
you can be more descriptive
on the tag, you don't just
have to use short words.
Compound words might be helpful,
so if you want to describe something as
Asian cooking recipes, well
that might work quite well.
That way you've got all three
words registering as one tag,
and that can be quite useful.
Also, make sure that those
tags or keywords are relevant.
Don't just put a bunch of words in there
to try to weight the results.
They need to be tied
back to the description
and the content.
Put them in order of importance.
The most important ones go first.
And again, make sure you do
a search to see which tags
and keywords show up most frequently.