- If you have a lot of
videos to upload to YouTube,
you can load multiple videos at one time.
This could be a big time saver,
particularly if you've been
working and you want to put
several files up and then
walk away for a while.
Your computer can continue
to work in the background,
and this is quite useful
if you save those videos
as being private, and that
way, you can queue them up
and then walk away.
Well, what happens here is
you can take advantage of,
first off, the basic uploader.
This does support adding
multiple videos in,
so it works the same
way as a single upload.
Just drag them in, and once they're there,
you can actually edit the videos
or the metadata all at once.
You can drag multiple videos in the window
or click and select multiple
videos, easy enough.
Once you've done that, as you see here,
they'll just appear one
on top of the other,
so if you upload multiple videos,
you can go through and modify the name
and the description for each.
Now let's go to the upload
screen, and you'll see
I can click the button here
to select multiple files.
I'll choose two videos
here and click choose.
Now in this case, it
will put both videos in.
One of the things that's
going to be interesting
is once YouTube starts to scan this video,
it's going to realize that
I already uploaded it,
so it won't let me upload
it twice to the same channel
unless there's a difference between them.
And here's the second video being queued.
If I click Show more, you see
I can actually start to modify
the description and put
all of that information in.
Remember, you can actually
set this to Private
so nobody sees them and even click Done
so that as the videos finish uploading,
they'll be stored and ready.
This way you don't actually have to wait
for them to finish processing
before you walk away.
Now easy enough, if you change your mind
and you want to stop something,
just click the Cancel button
and you can cancel the upload.
I'll do the same here and you see
that it cancels that individual file.
So it's easy enough, if you want
to put multiple videos in, to do so.
But what about if you
have a lot of content,
hours and hours of content,
a huge channel or multiple channels?
If you are a serious publisher on YouTube,
there are other options.
For example, if you are a member
of the YouTube Partner Program,
not a basic level member,
but you start to get upwards
of 10,000 subscribers,
you will see the option
for offline disk import,
and you'll be able to submit a disk
and mail it to YouTube
for batch uploading.
This can be particularly useful
if you work or live in
a lower-bandwidth area.
Also if you are using Google
AdWords to reach people,
you can actually bulk
upload and use a spreadsheet
through the Google AdWords interface.
A lot of people place video content
and use YouTube for paid
placement or advertisements,
and if you're tying that
or using Google AdWords
to drive traffic to your
videos, you can actually use
the Google AdWords interface
and their bulk uploader
to put up video and text
using a spreadsheet.
And if you are a serious publisher,
one who actually has a lot of
content that is copyrighted,
perhaps a television
network, a record label,
and you've enrolled in
the Content ID program
to legally protect your content, well,
then you're going to see
several different tools.
YouTube does offer a bulk uploader.
They do allow for things like SFTP
so you can actually set up
a folder and upload things
using a transfer tool, or you
can actually take advantage
of that same offline disk import
and just ship in terabytes of information,
and YouTube will take care of it for you.
Now for most of you, the ability
to use the batch uploader
is going to be just fine,
particularly if you're
only publishing 10 videos or so at a time.
But even tools like Adobe
Premiere Pro or Final Cut Pro
have tools built in that allow you
to actually compress the
video and directly publish it
to a YouTube channel, as well.
But if you are doing
high volume publishing
or you have a membership in
the YouTube Partner Program,
make sure you explore
some of the other options
that are available to you.