- One of the most common
questions I get is,
how to do I re-upload a video to YouTube?
It's been live for a couple
of weeks and we made a change,
or an update, or there's a mistake
and I need to put a new version up.
But the client's already embedded it
and I don't want to have to change
the URL or the embed code.
Well, if you've jumped right
to this video using a search,
and you haven't watched the whole course,
I've got bad news for you. You can't.
You cannot replace a video on YouTube.
You can simply unpublish it
and put something else in.
Now for those of you paying attention
to the status bar down below,
you're probably wondering,
"Why does he keep talking?".
Well there are some alternatives
I'd like you to know about.
While you can't replace a video,
there are a few useful things.
Keep in mind that the reason
why you can't replace a video
and keep the original view
count, comments, or ratings,
is that YouTube doesn't want
you to do bait and switch.
So when you upload a new video,
YouTube is going to make a new URL
and reset the view count
and reset the comments.
They don't want people to have a video up
that gets one type of
comments and ratings,
and then have people swap
it out for an advertisement.
Some other services like Vimeo
and others do support this feature.
So if versioning is important
with permanent URLs,
look into a service other than YouTube.
But the idea here is they don't want to
really build mistrust with the audience.
For example, if you had
this ability to use one URL,
maybe you put up a really popular video,
or somebody sells their popular video slot
and then you have all of
that traffic, ratings,
and total view counts and you replace it
with an advertisement or something else.
What YouTube doesn't want to see happen
is that people are selling popular slots.
For example, a video has a lot of hits,
and then they put up a new
version that has ads on it.
Or a video is one type of content that
has all these great reviews about how
family-friendly this is and awesome it is,
and then someone uploads something
that was inappropriate for the audience.
YouTube is really particular that
what you upload is a unique
file, so keep that in mind.
But you can do a few other things.
For example, you can actually put links to
the new version using the card
functionality or annotations.
Additionally, you can enhance the video.
This allows you to make some basic changes
using the YouTube video enhancements tab.
For example, you can actually
trim parts of the video,
adjust the audio, or auto
fix the exposure and color,
or blur parts of the video to hide things.
This can be quite useful.
For example, I use YouTube's
live streaming platform a lot.
And the first few minutes of a live stream
are typically everyone sitting around
waiting for people to show up.
You start the stream early so people know,
hey we're starting in about five minutes,
or thanks to you who are
coming out and tuning in,
because it takes a while for people
to notice that the stream has started.
So those first couple minutes are a pause.
Well maybe you trim that out.
Or maybe there's a section of the video
that really got off track,
you can get rid of it.
Maybe there's a mistake.
Well you can cut things out from a video.
You just can't add. So let me show you.
If you're logged into your account,
simply go to the video
manager. And then click edit.
You'll see that the second
tab is called enhancements.
This is where you have
the ability to adjust.
So you can actually fix a
video for exposure and color,
or stabilize, change the
speed, or click the trim button
to actually remove parts of the video.
So if you want to shorten
a video, you can do so,
allowing you to take
part of a longer video.
Now you can also split
a video if you need to,
to make different parts.
And this allows you to basically go to
a certain part of the
video and click split.
And then you can adjust those parts
and then go to another
part and split it again.
Now I'm going to click clear for a moment
and take a look at some
of these other choices.
Let's mark done here.
You'll see that you also
have some basic filters.
Now these are not going to be
useful for things like screencast,
but you can adjust or
stylize the video a bit.
And there are some blurring effects here
if you need to blur faces
or apply custom areas that
you want to track and blur to
hide them in the video itself.
This is really quite useful.
I also mentioned the idea of end screens,
and cards, and annotations.
End screens allow people to tell them
where you want them to go
next. It's pretty simple.
And cards, which we'll
talk about more later,
allow us to put specific call outs.
So if there is a new video,
we can actually link to it and add a link
right on the screen as an overlay.
So that can be quite useful.
So while you can't replace a video,
you can edit its description,
change its link, its title,
put in a link to a new
version of the video,
cut away parts you don't want to see,
blur out something you don't
have permission to show.
There is quite a bit you can do without
the ability of doing a
replace from an upload.