- One of the truly useful
tools is the video manager.
This lets you see all of
your videos in an account.
It's great for finding content
or making bulk changes.
With the video manager, we can do things
like actually see everything.
And there are a lot of tools
to sort and sift and find things.
Also, it's going to show
you everything by default.
But it's easy to change that
to see certain privacy settings
like only my private videos or only videos
that have been set to a
creative commons license.
These filter settings are quite useful
so you can find things.
And you can even take a look
at other advanced settings,
searching for things like who uploaded it
or how many views a video has received.
Also what's great is the ability
to control multiple videos.
This allows you to change any setting
for individual videos or a group.
This can be quite useful if you want to
put multiple videos into
a playlist, for example.
Or if you need to add tags,
change categories, or
add age restrictions.
Also, it's a great way
to check the status.
So on each video, you
can see key information
like the privacy, the publication status,
the number of likes,
dislikes, views, and comments,
and as you see here, it
really is total control.
I have the ability to see
exactly all of my videos.
I can see whether or
not they've been shared.
Is a video high definition?
Is a video being monetized?
Is the video scheduled or public?
And this is really quite useful.
In this case, it helps me understand
the status of what I've published.
Let me give you an example
of using the video manager
to make a change to several videos.
I'm going to go to one of my accounts
that has several videos uploaded.
In this case, I've switched
back to the Photofocus account.
And I'm in the video manager.
This is part of the creator studio.
I'm going to tell it that I
want to find certain content.
So under view here, I'm going to click
and say that I want to see
all of my unlisted videos.
You see that it finds my unlisted videos.
And in this case, I've
got a bunch of interviews
and other things that are only
published in certain places.
Well, I want to modify these studio tips.
So I'm going to select
all of the studio tips
that are currently unlisted.
These have been published
to a specific article
on the Photofocus website,
but they're not easy
for other people to see
unless they directly went
to that article because
they're not listed on the page.
So now, I'm going to give
these a broader audience
so they're easier to discover.
What I've done here is selected
all of the studio tips.
And we're going to make these public.
Now, you see that I can go through
and navigate through pages.
In this case I've got two
pages of unlisted videos.
So it's important to switch
and make sure that none were left behind.
And it looks like I found them all there.
So I'll go back
and in this case, with
those videos selected,
notice that it only wants me to be able
to do that on one page at a time.
So if I switch pages,
it lost the selection.
So it's important that you
either fit everything on one page
or you make these changes
in smaller groups.
There we go.
Now what I'm going to do
is make a few changes.
First under actions, I'm going to say
that I want to switch these to public.
And I'm going to update that
and click submit.
Now, as I'm waiting, you'll
notice that I am unable
to do things while that's being edited.
It says pending edit.
So this is going to take a
little bit to find all of those,
but it'll be done in just a moment.
Now they've been updated and are removed
from the unlisted list.
Let's go ahead and search here for things
that have studio tips in the title.
I'll just do a search here
and it found them all.
Now what I'm going to do is
click to select all of those
and I'm going to make another change here.
Under actions, for example,
I can make sure I tell it
that I want to monetize these.
Maybe I want to allow video ads
or sponsored cards.
If I click monetize,
now these videos are able to be monetized.
Now one of the things I noticed
is that the uploader
hasn't been consistent.
Studio tips plural,
studio tips plural with
a colon, studio tip.
Now, this is a great way to
see those sorts of problems.
So what you can actually do is work
with that content if you
needed to make a change.
So you'll see here other
choices including more actions,
which allows you to make
additional changes here.
Do you want to allow
something to be embedded?
Do you want to adjust the title?
So this'll make it easy and I can assign
a new title to all of
these videos if I wanted.
Pretty useful.
Let's go ahead and exit that for a moment.
But with all these videos selected,
what I want to actually do
is add this to a playlist.
So I'm going to click
cancel for a second here
and say add to
and I'm going to make a new
playlist called studio tips
and click create.
And you'll see that those videos
have been added to a playlist.
Add to studio tips.
Great.
Now we do already have
a playlist of that name,
so keep in mind that you might
have a little confusion there
if you have two sets of tips.
So it's important that you control this.
But in any case, you see that the videos
have now been set to monetize and public,
and those global changes have been made.
If I were to go over to
my playlist category here,
I'd be able to see things.
So here we have two sets of videos.
Studio tips, both public and private.
Now in this case, I'm going to get rid
of that new one that I made.
But you see, easy enough, it was able
to put those all into one playlist.
Let's go ahead back for a second.
Let's go ahead and edit that for a second.
And if I want to, I can
actually remove this one
from this particular
playlist and it's done.
Or if needed, I can click
the edit button here
and make additional changes
to this particular playlist
including the settings and other changes.
If you want, click the more button
and this is where you can
get rid of the playlist
or make other global changes.
Now I'm going to kill that
playlist 'cause I actually
have these videos in a playlist already.
But as you can see, this
makes it much easier
to control how videos are being used.
Now that ability to use the video manager
is quite useful and quite powerful.
Remember, you have great search controls
as well as an actions menu
that lets you change things.
As you start to select multiple videos,
that actions menu truly becomes useful
so you can apply global
changes to a list of videos
or use the add to button to organize them
into a playlist for enjoyment.