- By no means am I a lawyer.
So if terms of service matter
to you or your organization,
you might want to seek legal
counsel to discuss them.
But there are a few things
in YouTube's terms of service
that bother my lawyer,
and have actually caused problems
for me with certain clients.
Let's take a look at a
couple of the key things
that you want to keep
in mind if you're going to
upload content to YouTube.
First up, if you've never read them,
I would strongly suggest
that you take a look at
the terms of service.
There is a link on most pages on YouTube,
and this conveys additional information.
Some of the categories,
we'll talk about what
you can do if you're
using the paid version
of YouTube for subscriptions.
Things like YouTube Red
or YouTube television.
You'll also see additional information
there about community guidelines
and copyright notices,
but the one that you should
really take a look at
is the general terms of service.
And by uploading to YouTube,
you agree to these terms of service.
The big section that you
want to pay attention to is
the Your Content and Conduct.
For example, you'll notice
that YouTube does not
guarantee confidentiality.
So just because you upload
a video and set it private,
does not mean that YouTube
has to keep it private.
It does say that you are responsible
for the content and consequences.
So by publishing it to YouTube,
they're not responsible
for any legal issues
that you might face for upload.
And if you're putting this up on YouTube,
you basically give YouTube
a license to patent,
trademark, trade secrets,
copyright or other proprietary
rights in the content.
This doesn't mean that they own it,
but you're saying that you have
the rights to publish this,
and YouTube is able to actually see this,
and reshare the content
without legal repercussions.
So if someone in your company
uploads a video to YouTube
and reveals trade secrets,
well, YouTube is not liable.
Now, YouTube does say that
you actually own your content.
For clarity, you retain all
of your ownership rights.
However, and this is a big however,
you grant YouTube a worldwide
nonexclusive royalty-free,
sublicensable, and
transferable license to use,
reproduce, distribute, and
prepare derivative works.
Let me break that down.
Yes, you own your stuff,
but you've given it to another company,
who can remix it, share it,
license it and take money for it,
monetize it, put it anywhere they want,
change it and do whatever they need to
to it with you having no say whatsoever.
Now, when people complain about this,
I point out to them a real simple fact.
You get what you pay for.
YouTube is a free service,
and Google needs to monetize that content.
So they're going to put ads on it.
They're going to license it,
they might even sell your content
or put it into a subscription service
and not share the revenue with you.
If this bothers you, or you need
to maintain your legal rights,
take a look at a plethora
of other hosting solutions
that are out there that have
different terms of service,
particularly ones where
you pay to host the video.
Most paid services, such as Vimeo,
will say that you own your content,
and that those rights are
much more restricted on behalf
of the other company,
because you're paying
for that hosting service.
But with YouTube, you're not paying.
Therefore, you're giving
up a tremendous amount
of rights, and while that
might not bother you,
make sure it doesn't bother
the company or the client
that you're doing work for.
Other things to think about.
You agreed that the content does not
have copyrighted materials in it.
And that you have the
rights to put this up.
So you are saying that you
bear the responsibility
that you have the rights to post.
It also says that you're
not going to violate
the community guidelines
which are well-suited
and you should look at
those community guidelines.
There's lots of things
that YouTube wants you
to follow about what's acceptable to post.
Also, YouTube does not imply endorsement.
Just because something is on YouTube,
doesn't mean that YouTube believes in it.
So if somebody posts
something hateful or something
that shouldn't be shared,
YouTube does reserve the
rights to remove the content
with no notification.
Additionally, YouTube does
support copyright enforcement.
So if you find that your content
has been shared illegally,
there are ways to submit
a copyright complaint.
And this allows you to take down content
that you are the rightful
copyright holder on.
But keep in mind, don't
do this frivolously.
If you start to submit copyright
takedown claims on content
that isn't yours, you can
actually face legal problems.
Copyright violation is something
YouTube takes seriously,
as serious as we can say
that they take no responsibilities for it,
and they're not going to be held liable if
somebody violates someone's copyright,
but they will enforce a takedown
and pull down content that
shouldn't be uploaded.
Additionally, for content that others own,
through the content ID system,
they do pay out money
and damages and loyalties
or revenue from the ads
to those content holders.
So YouTube, as it has matured,
has taken copyright more seriously,
and does try to enforce copyright
and create an environment
where copyright violation doesn't happen.
But with all of those
billions of hours of content,
it's pretty hard to enforce.
So it relies upon a system
of people filing claims when they feel
like their content has
been misused or stolen.
So do keep in mind that YouTube
is a very interesting
quagmire of copyright issues.
And if this is problematic to
your organization or company,
make sure you explore it
and discuss it with a
lawyer before you upload.