- [Instructor] Let's start with
one of the most important
pieces of artwork
that you're going to
need for your channel,
and that is the icon for your
brand or you as an individual.
Now getting an icon that works
at a small size is important.
Let's go over the specs
and then I'll show you some
design strategies using a
tool like Adobe Photoshop.
With your channel icon, make
sure you choose an image
that's going to be recognizable
and work at a small size.
You don't want too much detail.
Essentially, the icon
is shown on most devices
at 98 pixels by 98 pixels,
but it's a good idea to design this
at an 800 by 800 square at least
for future-proofing, in case
Google makes some changes.
Animated GIFs are not
allowed for your profile icon
or your channel icon.
And be sure that you
also avoid things like
nudity, celebrities,
and copyrighted photos
that you don't have the rights to.
Now depending upon how you access this,
it might be shown as a circle or a square,
so it's important that you pay attention
to this when designing.
If it's a square logo,
you're going to want to
shrink it down to fit
inside of a smaller circle.
That's because, depending upon the device,
it shows up differently.
For example, for some odd reason,
Google's desktop team tends to use
a square icon when accessing YouTube.
But if you browse on any
of their mobile devices,
it shows up as a circle.
This does mean that,
as you design an icon,
it needs to work in both environments.
Let's switch to a tool
like Adobe Photoshop.
And what you'll wanna do
is create a new document
and size it to be a square.
Remember, the minimum
is 800 by 800 pixels.
And click Create.
Now you can use the command
File, Place Embedded,
to navigate to another file.
Inside of the exercise folder,
I put a few items together.
And from the logos folder here,
I'm just going to choose this PNG icon.
And click Place.
I can adjust the size of this very easily,
I'm just holding down
Shift + Alt to control it,
and when I press Return,
it redraws the file.
You can also do this with
vector files or other elements.
You might choose to put a
sample color back there.
So if I want a color, I
can load something that's
complimentary and start to put it behind.
I find that using the Hue
command can be quite useful.
This way, I can easily
adjust the artwork behind
until I find something
that's complimentary.
And click OK.
Then, simply save this.
I suggest if using a tool like Photoshop,
you use the Save for Web command,
which is found under the Export menu,
and this will allow you to
easily create a new file.
For the social icon, a JPEG at
high quality is a good idea.
Just click Save, and you
can create the new file.
Now, I'll click Cancel because
I've already made this icon for upload,
but that's basically the workflow.
Make a square, drag in a logo or a photo,
and then save it out.
Do keep in mind that the
logo might be cropped
to a circle when displayed on YouTube.
So if you place a square logo,
you'll need to inset it
so it's a bit smaller
and fits inside an inner circle.