- Designing a banner for
your channel is quite tricky.
That's because YouTube serves
up three different sizes
depending upon what platform you're using,
desktop computer, mobile
device, and a television.
Remember, a lot of TVs have
access to YouTube channels.
Internet connected TVs have become
a big part of people's homes
and instead of watching cable,
a lot of folks simply browse to YouTube
and find channels that
they're interested in.
Well, in any case, all of
these different platforms
can also serve up variance
because the phones have
different size screens.
As do the tablets.
And sometimes the resolution may change
based upon user settings.
As such, it gets pretty tricky.
But here are a few guidelines.
When it comes to making
channel art or a banner,
I always go with a template.
And I'll show you that in a moment.
But the minimum dimensions
are 2048 x 1152.
So if the image is lower than this,
it cannot be uploaded as artwork.
Make sure that the safe area
for the text is 1546 x 423.
This is a smaller component,
meaning that anything
that has text or logos
that you want to be read
has to be shrunk down
and placed in the center.
If an image is larger, then chances are
YouTube will crop away
some of the information.
The maximum width that you can
upload is 2560 pixels by 423.
This can get a little tricky.
If you upload larger, it's
going to crop it and resize.
What this really means here
is that the middle area
is always going to be visible.
So if you are going to build something
and you want it to be
skinny, this is the size.
Now, depending upon the device,
those areas might get cropped
or padded with a color.
The file also must be smaller
than six megabytes in order to upload.
Which shouldn't be a
problem if you save a JPEG.
There is a template file available.
And here's the direct link
to the support article.
But if you just do a search
on the YouTube help page
for channel art template,
you'll find this.
And in fact, a link is built
into the uploader as well.
You want to use this template.
It's available both as a PNG file,
if you're using other tools,
or a Photoshop template,
making it a lot easier.
This helps you understand
the different devices,
such as television, desktop, and tablet.
These devices will vary depending upon
the width of the screen
and what people are using.
Here's the image that I
was working with earlier.
And you see, if I turn on the PSD overlay,
there's actually a folder here
with all of those guidelines,
making it easier to see the content.
Let me turn off the
background photo for a moment
and you can see that I've
trapped the logo in the center.
Now I decided to nudge that to the side
because sometimes YouTube
puts other information
here on the right.
But if you wanted to center
that, you can do that as well.
Just select the item
and the background layer
and using a tool like the move tool,
you'll see options for alignment.
Now let's build this.
If you take a look at
the folder, I've included
a download copy of that official
YouTube channel template.
Just double-click to open it.
You may need to update the fonts.
Then, select your background layer
by choosing file, place embedded.
Navigate to the artwork
that you want to use.
I've put it in this sources folder here.
And I can choose this banner.
Now, I just need to adjust the size.
Holding down shift and
option, I can constrain it
so it scales up from the middle.
And then press return.
Then choose file, place embedded,
and navigate to the logo
that you want to use
and click place.
You can now adjust the size.
Holding down shift and option
to make it easier to place it.
Now, so that was more readable,
I chose to add an overlay.
I simply chose a Photoshop
color overlay style
and layered on white at 100% opacity,
making the logo cut a bit
better against the backdrop.
Before you save this off,
turn off the overlay layer
that shows you the template guidelines.
Now, you can simply say file,
export,
save for web.
Save off a high or medium quality JPEG
and it's ready for upload to YouTube.
I'll just set this to JPEG high
and click save
and let's call this channel art
pdp
2.
And I'll save this into folder 4.0,
where I'm working currently
and click save.
Now if I switch back to YouTube
and make sure I'm logged
into the correct channel.
Let's go ahead and switch here.
I can now choose to view my channel,
and I'll simply click
the photo button here.
And I can select a new image.
Let's go to folder 4.0
and I'll choose that
new image that I created
and click choose.
It uploads.
And I get a preview of
how it's going to look
on my different devices.
When satisfied, I'll click select.
Now if you don't build a template out
and you're just uploading a photo,
you might take advantage
of the auto-enhance feature
which will attempt to automatically
boost color and contrast.
But if you've built this
yourself and you used
a graphics editing tool,
you're probably okay as is.
So I'll just click select
and it updates and adds that in.
So you see that the page now
takes on the new branding.