- Another option you have that you can add
to all of your videos
is a branding watermark.
This is useful because
it essentially serves
as a subscribe button,
so as people watch your
video on other places
such as Search, they're actually prompted
and it has a little branding icon,
to help establish who made the video.
Let me show how this works,
now the subscribe button is a watermark
that goes over the corners of your video,
and it will work if
the videos are embedded
or shared on other platforms.
When you add the watermark,
people can hover over it
and if they click, it will subscribe them.
Do keep in mind that this
subscription component
only works on a desktop
computer at this time.
It's not shown to people
who've already subscribed to your video.
Some people will add the word,
subscribe to their button as well,
it's up to you.
It should be a PNG file
with transparency though,
so use a graphics editing tool,
like Photoshop or Photoshop
Elements to make this easier.
Now with the watermark,
it's going to work in
only specific circumstances,
but in general these
are the most common ones
and it's pretty useful.
It will only work on videos
that are in landscape view,
so if you're on a computer
or a mobile device
that's turned into landscape view,
you will see the watermark.
But remember, the watermark
is not clickable on mobile,
but it does serve to help brand
and can get your identity out there
to make it easier for people
to know what they're watching.
The channel watermarks will not appear
in custom YouTube players
or third party ones,
or if you're using the older
Adobe Flash based YouTube player.
So how exactly do you add the watermark?
Well it's essentially going to be
a higher resolution social media icon,
maybe the logo you made
for your channel icon
but simplified to a simple,
single color, or fewer colors
and make sure that it has transparency,
then it's pretty simple.
To add a watermark,
just sign into YouTube,
go to the Creator Studio section
and make sure that you
access all of the controls,
from there, you can choose
Channel, and then Branding,
click to add a watermark
and then follow the
on-screen instructions.
So let me show you,
when I'm logged in, I'll go
ahead and choose Creator Studio,
now I'll go to Channel,
and select Branding.
From here, click to add a watermark,
it gives you a little bit
of additional information
on what it thinks works best,
choose the file and
I've already placed one
inside a folder for here,
I'm just going to choose the PNG file,
here's a larger one, that's not square,
and here's a smaller
one, let's click Choose.
When ready I can click Save,
and it should add it in,
there it is, looks good
and I'll click Save.
It gives you a preview
of what it's going to
look like over the video,
you could decide how long you
want to wait for it to appear,
many folks wait a few seconds
after the video starts so
it appears and fades on,
but you can decide if you want
it up for the entire video
or how close it comes up to
the end as a call to action
when people are watching,
I generally recommend a custom start time
or the entire video duration,
then just click Update to have it store,
and it's now saved.