- Before you go forward and start to do
more things with your channel,
it's a good idea to verify your channel.
YouTube wants a phone number
so they can reach you.
And they're going to
send you a text message
to your mobile device
to verify the account.
The thought being is that
people keep their phone
numbers for a long time;
much longer than they do an
email address in most cases.
So by verifying your account,
additional features will become updated
and the account will be much easier
for people to search and find,
as well as you'll see later,
you can unlock advanced
tools like longer videos
and other settings like streaming.
To do this, you'll need a mobile phone.
On the page, you're going
to want to make sure
you're logged in and choose
to go to Creator Studio.
Then, go to Channel,
and click the Verify button.
You'll see that until you verify,
many other services are
marked as ineligible.
Let's click Verify.
It now asks me to choose a
country where you're based.
You can get a phone call if you don't
have a cell phone that
can get text messages,
and Google will read
the number out to you.
Or you can go ahead and have
them text you that information.
When ready, click Submit.
On your mobile device, you
may see a text message.
If you're using a service
like Apple's Messages,
it might appear on more than one device.
This code is going to be
uniquely generated each time.
Let's go ahead and enter that code in.
And now it's verified.
I can click Continue.
You'll now see that access
like longer videos become available.
And options to live stream can be enabled.
But we'll do that a little bit later.
If we click through and take
a look at our account there,
you'll star to see it.
And now the page is verified.
Let's go ahead here to
the actual Settings here.
And I'll choose to take a quick look.
Let's open up the Advanced tab,
the Channel, and Editing on Google.
Here you'll be able to see the info.
Remember, you can click and
make updates quite simply.
The phone number that you added
has not yet appeared here on the page.
Remember, you can click
to edit this information.
If you want to add additional info.,
clicking the Plus button
here is going to allow you
to add contact information,
websites, or other content.
I'll click Cancel for now.
Additionally, the Verified
page is now going to be
easier for people to find in Search.
Let's go back to our channel
settings for a moment.
And if I scroll down, you'll
see other options here.
Including Custom URL.
This is the last key
component to branding,
however, I'm not currently eligible yet
because I don't have enough subscribers.
If you click on the link,
you'll see that it gives you information
about what it takes to become eligible.
So for example, as the
general requirement,
you see that you need to get
up to a hundred or more subscribers,
and that the account needs
to be at least 30 days old.
You'll need to have
uploaded the channel icon
and the channel art.
So start posting videos and
getting other folks to join in.
Once you get those hundred subscribers
and your page is at least a month old,
you'll be able to assign a custom URL
which will make it that much
easier for people to find you
when they start to search
for you on YouTube.