- [Instructor] So why do we talk about change at all?
Well, the new product development process
is all about solving problems, and the changes are often
the problem statements that the engineering
and design professionals use as input
for the design tasks.
A change may describe some new intellectual property
that has to be created, a new design that has
to be created based on customer requirements, and so forth.
Conversely, a change may arise from,
shall we say, opportunities of a product
that's not performing up to expectations in the field.
Despite the fact that change is at the very core
of engineering, it also elicits a lot of emotions
amongst the stakeholders involved in the change process.
In this course, we'll examine how change
can be leveraged in an Agile new product
development environment and how to make change
a bit less painful along the way.
If we continue exploring this concept
of why change is painful, we can even trace
some of the roots back to the education
that engineering professionals get.
For example, according to Syracuse University's
Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering,
leading texts say that by controlling change,
you control cost, so it is a vital organ
of the business and should be run efficiently.
One can see from this quote how change
is being positioned and used not only
as a restrictive measure for engineering,
but as a cost control measure for the business.
Similarly, the Institute of Product Development
at the Technical University of Munich, Germany,
says that the leading text describes
the reason for change is for controlling
design changes is to restrict
the otherwise limitless creativity of designers
in order to keep the design
within the budget and time-scale.
Again, change is being positioned
as a very restrictive measure
as opposed to an Agile-mindset-like opportunity
to involve customers, to define customer requirements,
and to create greater customer satisfaction.
So we need to look at how we can reposition change
in the Agile mindset, but there's slightly more
that we need to consider first.
Another reason change is viewed as painful
is because there are many International Standards
that have very specific requirements around change.
For example, if we were to look at the ISO 13485 documents
which describe the new product development processes
and change processes in the medical device industry
and the ISO 16949 documentation
that describes similar processes
in the automotive supply chain industry,
we would find a lot of commonalities.
Some of the commonalities and some of the major findings
related to change is that the standards require
all design changes to be documented
before their implementation.
Now this is definitely at odds with the Agile mindset
that says documentation should be secondary
and the final product is what you're really working towards.
Similarly, the standards require that all design changes
are to be reviewed and approved by authorized personnel
before their implementation.
Again, this is out of alignment with the Agile mindset
of making changes and making improvements
as you go along so that the product evolves very rapidly.
And lastly about International Standards,
The International Standards prescribes some other
requirements of the change process.
So these standards as we've just described
dictate that the design needs to be documented
before any change is implemented
and that the change process needs to be reviewed
by a number of named personnel or named roles.
As such, industry has responded by creating
a number of artifacts.
We have problem reports and change requests,
and many of the artifacts that you're familiar with
from the new product development process.
Again, this is a lot of documentation
that is out of alignment with the way
Agile would prescribe change to be handled.
Similarly, the roles of the people involved
are very prescribed.
Again, this is out of alignment with Agile's idea
that teams should ad hoc come together,
work on a particular aspect of the design,
make decisions about the design
at a very granular level, and then move on.