- [Instructor] So given all the guidance
we have from the international standards
and the guidance we have from academic sources
and other thought leaders
why do so many project management professionals
and new product development teams
say that they're biggest problem
is access to data?
Well part of it is because of the way
we've chosen to implement systems
and tools and processes to manage that data.
For example
many new product development organizations
put their product data in a central repository
like a PLM or PDM system.
And that certainly is a good start.
But what they do then
is they link or manage related process data,
for example project plans
or the actual process they will use
to create the engineering designs
in something like Microsoft Project
or another project management tool.
This creates barrier because the two systems
are different and people need to go
to two different repositories
to make knowledgeable design decisions.
Similarly they may also manage bills of materials
or other tabular data in systems like Excel or Access
or other database tools.
And lastly they may route process information
or approvals in a email system like Outlook.
In each case these are standard tools
that can be used
but they are used in a very disconnected manner.
That creates many barriers
for the engineering professionals
that need to make knowledgeable decisions
about the changes that are proposed.
In order to become truly agile
one must have access to all the information
that's needed for a decision
at the time the decision needs to be made.