- [Instructor] Continuing to think
about the disconnected data that we have,
we often lack systems, technology, or process
to take feedback and incorporate it
into the new product development process
or into the actual design,
and continuous feedback is one of the core tenets
of the agile new product development methodology.
So, for example,
we often find things like handwritten redlines on drawings,
even in this day and age where we have very good tools
for reviewing and annotating drawings.
Many professionals, especially those on the shop floor,
prefer to hand-write on printed drawings.
This creates a barrier,
as the handwritten information
needs to somehow be translated
back into the design information.
Similarly, we still very frequently see
handwritten sticky notes used as riders
or other information added on to design documentation.
Again, this is a body of knowledge that's created
that's very difficult to translate back
into the core information.
Plus, it creates decisions that need to be made
by the new product development team
about what to include or how to include it.
Lastly, we must consider the human factor
and acknowledge that many people have very bad handwriting.
A lot of times, illegible or unreadable information
is provided to the new product development team.
This causes them to do either a lot of searching
to find out what the original stakeholder actually meant,
or worse, to make assumptions
and perhaps even make bad decisions
based on the information that they were given.
These are all problems in the agile methods
of new product development
which requires that close, continuous feedback.
Similarly, if we were to look at the feedback
or the connection between pieces of information,
just a bit ago,
we discussed how different systems
are used to manage data.
But if we look at the data itself,
we often know that, at the core,
we have a project plan.
Before, we described that that may be managed
in a project management tool,
but that plan itself drives a lot of activities.
The activities describe
to the new product development professionals
what they need to do,
and often specifically list the deliverables.
The deliverables could be things like CAD models
and specification documents, and so forth.
This intellectual property,
when involved in the change process,
needs to flow back and flow upstream
to the other pieces of information.
They need to be almost intimately connected
so that knowledgeable decisions can be made.
Having different pieces of this disconnected information
makes the agile change process very difficult.
What we need to do is close some of these gaps
both through technology and through process,
as well as acknowledging the human factors,
such as the poor handwriting, that we need to work on.