- [Instructor] Just as we discussed
how accessed information is a challenge
that many organizations struggle to overcome,
we ought to look at the organization itself
and its structure and determine how well it matches up with
the Agile methodology for new product development.
As you should recall from your knowledge
of Agile project management methodologies in general,
there's usually a number of teams that work together
on various components or subsystems of a design.
And the new product development process
is no different from that.
Each of these teams must have very good interfaces
so that information flows quickly and accurately
between the various stakeholders.
This is critical for the Agile process to work.
Similarly, as you should recall from your knowledge
of Agile new product development methodologies,
decisions are made as close
to the design owner's point as possible.
As such, the decisions that are made
must be flowed freely throughout the organization.
This is a very different mindset from a lot of companies
or a lot of organizations that have
a very structured bureaucracy
or a very structured hierarchy.
In such cases, you often need to consciously overlay
the Agile project management teams
on the corporate structure
for the new product development process to work efficiently.
This is something that will take
some organizational change on your part,
as the new product development professional, to fully enact.