- [Instructor] With the organizational
interfaces understood,
and even the best organizational structure in place,
there still may be challenges for you
to completely adopt and realize value
from the agile change management process.
For example,
one of the areas that I see all the time
as a practicing professional
is that the business
is very used to talking about requirements.
They're used to taking a list of requirements,
generating a project plan,
and executing the new product development process.
When you come at them,
or when you start using agile-like terms,
they get very confused.
First, this is an opportunity for you
to educate them again on the agile terminology,
and you certainly may need to do that.
But second,
this is also an organizational change opportunity
where you need to help educate the business
how the agile change management processes work.
Also, overlaid on this could be the organizational change
that needs to happen at the macro level
so that the extended group of stakeholders
can participate in the new product development process
and understand the flow of information that's happening
as driven by the agile methodologies.