- Once you've uploaded content to YouTube,
chances are you want
an audience to engage.
Not just to watch, but to comment
to share with others.
And to do this, you need to work
on building a community.
Now, lets share some practical tips
and some technical advice.
One of the first things
you're going to need to do
in able to have community interaction
is to enable some of
the community settings.
This'll make it easier for people
to engage in your content.
You'll do this from the Community tab
inside of your control panel.
Remember, simply click
and visit Creator Studio.
Then, go to the Community tab
and expand it, and you'll
see a lot of options.
Now, later on we'll talk about seeing
some of the particular things here
for comments and messages.
But, I'll go to Community settings.
This is where you can
control what happens.
So, if you want to have
additional moderators
you can paste their channel URL in here
so more people can be a moderator
without having to necessarily be
added as a manager.
You can also go here and take a look
if there's a need to approve certain
users so that they are going to be
automatically approved
to comment and post.
This way, even if something is being held
these folks can get through without
being hemmed up needing to wait for
their comments to be
approved before posting.
If there's somebody that you decide
that you don't want to see from because
they routinely misbehave, you actually
have the ability here to hide them
so that they're commenting
but folks won't see them.
And, you can also go in and block
particular words or particular links.
Now, down below are a couple
of important settings.
This is where you decide
what happens with comments.
Do you want to Allow all comments?
Well, this is fine and you'll get
a lot more engagement on your posts,
but it means that negative
things might get through.
Do you want to Hold potentially
inappropriate comments?
Well, this is going to scan the content
and try to make sure that if it thinks
there's something offensive in it
it's held for moderation.
Or, turn off comments all together.
Or, make sure that they
have to be reviewed first.
Now, the commenting on
videos is one thing,
but personally I disable comments
on the channel as a whole.
But that's up to you.
You can also decide that you want
to be able to create.
You can also decide to tag people
who have created videos.
So, if people decide to tag you in a post
as being a contributor or
creator you can do that.
And you'll see by default, that messages
in live chat are also going to be held.
And this is currently enabled.
But, you can turn that
off if you don't want
them to be filtered.
And this way, anything
that's said will go through.
Personally, I'm a little more cautious.
So I'm going to leave that checked.
These settings are worth reviewing
and you'll need to customize them
based upon your particular needs.
Now, if you decide to use the newer
version of the YouTube control panel,
there are some of these
settings over there as well.
You'll see that there's a Comments section
where you're able to
actually view comments.
And this is where you can
see what's come through.
If we go down to Settings here.
Now, within this you'll notice that
from the three dot menu, this is where
you can actually decide to take individual
people to come through.
This is where you can say,
always approve a person
or block a person, or mark
something for moderation.
You'll notice though that
some of the global settings
aren't available here.
If you need those, that's
currently a missing feature
and you'll need to jump on over
back to the classic view where you can
see all of those settings and make those
adjustments from the Community tab.
But if you find it easier to actually view
your comments and interact with them,
I do think the new users interface
is a bit more friendly, you can do that.
But for those greater controls
under Community settings, you will
need to return to the
classic user interface.