- From time to time,
YouTube spotlights channels.
Maybe it's a particular campaign
they're looking for or a promotion.
Now, there's no guarantee
that making your channel
ready to promote means
you'll get promoted.
But it's good opportunity to consider.
What you'll do is log in to your settings
and visit the Channel page.
And here, you have the
ability to feature content.
Now, in the past, YouTube has
had other featured content
options, and from time to time,
they bring back new
choices as they experiment.
At this time though, the
option's a little bit limited,
but it's still worth considering.
If you take a look here,
under the Channel settings,
and we go to Featured content,
you'll see that there's an
ability to set a featured ad.
This allows you to select
a particular video,
and it will run it as an ad.
Now, you'll notice here that
there are some restrictions.
It does say that they might use your ads
for promotional purposes.
They do emphasize that
you own your content,
but also that whatever
you put in your channel ad
is something that you have the rights to.
So this is just another
way that they're specifying
some of the same things that
were in the Terms of Service.
Once you agree, you can click
the button here, for Accept.
And then, you'll be presented
with an option to choose your channel ad.
Now, you can search through
any of your recent videos,
but it does need to be a
video below two minutes long.
So what a lot of folks
will do is make something
a little bit shorter and
smaller that they want to share.
Easy enough, you can
find whatever you want
to particularly pull through there,
but pick something that
is representative to you.
In any case, easy enough,
and you can choose
from any of your videos
that are under two minutes.
Or, if you know the URL for
the video you want to use,
just paste it into the
field here at the bottom.
When you're done, clicking
Save will add that
as your channel ad.
Now you will notice that featured videos
and featured playlists
have been recently removed.
This was a great way that YouTube
would occasionally promote these for you,
and you were able to select
content to be amplified.
But, currently, this is not
available on most accounts.
Depending upon where you
are in the Partner Program,
you might find other
featured content options.
But, for most users, the
channel ad is going to be
the only choice you have at
the time of this recording.