- At the end of the day,
you don't want to sit around
and wait for YouTube to
promote your channel.
You need to do some leg work yourself,
and I'd like to share with you
some practical pieces
of advice that I found
have been successful
strategies to raise awareness
for a YouTube channel.
First up, make sure you
publicize across media outlets.
If you have access to
a traditional content,
you can put the link up
for things like radio,
television, websites,
newsletters, or social networks.
In order to make things a bit easier,
make sure your channel
URL is easy to remember,
or you can tell people
to search for a keyword.
If you really want to make it simple,
consider using a shortener, like Bitly,
to make it easier to take a long URL
and make it easy to find.
Also, make sure you link
your YouTube channel
in as many places as you can.
For example, perhaps in
your email signature,
or your blog post signature,
or maybe in a forum signature
if you're participating
in online communities.
Maybe it's connected on your Twitter page,
and over on your Facebook account.
Taking the time to connect it
in as many places as possible
will drive viewership.
Also, make sure that you allow
your videos to be embedded.
If you want to get more views,
letting people put your
videos on their websites
or on their social media pages
will increase the amount of
times that people find it.
Remember, when you start
to look at statistics,
you can actually see what's
driving your traffic,
and I've found that
both searches on YouTube
and third party websites
are frequently responsible
for many of my views.
Taking the time to actually
tag the videos is quite useful,
particularly if there's
products in the videos,
or key things that people search for.
Commenting is one way
to increase engagement,
just keep in mind that
comments can sometimes be rude.
Make sure you take advantage of things,
like those cards, for polls,
or asking open ended questions
and inviting people to comment
on them below the video.
A detailed description
increases the chance
that people will find your videos,
and remember, playlists are
one of the greatest ways
to get people to watch multiple videos.
Many people find video and sit back,
and if you've got a playlist,
instead of them bouncing over
to other people's content,
and you losing them, you
can keep them engaged
with your content, or your
host, or your channel.
Contests are another good way.
Now, you have to be careful here,
and there are several contest
engines that make this easier,
but if you've got a giveaway
or promotion or freebies,
this is a great way to
get people interested,
and Google AdWords do work for video,
so you can drive traffic yourself.
If you have a video that needs to be seen,
or is strategically important,
you can actually pay to boost
the content in Google Search.
YouTube is deeply integrated
across all of Google's platforms,
so make sure where you
can put YouTube videos
about your business, your
cause, or your organization,
embed them into all
places where you're at.
This includes Google properties,
like your Google Plus page,
and your business or brand profile,
as well as the Google My Business page.
Additionally, make sure if you're using
other social media platforms,
you take advantage of
YouTube where you can.
Now, tools like Facebook tend to favor
their own video hosting
over YouTube these days,
making it less likely that YouTube posts
are going to get pushed and shared a lot,
so you might want to use
native Facebook video,
but many other platforms, like Twitter,
still make YouTube a viable option
for sharing video content.