- YouTube does offer
several different ways
to interact with the community.
And one of the challenges I find
is keeping up with the many
different ways that people
can engage with your
content or leave a comment.
Some of the things to pay attention to:
Comments are one of the
key ways that people
can leave a reaction.
Do keep in mind that
just like most websites,
the people who comment tend
to be your biggest fans
and your harshest critics.
If you only judge the
performance of your content
on comments.
You're really missing the opportunity.
Because people generally
need to have a lot of passion
to post a comment on a video.
Messages is another way that
they can reach out to you.
It is possible to send a private message.
Now, a lot of times what will happen here
is people want to point out a mistake,
but they want to do it politely
or they want to reach out to
engage with you for business.
Sometimes this is pure spam,
people offering to promote
your YubeTube channel
or do SEO services.
But, other times it is legitimate.
Subscribers are one of
the things you really want
to work to build.
This is where you can see the
people who have subscribed
to your channel.
Now, Super Chat is a unique
feature that's only available
for people in the YouTube partner program
at a certain level.
What this allows you to do,
is that you can have an
engagement method in chat
for live streams.
Where people pay for increased
presence during the chat.
They can actually boost
their comments so it stays
on screen longer, or is featured.
And Credits are a way that
videos that have involved
other people, such as particular talent
or Behind The Scenes crew can
be credited just like a movie.
You need to have enough subscribers
in order to be credited,
but it allows you another
type of connection
if you're participating
in the YouTube community.
Let's take a look at this
in the Control panel.
Over in the Creator's studio,
you'll see the Community tab.
Comments are going to give
you a list of recent comments.
And you can see any comments
that were flagged for review.
This makes it easy if you
want to approve something,
that you can do that.
With a checkbox, it goes live.
If there's a comment
you don't want to share,
just click the trash
button here to remove it.
If there's something you don't like,
you can also report something for spam
or hide any user's comments.
If we go over to messages,
here you can see messages
that people have sent to you.
Usually here, what happens
is, is they're going to reach
out to you about other content.
So for example, I produced
a few content articles
about HDR software.
Here's someone from an
HDR software company
looking to engage me.
You also may see that some of
these are going to be spam,
which is very common
with YouTube messages.
Subscribers lets you see what's happening,
who's engaged, and if you wanna
go back and cross subscribe
to their channel.
Or if you want to send them a message.
Now, there are no tools to send messages
to all of your subscribers,
but if a subscriber comments
and you want to send them
a private message, you can do so.
And you can also visit or engage,
and see who's interacting
with your content.
Super Chat is the functionality
for increased engagement.
And what happens here is you can enable
this on a particular Live Stream,
or take a look at what
people are engaging.
With Super Chat, it is
actually a way of monetizing
your content, uniquely.
Now, for my world, Super Chat's
not gonna be widely used.
But for people using
YouTube to stream gaming
or people that are true, legitimate,
Hollywood-type celebrities,
well, their fans may pay
to actually be prominently
featured and to be more
involved in the content.
For most of you, this isn't
something you're gonna try,
but it is worth dabbling
in to see if it's actually
something that your audience responds to.
Beyond Super Chat, we have
our simple Community settings,
which we've talked about earlier
and the ability for credits.
This is where you can tag
that people are involved,
but in order for this to work,
you do need to have a
premium account with plenty
of views before you can
actually be available
to be credited in a YouTube production.
Now, if you are using the
newer version of YouTube,
it also offers some of these controls.
You'll see here that
you can view comments.
And this is where you
can see what's happening.
Public, Held For Review.
If we click the Filter Dialog box here,
we can actually search for something.
So if I wanna take a look
for people commenting
on a particular tool,
I can type something in like Photoshop.
And now it's searched
through all my videos
for where the word Photoshop
appeared and I can respond.
This makes it easy to
actually find something.
Or maybe you're looking
for a particular person.
However, this really is
the only option you have.
You don't have the ability to
see your entire community here
from the new view at this time.
So, while this is useful
and a great way to review
and look at comments,
it's still being built out
and a lot of the functionality
you're going to desire
is going to be over in YouTube Classic.
So in this case, you might need to click
Creator Studio Classic and switch on over.
And this will let you see
all of those other views
for Community.