https://git.ir/
- Welcome to this course
where we're going to explore Agile versus Waterfall.
And I'm personally going to be fascinated to record this.
We're going to record it live.
I'm going to interview Doug Rose.
He's an expert on Agile and I'm really pleased I've got him
because not only is he very knowledgeable
he's made a whole load of courses on Agile
but also, he's really intelligent.
And I have found that some people who like Agile
I guess like anything else
are just regurgitating stuff they've learned.
But what's great about Doug is he really understands it.
The other thing I like about him
is he's got a sense of humor.
So I'm going to tease him a bit, he's going to tease me.
And hopefully between us
we're going to really get to the bottom
of the pros and cons of Agile.
I don't even know what answer he's going to give.
He's much more of an expert on Agile than I am.
But I've got a load of questions.
A load of things that worry me about Agile.
So I'm going to ask him about 25 things
and during that time we will get to the bottom of Agile.
So, let's get started.