https://git.ir/
- Okay, so Doug, to start with
for those who don't know, what is Agile?
- All right, thanks Chris.
Agile is typically, talking about the Agile manifesto.
So the Agile manifesto came out in 2001.
It actually Scrum, extreme programming
which are different frameworks that you use
when you're working on an Agile product
actually preceded the Agile manifesto.
- Okay.
- So all these guys got together
and they said, we're doing something very similar,
let's come up with a name for it.
And so they came up with the term Agile.
So Agile is typically anything that's consistent
any way that you're developing a product
that's consistent with the Agile manifesto.
And so the Agile manifesto is a list of core values
and if the work that you're doing
is consistent with the Agile Manifesto,
then you're working sort of as an Agile team.
- Okay, and is the real essence of the Agile Manifesto
that you're not locked into a plan from the start
but you can vary it as you go along.
Or is that just what I've pulled out of it
from looking at it.
- Agile puts less emphasis on planning
and more emphasis on adapting to change.
And so you are not planning out a project
like you would in project management,
not looking at everything that your project will deliver,
instead your planning in much smaller chunks.
And you're sort of building up a product that way
by doing these really short-term plans.
- Okay, great.
So I understand that.
Next I want to explore that in a bit more detail.