https://git.ir/
- So this idea of adapting to change,
this is one of the ideas that really
worries me about Agile.
And I don't know whether you'd use Agile
ever to build a house, I think you probably wouldn't,
but tell me in a minute.
But I've been thinking, if we use house building
as sort of an analogy, if you were going to build
a house using Agile, you'd have a list of everything
that was going to go into the house at the start, I guess.
And clearly you can't put the roof on before the walls,
that's not going to be a problem.
It's not like Agile people are going to do things
in the wrong order, because you physically can't.
So providing you do everything in some order,
you might think that that's going to be fine.
Why do you need a plan?
But I've been thinking about this,
and I think there are two reasons why
you do need a proper plan from the start,
certainly with a house.
And the first one is that there will be a critical path,
there'll be a longest sequence of things
to build your house.
And therefore, you want to start on that straight away
if you're going to get the house built
as quickly as possible.
So if you're Agile and you don't really have a plan,
and you're just doing whatever you feel like each week,
then there is a risk that the first week
you'll think, let's do the fish pond.
And then the week after you'll think,
oh maybe we should start on the walls,
and later on you'll regret that.
You'll think, oh we should've started on the walls
straight away, 'cause they were the slowest thing.
So I'm just thinking, critical paths seem
like a good idea, and I want to find out
if they're in Agile.
But the other thing I was thinking is that,
if you don't have a plan for the whole house
at the beginning, you'll do the foundations,
'cause you have to do them first,
and then later on when you think,
actually let's put a third floor on our house,
you'll be thinking, oh we should've done
the foundations deeper.
And if we'd known at the beginning it was going to
be a three story house, we'd have done deeper foundations.
So it's a bit of a complicated question,
but I just wanted to know about the critical path question,
and also the regretting later problem.
And how does Agile handle all of that when you do projects?
- Now this is going to really freak you out,
'cause you would never use Agile to build a house,
but if you did, because software and a lot of digital
products are much different from building stuff
with concrete, and things like that.
But if you did use Agile to build a house,
or specifically Scrum, then what you would do
is you would get together with your customer,
and you would decide which room in your house
is the most valuable.
Now for a lot of people, it would be a bathroom.
So that's the room that you need the most
in your house.
Other people would be a kitchen.
- I was going to say it's a little bit weird--
- They'd just go outside.
Yeah, so just a kitchen and then just a bucket outside.
But whatever it is, you would work with your customer
to figure out what the highest value part
of your house is, the room, and then you would
build out this bathroom completely.
It would be suspended on the third floor,
completely built out, the faucets would work,
the sink would work, everything,
the toilet would work, the shower would work,
all the finishing would be in there.
- So for house building, this is completely mad,
but for software, I can see how that would work.
'Cause you do the most important feature first, and then?
- And then it's complete.
And so your customer could essentially live
in their house, just in their bathroom.
And so they would have just a one bathroom,
but it would completely work.
And so that's a really tricky thing for a lot of people
when they're coming away from Waterfall
is this idea of what's called incremental
and iterative delivery.
- Yeah, you're messing with my head already.
- I know.
- You've only just started.
- I know, it's crazy.
But if you're coming from a Waterfall background,
or from any kind of deterministic planning background,
then this idea of incremental and iterative
delivery is freaky.
- So you do the one most important thing first,
and then you can build on that from then on.
So you couldn't use it for something like a house,
or anything where you can't do the most
important thing first.
- Well you don't want to use it for anything
that's like manufacturing.
Because classic Waterfall, deterministic planning
comes out of manufacturing.
And so anything that's steel and concrete
that can't easily be built on, reassembled,
that type of thing, is going to be difficult
to have an a team with an Agile mindset work on it.
But once you have your bathroom completely built,
then your team would move onto the kitchen
if that was the second highest value item,
and then make the kitchen complete, everything.
The Viking appliances, the floor, everything
like that's complete.
Now of course you'd never do that with a house
because you would never want to make a wood floor
complete in one room, and then leave the rest
of the house just on stilts.
- 'Cause you might need to put wires through
to get to the sitting room later,
and you'd have to take the floor back up, or whatever.
- And people don't work that way when they're
building a house.
You don't bring in the flooring person in for one week,
and then you send them off.
But for software development, it gives you a lot
of valuable insight into how the rest
of your product will look.
And so when you have a part of your product
that's feature complete, typically only
after a sprint or two, then you get a lot of insights
into what your customer's priorities are.
And so you can build off of that iteratively
and incrementally, until you build out a product that way,
giving your customer a chance to give you feedback,
which is a key part of Scrum and Agile mindset,
and then build off, and not only get feedback,
but learn lessons as you're building.