https://git.ir/
- So I can see that you get the flexibility
and you learn from the customer
and you can have those increments.
Do you pay a price in terms of the time it takes
and it cost it takes,
because sticking with the house analogy,
if the flooring guy comes and does the kitchen floor
and then later on comes back and does the bathroom floor
and then does another floor,
rather than just doing the floor in one lot,
which you would do if you had a project plan,
does it mean that projects take longer to finish
and probably cost more if you do them in an agile way?
- Yeah, well typically agile teams don't deliver projects.
They are building products,
which is distinguishable
because your agile team is not thinking about
all the things that make a project,
it has to be novel but with the iron triangle
and things like that.
So with an agile team that's working on a software product
or some sort of product,
they should expect a lot of rework.
XP teams say that, extreme programming,
this is one of the frameworks used in agile.
They say that you shouldn't be afraid
to throw away software, if it's suboptimal.
- Yeah.
- And they call it software refactoring.
Where you're optimizing it all the time.
But the idea behind it is that it's much easier
to create a product and throw away work that's suboptimal,
than it is to try and plan everything out in the beginning.
So you take that time you would've spent planning
and you get rid of it,
and instead you use it on adapting.
And sometimes when you're adapting
and learning from your mistakes you have to throw out work.
But in the end you still save time
because you don't have that planning, that big chunk.
- Yeah, and I guess that depends how long
it takes to plan things.
Or even whether it's possible to plan.
'Cause I've got of a confession,
as somebody who has got some prejudice
against agile before this conversation.
I had an app made, my Jobs To Do app,
free on the app store folks.
I made a Jobs to Do app
because none of the jobs to do apps did what I wanted.
And when I say I made it,
I paid a guy to make it,
really clever app guy I've got.
And I think it wasn't possible for me to plan it,
to think of everything beforehand.
So we made it agile style.
And we didn't have scrums and sprints
and all that sort of thing,
but basically I explained to him roughly what I wanted
and he more or less understood,
so I knew probably 80% of what I wanted
and by the time I'd explained to him
he understood probably 60% of what was in my head.
I wasn't very good at explaining it.
So he then made that,
and then when I got it I sort of said,
"Well I like it but could it be a different color,
"and could this be over here, and could this be bigger?"
And then we had version two
and then I used it for a bit
and realized I need an extra screen
and I wanted it to go from small to big
rather than big to small.
And we did about probably four iterations,
which took longer and cost more
than if he had just nailed it first time.
But it just wasn't possible for me to even know
what the finished thing was going to be like.
And because it was software,
he could easily just go back in and tweak it
for another hundred pounds, and another hundred.
And so by the end I wasn't bitter
about the fact that it had cost a bit more than we thought,
because it was me that kept messing him around.
So I was fine with that.
And I kind of knew at the beginning of the process
that that was how it was going to have to go.
So I can see with software that
you can change things halfway through
in a way that you can't change with a house.
And I can also see that with software
it's harder to imagine sometimes what it's going to be like,
so you have to be pretty flexible.