https://git.ir/
- So, if you were doing something bigger like, say a website
and something where you could
actually visualize the finished product,
then it seems to me that
it would still be worth having a plan
rather than doing it in some sort of suboptimal order.
So I'm thinking that even with some software
if it's possible to plan it,
maybe it would be a benefit to plan it
rather than do it, doing it agile style.
- Yeah, I mean, I would with your app, it was agile-ish.
I wouldn't say it was full agile.
If you were actually developing an app,
which a lot of people do when they're developing,
you know, these apps in the app store,
I mean, it seems like there's software everywhere,
you would be sitting right next to your developer,
and they would work right next to you all the time.
And so the commitment, when you're the customer
and you're trying to sort of have a product delivered
using the more agile mindset is
you have to have the customer really sit
with the development team and be part of the team.
And so imagine if your developer that you hired to do this
was like sitting in your living room
developing it all day while you were eating cereal,
watching Netflix, whatever,
and they could just turn around and ask you a question
and you could turn back,
and they would just be able to work
sort of at a nice sustainable pace that way.
- That would be great.
- Yeah
That would be a real luxury if you could do it.
- And then they would finish it really quickly
and it would be exactly what you want,
because you're always getting that realtime feedback.
But, if you work an agile team, they don't really see it
as a luxury as much as a necessity,
because even though it would be awkward
to have a software developer sitting in your living room,
that the productivity gains you get from it are enormous.
And so, and I work in a lot of organizations
where they have difficulty with this concept
because they're used to business analysts
and things like that, who just come up with requirements,
kind of throw them over the wall,
and then say, "Okay, that's your responsibility."
- That's what I did with my app.
I just said, "Make me this."
- Exactly.
- And he came back with version 1.
- Right. And if you're working in an agile team
you don't have versions typically,
because you are always, you know,
there's nothing to show you
because you've been there the whole time.
And so the product owner will be,
you know, typically, if you're on a scrum team
this is called the product owner or the customer,
will typically be sort of interacting with the team
in real time at all times.
- So that's really different
to conventional project management
where you almost want to keep the customer at arm's length,
because you don't want the customer to see
some of the problems that you have
and you don't want the customer
to keep messing around and changing the spec.
- Yeah.
And you just want to get a really clear brief
and then be left alone to get on with it.
And also you might be some things that are secret.
You don't want the customer to know how you do them,
so that's really, really different.
- XP teams call it "embracing change."
So instead of saying," Okay, I don't want to
interact with my customer because they might change things
and I've got a lot invested in this the way that it is,"
instead you're like, "Give me changes
because I know that the more I change,
the more likely that I'm going to meet your expectations."