https://git.ir/
- Now, can I ask you about embracing of change?
And before we started filming,
you mentioned that actually you think
that conventional project management
might even be too flexible.
Because one of the things that,
kind of irritates me about Agile people is they say,
"Ah, yes well Waterfall's too inflexible."
And that really annoys me
because I don't think Waterfall is inflexible.
It seems to me that, yes, you start with a plan
but if the customer wants
to change the plan at any time, they are welcome.
It'll probably cost a bit more.
And it'll probably delay the project a bit more,
but it's no problem to change the plan.
It just means that if you change the plan,
you know the effect of the change.
So I can tell you, "If you want to add on
"this extra bit to the project,
"it's going to take another three weeks
"and cost another 5,000 pounds or whatever."
So, and I'm not sort of punishing you
'cause I'm against change,
I'm just saying that's what it would
cost to make that change.
And I kind of feel that with Agile
if the customer changes something
no one really knows the effect of that change
because there wasn't a plan in the first place.
So, yeah, we can easily do the changes
but we don't know how much extra--
and therefore we can't make a sensible decision
about is it worth making the change.
Because if I was the customer and I said,
"Oh, can I change the design of my shower
"in my bathroom?"
And the guy said, "Well yeah,
"you can do that but it's going to cost
"another 20,000 pounds."
I'd say, "Oh, well actually in that case,
"let's not do it."
Where as with Agile they might go,
"Yeah, we can do that."
And you'd never kind of know the effect.
So, tell me a bit about
do you actually, do you,
'cause you know about Waterfall and Agile,
do you believe that Waterfall is inflexible?
And why might you even think it's too flexible?
Which is a very weird thing to have said.
- Yeah, I know.
It's, no I do.
I don't think that it's inflexible,
like I said I think it's too flexible
because when you're working on a Waterfall project
then you can, you know, you receive changes
kind of as you receive them.
You know, there's a lot of times there's a process.
You know, maybe you'll have a changed management team
or something like that.
But it's very difficult to keep track of these changes.
And you know, you have the iron triangle,
where you add a certain amount of changes and then--
- Which is cost, quality, and time.
- Cost, quality, yes, thank you.
And then the time goes up and then
of course the cost goes up once the time goes up.
And so, that to me seems a little too wishy,
you know, a little too flexible.
And also, a lot of times, since you're working,
when you're on a Waterfall project,
a lot of times, it's really difficult
to keep track of time.
You know, people will sit in a meeting
and it will be scheduled for an hour,
it'll turn into two hours and no one really knows
how much extra that's costing the project.
And so, what-- if you're working with a,
on an Agile team, then every metric is locked.
It's called a Timebox in scrum.
In that, you deliver what you promised
every two weeks over time.
And so, you always, your product, your customer
always has this sense of this kind of sustainable pace.
And they always have predictable delivery.
And so, it's not-- you know, if you
are going to add something, it's very easy
to keep track of how much it'll cost.
Because it'll knock some things off of the next sprint
and then you'll have to put new things in.
And so you can keep track of, sort of
what you're adding by saying,
"Okay, well, you added this and so
"it's going to add three more sprints,
"I know that I have five people on the team
"and so it's going to cost me this much amount--
"this amount to sort of add those extra sprints."
And so it's much easier to keep track of that stuff.
And so, I think with a deterministic plan,
you know, Waterfall or something like that,
we are trying to go months or even longer in advance
that teams sort of get-- lose track of time.
- I mean, you can go into more granularity
and you can say, "We'll divide it into small bits
"and we'll measure the small bits."
So there are ways.
- Yeah, it's just, but it's at every two weeks.
- But I can see that you can see the progress.
Well, there has to be the kind of project
where you can progress as you go along.
I mean, some things you might not see
progress for a while, I guess, but
if you've got a project where you can
see it in small bits, then Agile would show that.
- Yeah, and that's, and that's exactly right.
'Cause each, every two weeks, you're showing
your customer exactly what they have.
- So this, this locked-- did you call it
a locked down box?
- Timebox.
- A Timebox.
- Mm-hmm (affirmative)
- (laughs) I had a conversation with a guy
on a course once, and I think that
there are a lot of misconceptions about Agile
and people think they understand it and they don't.
And I was talking to this Agile guy and he was saying,
"When we start the project, we don't have a plan
"for the whole thing, you know, we really don't.
"And every week, we look at the backlog of tasks
"and we choose what to do."
And I said, "So you don't know how long
"it's going to cost-- you don't know how long
"it's going to take in total, do you?
"And also, you don't know how much it's going to cost?"
And he said, "Well, no," he said.
"Chris, that's not really true," he said.
"I can finish the project on any date you want,
"I just can't tell you what I would've done by then."
(laughs) And I'm just thinking, well,
that's just stopping halfway through.
You know, you can stop when you run out of time
or you can stop when you run out of money,
but that's not what project management--
Project management is saying, "I will finish
"on a particular date and I will have finished
"the whole job by that date
"and I will have done it within the budget."
And I'm thinking, is there something in Agile about,
you put the deliverables in priority,
and then when you run out of money,
you've done all the top ones and
you've done most of the others, so that's the result.
Or can you really tell me when you will finish
and what the whole project will cost?
- And that-- excuse me,
that's where things get freaky again.
So this, this idea of incremental
and iterative product delivery.
So, if we went back to our house, which we talked about.
So, if you're building it out a room at a time,
you know, you've got your kitchen, you've got your bathroom.
If that was an Agile product, your customer
might decide that they don't need an extra--
you know they don't need a living room,
or something like that.
I mean, that would be unlikely
but maybe they only need
three bedrooms instead of four.
And so, since you're building it up
a room at a time, feature complete
with a roof and everything, then
your customer could say, "You know what?
I'm running out of money.
I will take this house with two fewer bedrooms,
because I need to live in something
and this is the date, you know, so let's just stop working."
- And that would be the best thing to miss out.
If you, if you run out of money,
and you got to miss something,
you want to miss the least good bit.
- The least valuable.
- So I can see the point of doing that last,
if it's the kind of project where
you can do things in any order.
- Yeah.
- Then I can see why you would do that.
- Yeah, and that's, it's-- so that's
incremental and iterative delivery
and you're just sort of building it up over time
and then whatever's left should be the lowest value.