https://git.ir/
- A friend of mine does refurbishing of buildings
and we were talking the other day
and he was saying that he always has
trouble with the electricians.
So they always say,
"Oh, yeah, we can do that in four weeks."
And then when he comes back after the first week,
they've done nothing 'cause they've got four weeks.
And then after two weeks they've done a little bit
and he goes, "Are you going to finish this?"
And "Yeah, it's going to be fine,"
it's all going to come together at the end they say.
The classic Waterfall, as you can say,
and then when he comes back after four weeks
they go, "Oh sorry, yeah, we had terrible trouble,
"it's going to take six in total."
And he said this happens every time.
And I said to him that's just granularity
because if you don't allow the electricians
to say it's a four week job,
if you say I want to see one week,
if you like sprints, just divide those tasks
down into one week tasks,
then firstly they've got to show you a plan
that adds up to four weeks
and when they're making that plan
they might go, "Actually we can't do it in four weeks,
"I've now realized,"
'cause they've had to really focus on the detail.
And if it is doable, they can't just waste the first week
'cause they got ages,
'cause they've got a deliverable the end of that week,
which is kind of what you were describing.
So I'm thinking you can have tight control with Waterfall
if you granulate it down to whatever size you choose,
I mean you could even have every day,
I'm going to come and see how much you've painted.
You know, you could do that.
And so I think that's not exclusive to Agile.
I think that idea of having tight control,
you could have that just the same in Waterfall
couldn't you?
- Well, it's slightly different,
because you're talking,
project management deals with the,
you know better than I do,
but with milestones and things like that.
But remember when you're delivering your electrician,
they're essentially delivering in phases.
- Yeah.
- They're just like this is the first phase, second phase,
third phase, fourth phase.
And so in Agile, you don't deliver in phases,
it's Scrum typically.
You deliver iteratively and incrementally.
And so if you were going to have your electrician work
in sprints and true sprints,
not just like phases called sprints,
which is a very common thing that people do.
Then the very first sprint,
they would have one room completely wired.
Everything, and it would be the most valuable room,
the kitchen or something like that.
And then they could walk in
and they say, "Okay."
And that way if the electrician gets sick,
goes to Madrid, whatever the last thing.
- [Chris] You've your best room.
- You've got three of your four best rooms.
- Yeah.
So yeah, so that's fascinating and if it was,
but again you'd be mad to actually use Agile
if you are wiring up a building, because I mean,
I know the electrician could get sick or whatever,
but it would be a very inefficient way to do the job.
- And a thing to keep in mind
which is one of the big advantages of Scrum and Agile,
is that if you used a traditional phased approach
then you'd have no rooms with electricity,
or you'd have like, it all comes together at the end.
So you'd have like two weeks
before you're supposed to move into your house,
none of the electricity would work
and then they flip a switch
and all the electricity works.
But with Agile. you can actually move into your house
after the first or second sprint
provided that you're okay living in your kitchen.
- Or you can be making money
if it's something that you're making that you can sell.