https://git.ir/
- And another thing I've got on my list actually
is this idea of the minimal viable product here,
minimum viable product, MVP.
And this idea of, let's just make,
sticking with my app example,
let's just make the basic app that works,
get it out there, 'cause then we can learn
from the customers, and then we can make
version two, and version three, and we'll
gradually improve it.
And that seems to me, related in a way,
to what you're saying about you've at least
got one room wired up, and you could at least
be using that or selling it, renting it out, or whatever.
And I can see that, but it seems to me
that quite a lot of things don't have
a subsection that is viable.
So if you're building a car, you wouldn't say,
"Well the minimum viable car will just
"have the seat and the steering wheel, or whatever."
You have to finish the whole thing
before it's any use.
And so I'm thinking that maybe Agile only works
for things which you can add onto later.
So our house example is kind of so ridiculous,
'cause you've got the suspended kitchen,
but do you think it's true that in the end
Agile only really works on software?
Is there anything other than software
that you could use it for?
- Yeah, it works for, I actually work more now
with it using data products.
If you have five petabyte data set,
you can use Agile to gain insights from that.
But it is much better suited,
there are people who use Agile for HR products
and things like that, but it is much better suited
for digital products, something that can be easily reworked.
- 'Cause there is a trend, I've noticed just looking
on YouTube and the occasional article you read
on LinkedIn and things, that people are trying
to push it out into other areas,
and could we, if we were going to rewire a building,
could it be done as a series of sprints?
I think they are trying to push it out into other areas,
probably because consultants get paid money
for pushing this, but do you think there is any mileage
for pushing it out into other areas?
Or do you think they're just trying to get paid more
for pushing their idea out wider?
- Well, let's think about your car.
So let's say that we just start, if Elon Musk can do it,
let's say you and I do it, Chris and Doug's Automotive.
And so we start building an agile car.
So what would we deliver in the very first sprint
of that car?
What do you think?
- Well before I answer that, I want to tell you
about a poster I saw at one of my customer's offices,
'cause they were Agile.
And they had this poster, and it said,
Agile and Waterfall, and Waterfall was just a wheel,
and then just a steering wheel, and then just the shell,
and then the finished car.
And they were somehow saying that
that was never going to suddenly happen,
it wasn't going to suddenly evolve like that.
And then Agile had a skate board,
and then it had a push bike, and then it had a motorbike,
and then it had a car I think.
And the idea was that you would sort of evolve.
And I was looking at this, and I was thinking, No!
Because if you were going to build a car,
you would build the chassis, and the steering wheel,
and you wouldn't, if you were going to build a car,
your first sprint wouldn't be to make a skate board
and then throw that away and make a bicycle.
So although those things have evolved,
and you could say evolution is kind of Agile,
that's not how you would do it.
'Cause if we were going to make a car,
we wouldn't make a skate board first.
So the answer is, I can't imagine
what the first sprint would be.
I think we probably would have to make a whole car,
and then see what it was like,
and then make the car better.
- Yeah, no you're exactly right.
We wouldn't use, if we were going to deliver a car
as a project, you're absolutely right.
It's chassis, whatever you'd go through,
and then at the very end it would be like
the Detroit Auto Show, we would pull back the sheet,
and there would be the car.
- [Chris] And Waterfall could deliver that.
- Waterfall, yeah, because assuming that you have
all of the planning, and you have the design specs,
Detroit's been doing this for decades.
But if you were going to use an Agile approach,
then you're focused on the value.
So if you're focused on the value,
then you and I would meet with the customer
and we would say, "What's valuable about a car?"
And they would say, "This is transportation,"
that's the valuable thing in a car is transportation.
And so we're here in London, and so it might be very easy,
if you and I were just focused
on the transportation business, not on the car business,
but on the transportation business,
so we're not focused on delivering a car project,
we're focused on delivering valuable items,
valuable products in the transportation business,
then something here in London that might
be really valuable is a motor bike.
Because if you only have to go a half a mile away,
or a kilometers, I'm not great with the metric system yet,
but if you only have to go a few kilometers away,
then I wouldn't want a car if I were living here,
I'd want a motorcycle, or even a bicycle
or something like that.
So if we were doing an Agile product,
we would build it up over time,
and then we'd let the customer test it out
through the streets of London, see what works
best for them in terms of adding value
to their transportation need.
- But I think I would say that with Waterfall,
if a customer said, "I want a car,"
you'd say, "Okay, let's define it,"
and the first stage of Waterfall is to define
what the project is going to be.
What are you going to deliver?
And you would spend quite a lot of time,
perhaps more time than you do with Agile,
thinking about what are you going to have?
And with something like a website,
if you're doing it traditionally,
you really force the customer to think carefully
about what do you want?
Whereas with Agile, don't you just wade in and say,
"Well let's start making it, 'cause you can
"always worry about the detail later."
So I would argue that that defining of what
the product is, is just as strong with Waterfall, isn't it?
- Well in Waterfall what you're doing
is you're trying to have your customer
commit to requirements.
And so, you're saying, "This is what you want,
"and this is what we're going to deliver."
When you're working with Scrum, trying to build
out a product using Scrum or something like that,
then you're not talking about what the product is,
you're talking about what they want.
And then you build it up a little bit at a time.
So let's take a website or something,
but you're right, if you have the requirements,
exactly what that website's going to do,
then that's great.
But if you wanted to try a Scrum using an Agile mindset,
you could build out one page of that website,
let the customer give you feedback about it,
and then work on, build out different pieces
of it over time.