https://git.ir/
- So, I guess it depends on whether you know
much about websites before you start.
'Cause if you've seen lots of websites,
and you kind of know what you want,
then it's fairly easy to define what you want from yours,
whereas if you've never
done anything to do with websites before,
or you want a really radical website,
then you might approach it differently.
But that actually brings me to something else
I've got in my little list of questions.
Somebody said to me, that Agile works
when they've done similar things before,
they've got a bit of a process,
because then they know what,
they pretty much know
what order of sprints they're going to be in,
they know what the sprints are, before they start.
Whereas with Waterfall, often,
you're having to plan something you've never done before,
like space rocket to Mars, or something,
you'd have to do Waterfall,
wouldn't you, you wouldn't do that Agile,
'cause you'd have to really have it carefully planned.
So this guy was saying to me that Agile is great
if you've done similar things before,
and then they can evolve their way through,
and there'll be variations,
but they kind of know roughly what's involved.
Do you think there's a difference there,
that Waterfall is for stuff you've never done,
or is Agile better for when you go totally into the unknown?
- Yeah, I would argue the opposite.
I would say that if you have a ends, you know,
if you can get your customer to give you requirements,
and that customer will look you in the eye
and say, "I'm not going to change this,
"I've done this a million times,
"I understand this process, I know exactly what I want,"
then go Waterfall, 'cause it's,
you can have that kind of planning.
- [Chris] It would be easy, that's a dream project.
- Yeah, I know.
- [Chris] Yeah.
- And so, but if your customer is like most customers
and they, and this is where I find that
actually customers that have done lots of websites
or things like that are actually more likely to like Agile,
because since they've done a lot of them,
they have a lot of ideas that they want to implement,
and they know that space is always changing.
And so if they have an idea of what they want to do
that's valuable to them,
then I think, well it's better to do as Agile.
Because then you can get their feedback
and then you can kind of build it up over time
iteratively and incrementally.
But if you can get your requirements, by all means,
there's no reason to have an Agile team work on a product
if you have solid requirements that aren't going to change.
- So if you're doing something
you're really into the unknown,
the customer's not quite sure what they want,
and the Agile team are not sure how they're going to do it,
how do they know what the sprints are going to be?
Or do you have to know what all the sprints are,
your backlog, before you start,
or do you keep adding new sprints as you go along?
I think I know the answer to this as I'm asking it.
- Yeah, typically if you're working in Scrum,
what they say is that Scrum teams are predictable
but not planned.
Which means that the customer knows
that every two weeks they're going to get something new
and it's going to be valuable to them,
they're going to add value every two weeks.
But they don't know what that's going to be.
It's not planned out.
And so you stop delivering the product,
when you're working in Scrum,
when your customer stops paying you.
When they're just like, "I've had enough,
"This is great, this is perfect."
Like we said with the car,
if we're here in London
and the customer looks at the motorbike
and they say, "You know what?
"That's going to work better than a car for me.
"Let's stop."
Now again, if you ran that as.
- It assumes you've managed to finish the motorbike
before you run out of your money.
- But remember we talk about this in terms of the,
suspended rooms when we're planning out our house.
Is that everything you deliver,
it's called a potentially shippable product increment
in Scrum.
Everything that you deliver in Scrum
is potentially shippable.
And so it's not, if they stop at a motorbike,
their motorbike doesn't need to be painted or anything.
It's done.
- So we're assuming that you've definitely
got enough money to do the essential part,
let's just call it the engine and the wheels
and the seat or whatever.
And then all the rest is kind of extras you might have.
So Agile's going to work if the essential part
of your project is quite small,
and everything else is extras.
Which is often the case,
and I'm not saying that that's not valid.
- I would say it this way,
I would say that software,
is if you're tearing up things and rebuilding them,
then as you move further into your software product,
you're actually building something
that's more feature complete,
and sort of will give your customer
a little bit more of what they need.
So I wouldn't think of it as phases,
like once we get through four or five sprints
we're going to have a pretty good product,
and then every sprint after that's kind of just gravy.
I would think of it as, okay we're delivering our sprints,
and then our customer might pivot
and make something completely different.
And so I mean it's not uncommon
to be three or four sprints into an Agile product
and your customer completely changes their mind.
- [Chris] Right, if that's what the customer wants to do.
- Yeah, I mean you could end up,
and that's good for the customer,
because they don't have to pay for an entire project
of something ultimately that they're going to reject.
- No.
- And then you could sort of
just take what lessons you've learned
from those previous three sprints
and then start developing something completely new.
- So it seems obvious to me
that if the customer is not going to make any changes
then you would go Waterfall.
And if they're going to make massive changes
and pivot suddenly halfway through
then that would be a nightmare for Waterfall.
I mean you could cope, you could re-plan it.
But why have a big plan if it's quite likely
the customer's going to change everything?
And so that's clearly a great case for Agile.
But I'd have thought most projects
are going to be halfway in-between.
They're going to be,
the customer's got a pretty good idea of what they want,
and there are going to be some small variations
as they go along,
they might want to change the color of a room,
or they might want to move the door a bit
when they actually see where it is.
And I'm wondering whether you think Agile
or Waterfall is better for a project
where there's going to be a few changes as you go along.
- Well I don't necessarily think about it
in terms of changes,
I think of it in terms of feedback.
And so if the customer wants to give you lots of feedback,
then I think that that's better to use an Agile approach.
If the customer's very comfortable,
sometimes you see this with developers
who are on a different continent or something like that,
where they'll spend a lot of time
coming up with requirements, use cases and things like that.
System shell, whatever.
And then ship it off somewhere else
and then have it come back as a first version.
Then yeah that's a fine,
if everybody's solid on that,
then I agree that there's no reason
to go through the trouble of having sprints
and having the sprint reviews every two weeks
and things like that.