https://git.ir/
- So I can see it's more flexible if you're doing it
with the agile way, will it cost more though, in the end
if you go agile rather than waterfall?
Because you've got the extra responsiveness,
does that come with a price financially, overall,
if you looked at the same product made by both methods?
- Well, I mean it's kind of,
and this is going to sound unsatisfying,
but it kind of depends, you know?
I mean if you have a customer that knows what they want
and they're not going to make any changes
then you could run that as an agile team.
It should cost roughly the same
because, you know, they'll be delivering in sprints
and they'll just be,
they won't have to deal with a lot of feedback.
- They're doing the same amount of work.
- Exactly, yeah.
And they won't be dealing with a lot of feedback,
they could probably get rid of the sprint reviews
and just sort of focus on the work.
But if you're, so that would be the same
as if you ran a traditional waterfall project.
But clearly the cost element here is the feedback.
- Yeah, but that might be a price worth paying.
to get a really great outcome.
- Yeah, so if you have zero feedback
from both a waterfall project and an agile product delivery
then it should cost roughly the same,
but it shouldn't cost more.
- ALthough it might take longer if you're doing it agile
because you might not do things in the optimum sequence.
So if you knew everything you were going to do,
and you planned it out.
Because one of the things I find weird about agile,
is that it doesn't have any concept
of critical paths, does it?
It doesn't really have a concept of dependencies.
I mean, obviously, we know we can't do the roof
until we have done the walls, so that's the dependency.
But they don't plan out all the dependencies and therefor,
because one of the objectives
of conventional project managing
is to do everything within the critical path time
because you've got all the floating tasks
fitting in around it.
And you can't do it quicker than the critical path.
And agile says, well we're not interested in any of that.
And so, am I right in thinking that if you want to get it,
if you know what you want
and there aren't too many variations,
waterfall will deliver it sooner, is that true?
- Well, I don't know that it would deliver it sooner
because like I said, if you know what you want
and you can give it to either team
and you don't need feedback
and you're not going to make changes
then the team should just be able to deliver the work.
- Yeah, but in the right order is the question.
That's why I was saying sooner rather than quicker.
Because it's the same amount of work
but if you do it in the wrong order,
which you easily could with agile.
I think agile assumes it doesn't really matter,
or at least you do them
in the order of value to the customer.
And I totally get that and I didn't know that
until this conversation, but that could take longer.
- Yeah, and dependencies with agile is tricky
because you are trying to get work
as small as you can possibly be, sort of fit into a sprint.
So typically, teams will use something called user stories
which are supposed to be independent.
And then you kind of manage the independencies
within the team through conversations
and individuals and interactions.
- Maybe with software, there are less dependencies.
Maybe you can do it in any order.
You know, whereas with construction and manufacturing,
you have to do things in a certain order.
But maybe in software there's a lot more flexibility
about the order you do things so it doesn't matter so much.
Although, I don't know that much about software
but I get the feeling some things sort of architecture,
whatever that is, that has to be done first.
But maybe agile people know that
and then on top of that things can be done in any order.
Maybe all the features can be done independently.
- No, dependencies are a huge issue like in agile
because, typically, what you have to do is that
you won't necessarily have to deal with dependencies
such as like create the hull of a ship before the top
but you'll deal with dependencies
in terms of the organizational structure.
So you'll have like a data team
and they'll need to sort of create things
in their data cluster for the software team
to be able to do their work.
And then some organizations are silo
to the point where you have QA teams and things like that.
And sometimes if you're working a traditional project,
you'll have a lot of dependencies in software.
The way that agile, or typically Scrum teams deal with that,
is that they have what's called cross-functional teams
that deliver on each sprint.
So each person will have, they'll be a generalized expert.
So they will know a little bit about everything.
You can do a little bit of database work,
a little but of UX/UI work all within the sprint.
And if you think about it, that's the way
that you have to do it if you want to deliver iteratively.
You know, and incrementally.
If you're going to build out a complete product every two weeks
or potentially shippable product every two weeks,
then you have to have everybody on the team
that knows how to do a bit of everything.
So that you can deliver something.
You don't want to say, okay well we're 90 percent finished
with our increment this week,
but we really need that UX/UI person to come through
and fix things up so it looks nice.
- As far as the waterfall,
you can have specialists, can't you?
'Cause you break it all down to bits
and each person does their bit and it all comes together
at the right time, in theory.
So yeah, that's interesting.
So you have to have people who can do a bit of everything.
Although, they're useful if you can get 'em.
- And they're very, it's difficult.
That's one of the most difficult challenges with agile,
is that because organizations are not set up that way.