https://git.ir/
- And something else I've got on my list to ask is,
when projects get bigger, my gut feeling is
that if you're going to do something really big,
you wouldn't use Agile because you couldn't
keep control of it.
You know, as a Waterfall person,
I'm a control freak, so I want to know
what's the plan? Are we on schedule? Who's doing what?
And Agile just feels horribly out of control to me.
So, do you think that there's a limit to the size
of project you could use Agile on?
- I think that, yes.
I think that it's a big challenge
kind of in the Agile community, and so they came out with
a bunch of frameworks, so scaled edge frameworks
- I've seen, Safe, yeah, the scaled Agile frame.
And I looked at that, in Google Images
and, whoa, it was this horrendous, but I mean, does it work?
Or could it work?
- Well, you know there's Safe, that's Dean Leffingwell
you know, there's Less, there's stuff coming out of
you know, Scott, I forgot his last name
but he comes out of IBM, he's got a scaled edge,
a Discipline Agile, which is another sort of scaling
Agile framework. And, so-
- Clearly, if a management consultant could crack it
they'd make a load of money.
So there is an incentive to scale Agile, but is that
basically trying to make
a pig into an elephant, or something?
I mean, is it impossible?
- It's a challenge, because I think that, you know,
you have your organization set up for silos, and so
scaled Agile, or a lot of the scaling frameworks come in
Less is a little bit different,
but they come in, and you know, they say,
"Well, okay, we can work within this
organizational structure".
And, so what they do, is they create a bunch of sort of
Agile-like processes, which try to push down some innovation
in feedback to the team.
So, essentially, you take away a lot of their flexibility
so you can assign work to teams, sometimes they're
you know, Safe uses something called Agile Release Trains,
or ARTs, which are like product streams,
and then you put, sort of, work into those.
But, of course, the challenge with that is that it
takes away from a lot of the creativity of the teams.
You know, typically, you know scrum teams, they have
the ultimate flexibility to sort of deliver the product
the way that they like.
So, if you're working on a really big product,
you have to take some of that away.
But, the way that a lot of these scaled frameworks do it,
is they take away, but then they kind of break them
into phases.
So it's almost like,
"Okay, you're an Agile team, so you work on"
- Oh, I'm getting a bit of a Waterfall feeling now.
- Yeah, so you're like the wheel team,
or you're the chassie team, and you're the paint team
and you can be as agile as you want, making the wheel.
But, that's-
- [Chris] But it's got to be ready by a certain date.
- Right. And, so, it's kind of a little bit of a mish-mash.