https://git.ir/
- Well, that brings me to something
else I wanted to ask actually.
Which is, what if Agile is part of a bigger project?
So, suppose I'm doing a Waterfall project
and I'm going to build a massive skyscraper or something,
and the software is being done by an Agile team.
So, I need to know when certain bits will be working,
because that's when the rest of the building
has to be plugged in or something.
Is that little bit of flexibility and variableness
that's coming into my project via the Agile component
going to ruin my whole project?
The whole control of my project.
Because I'm thinking of the answer as I ask this.
Because I guess,
if it's the most valuable thing you could guarantee it.
But if I need you to have the whole
motorbike ready by a certain day,
'cause that's the time when The Queen comes from London
and she wants to go riding on a motorbike with you,
- That would be fun. (chuckles)
- Yeah. (chuckles)
How is that going to work?
Or, going back to my house example,
if you're building a house using Agile,
you have to hire a crane,
and you have to book it, you know, six months ahead,
with a Gantt chart you know, hopefully,
where you're going to be by that time.
You have a bit of contingency.
So, you're pretty certain you're going to be ready
for that crane to arrive on that day.
So, if there's any external dates coming in,
either from cranes or from the rest of the project,
how does Agile make sure that it fits
in with the rest of the world?
Or, does it just not do that?
Is it just a self contained world of fun sort of thing?
- In my opinion, it's a little bit of a mess.
It's a little bit of a mess.
The SAFe framework, Dean Leffingwell's framework.
They use that with Lockheed Martin,
which builds, you know, essentially--
- (Chris) Yeah, serious great big aircraft.
- Right, so you're building a fighter jet.
So, there's a component of it, which is hardware.
You know, they're not just floating in the sky in software.
And then there's a component of it that's software.
And so, they use a scaled framework,
The SAFe, or a variation of it.
And so, they have to deal with
delivering software on certain dates,
and they don't have a lot of flexibility.
They're just like, okay, you can't decide,
"Well, I'm going to change where the panel is."
Or something like that.
Or instead of fighting, I'm going to go,
I'll spray candy, or whatever.
And so, the team doesn't have sort of
the flexibility to pivot, really.
But they try to get something that gives you some value
from Agile by allowing the team to innovate
on very small pieces of the product.
And so, I don't know that that's much more valuable
than just running it as sort of a strict waterfall.
They say they have metrics, that it's a lot more valuable,
sort of these scaling frameworks.
- I think SAFe sounds almost like Waterfall.
'Cause it almost sounds like you've got a sequence
and then you're almost into Gantt chart, aren't you?
I would have thought.
- Well, the Agile release trains are based
on value and not necessarily based on time,
like Gantt charts.
But it is, I mean,
Dean Leffingwell, who came up with SAFe,
came up with the rational unified process.
He's the same person who used to work for Rational Software.
And so, it's not coincidence that it's kind of
got that same kind of RUP approach.
- Yeah, that release train,
they're in order of value, but they are in order.
So, you do have, we're going to do this, then this, then this.
And you do have it planned out at the start?
- Well, the way that the release trains work
is that you basically sort of, you know,
they are predictable, like sprint delivery.
But they have more increments in them.
So, instead of,
like typically if you're working a Scrum team,
you'll deliver something each sprint.
And that will be a potential issuable product increment.
With a release train, you have basically a train,
which is a series of iterations or sprints.
They don't call 'em sprints there,
but a series of iterations.
And then you are kind of dumping
a bunch of work into the train.
And the train works kind of like it does here in London,
where they're very predictable
in terms of when they show up.
Well, at least today.
And so, they're very predictable
in terms of when they show up,
and then all of the value pours out of them.
And so, it's kind of trying to use a phased approach.
- It's that just fancy words for a Gantt chart?
Because I know that the Gantt chart
doesn't move along like a train,
but time moves along the Gantt chart.
So, you've got a sequence of things
you're going to do by certain dates.
Is the release train really a
Gantt chart under a different name?
- That would be funny, but no.
Gantt charts are about sort of putting
a bunch of dependencies in and making sure
that you know what goes into the chart.
I mean, you're charting it out,
and everything is-- - Yeah.
- And so, a release train has the flexibility
to put whatever you want in the train.
And so, instead of focusing on what's going to be in the train,
like you would with a Gantt chart,
you're just focusing on the fact that
the train will deliver at a certain time.
- So, the train is what you're going to have when,
and the Gantt chart is more how you do a job?
- Right. - (Chris) Okay.
- The Gantt chart's got everything in it,
the release train just says, you know,
it would be like a Gantt chart
without any deliverables in it.
'Cause you don't know what it's going to be,
you're just kind of throwing this stuff in.
- (Chris) Yeah.