https://git.ir/
I've been so looking forward to asking you all this stuff.
I got this great big old list of questions,
and one of my questions it was,
I bet you have a Gantt chart really, you know.
So when you're doing an Agile project,
and you say, well, we're just going to do this,
build this room and then this room
and then we see how it goes and maybe,
or secretly on a piece of paper, have a rough plan of
what's going to happen or do you really, every two weeks go,
"Okay guys where are we at?
"What should we do for the next two weeks?"
I mean do you, is that really what you do?
- I secretly Gantt at night and so,
but it's, the Gantt chart is different, you know,
Gantt charts are great and
Henry Gantt, whatever, he created them
to do really big projects,
you know, like the Hoover Dam
and I think he was a shipbuilder or worked in shipbuilding.
And so it's designed for manufacturing,
really big manufacturing project.
- Although I would have a Gantt chart
even for something quite small,
just saying, because they're so quick to draw,
so people say to me, at what time,
sorry I'm interrupting but people say,
"At what point does something become a project?
"What time is it worth planning?"
And I would say if you've got more than about 10 tasks
or if you've got two or three people involved,
it's worth having a bit of a plan of who's doing what
and everybody can then see what their part is.
And so I think even for something really small it's well.
And that's why I just find it so weird
that even for quite, you know, just a smallish Agile project
there isn't secretly some kind of Gantt,
(crosstalk)
kind of telling me how
you really don't have, - I haven't seen it
but maybe there's a secret Gantter out there
on one of the teams, but
what a Gantt chart records
isn't information that's available
for an Agile or Scrum team.
And so, because, remember, you know the Gantt chart,
the whole reason that they do the Gantt chart is so that
you can build the hull of the ship
before you build the top of the ship.
You can build the house, you know,
start with the slats, and then move away into cement,
and whatsit, showing dependencies.
- But you do have an order you're going to do it in.
I know you're doing the most valuable thing first,
but I mean, there is, you know you're going to do the kitchen
before the bathroom, and you know when you do the kitchen
you're going to have to do, you know, the cooker,
and the floor, and, so you kind of know the order.
- The only way that you could ever use a Gantt chart,
I think, successfully in an Agile/Scrum project or product,
is that if you have the team create a two-week Gantt,
each sprint.
- [Chris] Okay.
- And so, but, again, you know, it's,
- Well, you don't need that, because it's only two weeks.
- Right, and the way that a Gantt chart extends
off into time,
kind of like, you know, you can just go horizontally
forever until the product, the project is finished,
is something that would be very disorienting for,
I think, a good Scrum team, because,
that's why typically Scrum teams use a burndown chart,
is because you're burning down the work, yeah,
you're burning down the work, until you have nothing left.
And so it's not a continuum of work that you're managing,
and then you're delivering at a certain time.
You're burning down your work based on the highest value,
until there's nothing.
And so, but you wouldn't, remember, like, in Gantt,
you're trying to plan out an entire project.
I mean, that's the real value in it,
is that, you know, you're doing the dependencies
and things like that, but,
with a Scrum team, Agile team, you're not running a project.
You're building up a product, and so you're doing this
iterative and incremental delivery.
- But to build that product,
I'm just sticking to my house analogy,
even though I know you wouldn't use Agile for a house, but,
to do that product, you know it's got certain rooms,
and you know there's work within those rooms,
and you've decided on the order of the rooms,
because you're going to do them starting with
And so, Scrum was based on sort of this empirical process
they met with, actually,
a chemist in University of Wisconsin,
where they focused on using an empirical approach
to deliver software.
You're doing an experiment, like,
- Sort of like research and development,
where we're just gradually trying things,
developing, you know, a new drug or whatever it might be,
a medical drug. - Pharmaceuticals,
or things like that. - Yeah.
- Or is it like manufacturing,
where you're, like, delivering, you know, shoes,
or delivering, you know, a car, or something like that.
So is it, now a lot of people who work on software products
think it's more like science.
More like, you know, pharmaceutical research,
because when they can pivot, they'll learn something new,
they can create something new,
and they don't know that much when they start.
And some people think it's more like manufacturing.
- I really, I am really glad you said that,
'cause that's something that I've been thinking for a while,
because I, when teaching people product management,
I say to them that everything you do is either a project
or a process.
So you've got projects which have a start and a finish,
and you're going to build something and there it is,
and then you've got processes that go on forever.
And so, you know, I've come from running factories,
and you can probably tell by my whole mindset,
so in a factory, it's mostly processes that just roll along,
but you have the occasional project where you
improve a process, or you install a new production line,
a new product line or whatever,
and then that's a project, and I always loved the projects
because that feels like progress in the end,
where you do something new.
So in my sort of mindset, you've got processes that go on
forever, and then you've got projects.
But of course, you've got things that are in between.
So quality improvement is sort of a process
that consists of lots of little projects,
and coming up with new products over the years.
You know, your product evolves,
and is that a project or a process?
And I wonder whether Agile sort of sits in that area
in between.
It's not really pure project management, in a way,
it's more to do with processes and having, you know,
great communication,
and good communication with the customer.
So it's more like a process, although it does have a finish.
And there is a burndown chart,
and there's money running out.
But it's more like, for me, it's more like a process
than a project.
- Yeah, I mean, I would think of it more like, just like,
product delivery,
instead of just like an ongoing forever process.
You know, in project management,
you'll have your scope tied down,
some sense of sort of like, the, you know, the time,
then of course because you have time, you have the cost,
and with using a Scrum/Agile approach,
then you don't really have the, you know, you don't,
you have a little bit of the scope,
but not in the same way that you have
with project management, because with project management
you have the scope, which is both what it will do,
and how you will deliver it, somewhat.
But you don't have, you have the time, and you have the cost
but those are not tied down, like an iron triangle.
They kind of, and a lot of times what you'll hear about Agile
is it sort of flips it on its head.
The way that I like to think of it is that
instead of having a triangle,
where you have sort of scope, cost, you know, and time,
you flip it over, and then you fill up an Agile product
with as much scope as your customer wants.
- Until you run out of money.
- Yep, until your time and your money run out.
- Yeah, and with my app, I actually didn't have
a fixed amount of money, we didn't go 'til my money ran out,
I just spent more.
And I was fine with that, 'cause I thought,
you know, it's not costing me that much,
and if I have to pay a bit more to have the app I want,
I will.
And if I have to wait a bit longer, I will.
And I think Agile's really great
when you're not quite sure what you want,
you don't really care what it costs,
and you don't really care how long it takes.
And actually, I think quite a lot of projects are like that.
My app was like that.
But I think if I was, you know, doing something bigger,
then there might be a date when it must be done by,
and there might be a budget that I really can't go beyond,
and then it would be less good.
- Almost all Agile products, almost all Scrum projects
I work on with a team and Agile mindset
has a very set cost,
and so, - okay, so, it's how many
features can you get for that cost?
- Exactly.