https://git.ir/
- Yeah, well that actually- that reminds you of something
that occurred to me earlier in this conversation.
There's so many things that I want to ask you.
Um, which is suppose there are ten things
I'm probably going to have in my finished product,
and there are three I've got to have,
and the other seven would be nice,
and they're in sort of descending order of niceness,
the last one I hardly care about at all,
I'll get it if I can.
- So you're building a product backload.
- Yeah, then um,
I'd be happy with agile,
because I know I'm going to get my three.
I'm probably going to get five or six,
I might even get nine or ten, and that would be fine, but--
and you know thinking about our motorbike example,
if I'm bound to get the wheels and the engine,
and the rest is luxury, then that's okay,
but I think quite often,
and I think in the case of the motorbike
I must have eight out of the ten.
And there's only a couple that are a bit optional.
You know, so I've got to have everything on a motorbike
except for maybe paint is optional.
And I think I would worry then with agile
because there's so much variability
I might not get all eight.
And do you think it's fair to say that if there are a few
things we've got to have, the rest is all optional,
and agile is fine but it would be-
you'd want to go for a bit more of a controlling process,
a real proper tight gant-shot,
if you've got to have eight out of ten.
- Well, it depends what the eight is.
And so if the eight are requirements,
and you know exactly what you want,
then yes, I would use a deterministic approach.
But if the eight are something that you value,
but you don't really know how you're going to do it,
then I think an agile approach would be better.
Because it's-- and that's how a lot of software ends up,
is that you sort of-- because I mean if you think about it,
when you start delivering a software product,
there's a lot of chaos, you know, some of the database
servers, you know some of the database servers
you might use might get upgraded, so they might roll in
a feature that you were developing,
and there's a lot of open source projects out there
so those might get better or worse change.
So you're dealing with a lot of chaos,
and so it's really difficult I think,
to come up with that list of seven or eight,
which is, we're able to say these are my requirements
I need them done this way. - Yes.
- If you can, if you go through that effort,
if you're lucky enough to get that in a software project,
then I would absolutely use
the deterministic waterfall approach.
- Because, with the motorbike example,
there definitely are a whole load of things
you've got to have, but that's an unfair example
to be using on agile, because it's a manufacturing
example and so by using those examples I'm aware its unfair
and I could see that for software, there might be
only a small number of things that you've got to have.
Although you do get agile in manufacturing I think,
as I remember years ago there were--
I think it was Toyota were talking about
parallel development and they were--
I've always been fascinated, because they were saying that
we develop-- they used to either have the shape of the car
first and then they would say to the engine people
"you've got to make an engine that fits in this shape",
and they'd go "ugh we'll have to make a flat one".
Or, they would start with the engine and then they'd
say to the car design body shape people,
"you've got to make a car that fits this",
and they'd go "ugh, we're going to have to make it really
thick there, because of the shape of the engine".
And that makes sense to me, you start with one or the other,
and there's a debate about which one you start with.
But Toyota I think it was were doing both at once,
so for the new car, they got people designing the shape,
and people designing the new engine,
and they just talked to each other a lot,
and they go, "we're thinking of going quite flat"
and they'd go "yeah well we're thinking we want
to be quite wide, well okay we could--"
and they sort of both somehow iterate together,
and by doing that, they can do it in half the time.
Because you haven't got to do one and then the other,
and I remember thinking "whoa that's amazing,
how can they do that?"
And that was perhaps the start to agile.
- It was one of the starts of agile,
but yes, the Toyota production system started lean
software development, properdin started that,
and a lot of the ideas about lean get rolled into agile.
You know, the idea of cross functional team.
- Kanban. - Kanban, yeah.
- I need to ask you about kanban.
- Kanban came a little later, but it was, yeah,
but you know, got rolled into you know, cross functional
teams and everybody, and actually it was an article
about the Toyota production system and other things
that started out scrum when they--
in this article Who Knew Product Development Came,
when they talked about how in these production systems,
they had teams working together like a scrum team
pushing the ball forward, like uh,
you know, and that's where you get the framework scrum,
is because you have these, these,
this whole team, cross functional team focus
completely on the ball together, and then pushing it forward
and so a lot of that stuff came right out of Toyota
production systems, that leading step.