https://git.ir/
- I want to ask you about Kanban,
or Kanban as some people would call it.
I think I probably used the proper pronunciation.
Because I've come from manufacturing
and we used Kanban there as a way
to keep work in progress down.
Because just for the viewers, 'cause you already know this,
the idea is that if I'm doing a job
and I'm passing it to you, if you're slower than me,
or you're ill or something like that,
I can just make a great big pile in between the two of us.
And then, that means that the whole lead time's much longer,
'cause everything that comes through the process has
to wait for ages while it gets
through the queue before it gets to you.
So the idea is to limit the work in progress
to only a certain number, so you might have room for only,
like, say nine, little three by three box between us.
And when that box is full, I have to stop,
and I've got to come and help you.
I've got to say, "Doug, clearly there's a problem,
"because you haven't taken anything out
"of my little box where I put stuff."
And sometimes, if we're geographically spread,
you might be coming and taking them from my box.
But if you don't come and take them,
I know there's a problem at your end
'cause they're still in the, this is right, isn't it?
- Yeah. - So that's all great,
and I love that, and then, I suddenly discovered
that the Agile people are using Kanban.
And when I had a look at their Kanban system,
I was bitterly disappointed, 'cause I just thought,
that is so ridic-- - It's abomination.
- Yes, sort of facile, 'cause all they've got,
their boxes are jobs to do,
jobs we're doing, and jobs we've done.
And sometimes you might have design and test,
or there might be a couple of stages that they go through.
But mostly it's just jobs to do, jobs we're doing,
jobs we've done, and the only reason you could possibly call
that Kanban, I guess, is because there's a limited number,
amount of space on the board for Post-its.
So it does limit to, say, to nine Post-its,
so you can't have more than nine things in the queue.
So it's sort of, but it's not really Kanban, is it?
Or have I missed the point, is there something
really clever about Agile Kanban?
- Well, I mean, Kanban is, it came a little bit
after the Agile Manifesto, but it was about, basically,
managing queue size, you know, it's from queue theory.
Actually, I ran into queue theory on the way over.
I mean, I took the tube over, which is nice.
But they could clearly put more than a few stills,
these little things that you go through to get into the--
- Oh yeah, the ticket reader.
- Yeah, the ticket reader things,
you know, and they've got three or four.
And so, that's a Kanban system.
And so, if they put six or seven, when it's rush hour,
everybody would come through, and they would cram onto--
- I know. - Yeah, and they would cram
onto the escalator, and the system would shut down
because it would be crammed.
There wouldn't be sort of a smooth flow
of work through the system.
And so, in software, Kanban is a way
to maintain a sustainable pace
when you have work going through a system.
So typically, it's kind of an Agile way of working
if you have a team that has operational, repeatable work.
Something like a help desk ticket system,
where you have all these people who are working
on help desk tickets, doing operational stuff,
helping people check their email,
helping people fix their computers.
So you have a huge amount of work that comes
into the system, but you always have to have a steady flow
of work to come out, otherwise the team will get overloaded.
And so, some teams use Kanban boards for the Scrum board,
the task board is basically a Kanban board.
- [Chris] Is it really just the chops
to do this, then, really?
- It's not, it's a way to show whether
or not the team is going to deliver at the end of the sprint.
That's kind of what the purpose of the task board is in Scrum,
is that if you see everything stuck in doing and not done,
and you're a day or two away from the sprint review,
then you know you're going to be in trouble.
And so, it's a way to look at the board and say, okay.
And in Scrum, you have to work on the highest priority work
on the task board, so that's the stuff on the top.
- So those are the tasks within one sprint.
- Right. - And all those tasks have got
to be done by the end of the two weeks.
- Right, and so they have to go from top to bottom.
And so, the highest priority moves across the board.
And so, you can see, as a product owner,
usually, typically a product owner than a scrum master,
will look at the board and they'll be like,
"Oh my gosh, all of these tasks aren't going to be done
"in the next two days, I'm going to be standing up
"in front of the customer talking about
"how it's a funny story, we didn't finish."
And so, that's the purpose, really,
of the task board in Scrum is to help the team
regulate the work to make sure they're working
on the highest priority stuff from top to bottom.
But you can also use a Kanban team, a Kanban board,
for operational teams to work on help desk tickets
or things that are predictable work, but could come in,
you know, you have to have a predictable output,
but you could have a variable input.
So you could get like, the email server could go down
and you'll get 50 tickets in one day.
But you can't just stand there and be like,
"I'm overloaded," you have to start somewhere.
And so, you just prioritize the work
and pull it across the board.
- And is that the same as your backlog of tasks,
or is that a, there's a backlog of sprints as well,
so could you have a Kanban board
for all of that as well, for the higher level?
- I don't typically use a Kanban board,
or the product backlog,
because you don't get that much value from it,
because you're not really managing the work coming out
of the system like you are on the task board.
But what the product backlog will do,
it will show you the product owner's highest priorities.
And so, the product owner should
constantly be shifting the product backlog to make sure
that the stuff at the top is the most valuable to them.
And that's slightly different from the Kanban board,
which is more about just making sure
that the work the team produces is being done
at a sustainable pace.
And you'll see that in Scrum,
where they say they divide the work up based
on the how and the what, is the product owner will decide
what gets delivered in a two-week sprint.
But the development team will come up with the how.
They'll say, "Okay, here's how we're going to deliver it."
And so, they'll typically work off
of the Kanban board, or the task board.
So, does that make sense?
- Yeah, it does, actually, yeah, yeah, yep.
I can see the Kanban board isn't quite as bad as I thought,
although still not proper Kanban.
- Yeah, I mean, it's 'cause it comes out
of manufacturing, so-- - Yeah, yeah absolutely.