https://git.ir/
- You mentioned burn down charts earlier on.
That's another of the buzz words that,
Agile is so full of buzz words.
- Yeah.
- But, you know, that makes it exciting for people,
and harder to assess.
(laughs)
But burn down charts, are they really just a budget?
I suppose it's got a timeline,
so you can look at the angle of it,
but is it really just looking at your expenditure rate
and saying, if we carry on at the current rate,
this is when we're going to run out of money?
Is that all it is, or is there more to it than that?
- It doesn't directly have to do with money,
because you have two typical, two burn down charts
in a Scrum team.
You'll have the Sprint burn down,
which will be the number of user stories.
Which is basically sort of doing the same thing
as the task board, it's just showing how much of the tasks
are being burned down to meet the bottom,
which will be the Sprint review.
Because, again, in Scrum it's inflexible,
you have to deliver something in two weeks.
You can't just stand up there and be like,
well, you know, sorry.
It's December and so we.
So you have to deliver what you commit to delivering
at the end of the Sprint.
But then you have a release burn down,
which is a little bit more sophisticated.
Where you and I would sit together and we were doing
an Agile product, and I would say to you,
how many Sprints worth of work can you afford?
I have five developers that cost me $250,000 a Sprint,
you have a budget of whatever.
So we'll go through and we'll figure out
when we're going to be done delivering something.
So we'll have like 20 Sprints or whatever,
and we'll burn down the work that the product owner
identifies until we release at the end of that,
you know, whatever.
- But it's not a Gantt chart because we don't know
what we're going to be doing at each time.
Because a Gantt chart will tell you
what you're going to spend when, and what you'll get for it.
But with this we just know that's the rate
that the monies going to be going at.
- That's how many Sprints you can afford.
- Yeah.
- And Gantt charts also manage dependencies.