https://git.ir/
- Okay, so that makes sense.
Now, it's divided into these,
you were saying inflexible two week sprints.
Wouldn't life be great if you could divide
everything up into exact, two week chunks?
But I'm thinking, what if it's a four week job,
or a one week?
I suppose if it's one week, do you just deliver
two one weeks within your sprint?
I mean, how does everything get wedged into
a two week chunk?
- Yeah, that's the inflexible part of Scrum,
is that you have to deliver what your product
owner requests at the top of the product backlog
every two weeks.
And sometimes if the product owner,
you'll have to work with them to break something down.
So like, if the product owner, let's say that
they want, like, a webpage at the end of the sprint.
So you might say to them, "Okay, what's the most
"valuable part of the webpage?"
And they might say, "Well this is, you know,
"I want a form where people can submit their information."
And then I would say, "Okay, well we can't create
"the whole form in two weeks,
"so what's the most valuable part of the form?"
And they'd say, "What I really need is their
"email address and their first name."
And so, at the end of two weeks, our team would deliver
a webpage that just comes up with two boxes
that just say first name, email address.
But the key thing to keep in mind is that
that webpage will be the same webpage
that's in the final product.
It will completely work.
It will be going to a database, it will be backed up.
It will be optimized.
- So you can't be halfway through something
at the end of your sprint.
That's got to be something that works
at the end of every sprint.
- And that's one of the biggest challenges
for new Scrum teams, is they'll just say,
they'll put up something like a UX UI drawing.
And they'll be like, "And next week, this will work."
You know?
"In our next sprint, this will work."
And you can't do that in Scrum.
It's cheating.
So.
- But I guess with enough thinking it might
be possible to divide everything down
into working pieces of two week size.
I don't know, it seems like, in a way,
an unnecessary constraint to put on yourself.
Because it, on a Gantt chart,
something might be a week, it might be three weeks.
Whatever it is, we put it on there.
And then at the end of the three weeks,
or the one week, we say, "Have you done it?"
But it's kind of odd that they've just chosen this,
I mean, two weeks is a good amount of time.
I get that.
But that is quite a constraint to have put on yourself.
- That's what I meant when I said I think
that style is much more, sort of,
chaotic and flexible to me.
Because I think to myself, well, you know,
it could take two weeks or three weeks.
So what happens to the person downstream,
because then they have to take into
account your variability?
And so then you just put in a bunch of little buffers
and things like that to try to make it all work,
which completely makes sense.
But for software, it can get into a lot of trouble that way
because you can end up with, you don't want to have,
you know, obviously you wouldn't want that
with a ship, as well.
You wouldn't want to have like 3/4 of a hull done.
But with software, there's an old joke in software
that software developers are like 90% finished
90% of the time.
(chuckling) - Yeah.
- And so, and that's true, and so you force them
to sort of deliver a sprint,
deliver a working product increment
at the end of every sprint.
- Well I must say, my experience with software guys
is it would have been great to have nailed them down
to at least finishing something by a certain date,
so I totally get that.
- That's why managers like Scrum, typically.