https://git.ir/
- I'm sort of thinking, if I was a customer,
would I like Scrum?
And I'd like the flexibility to change my mind all the time,
that would be great, but I wouldn't like
this thing about not having the iron triangle.
Because if I'm a customer, I want to to say to you,
build me this job and guarantee I will get this
on this date, back to the iron triangle you know.
I will get this on this date for this money.
And if you said to me, "Well you know,
"we'll just go 'til we run out and you know,
"we'll do quite a lot, you might get seven things,
"you might get nine things,
"we don't really know, and it kind of depends on you Chris,
"how much you change your mind."
I'd be thinking, well all the risk is with me.
Now, I've got customers who agonize
between do we quote fixed price for consultancy jobs,
or do we just charge by the day?
Because clearly, if you charge by fixed price
then it's much more scary because you might not deliver.
And you sort of think, well surely a customer
would always want a fixed price,
but actually they don't always want a fixed price.
Because if you force me to quote you a fixed price
I'm going to put in a margin on top,
because the risk is with me.
So, I guess if got an agile team who I can really trust,
and who I'm sitting with, working with all the time,
you know, maybe the risk isn't completely with me.
But I still feel as a customer
it's a little bit out of control, for me.
- And you don't have to really trust them either.
Because remember, they're delivering every two weeks,
so you can see if they suck much more quickly.
- That's true.
Yeah, you would know, I mean you would know
with a gunshot straight away,
because you know that they're keeping up
with the coloring in.
Are we keeping up with the line?
So the first task of the gunshot,
you'd be able to see have they done it.
So I think you do have just as much visibility
but I do take the point
that it has to be a working item, doesn't it?
After two weeks, so you can really, really check it
with Scrum.
- Like your friend with the electrician.
I mean, they may have been a great electrician
but they won't know until the fifth week.
- Nope, nope.
And the whole gunshot plan could be a big con.
And you wouldn't know until the end
unless you knew a bit about it, which you might not.
Yeah, so you would say then that the customer
isn't taking more risk upon themselves
by going agile then they are with a gunshot.
- No I would say they're taking less
because instead of getting commitments,
they're getting software.
And so, you know, that's what agile,
one of the agile principles in the agile manifesto
is that you know, working software.
And so it's, and that's how teams communicate.
They communicate from working software.
So you got...
- But you don't know when the whole things
going to be ready.
Or if you do set a date, you don't know
what you're going to get by that date.
- Right, it's up to the customer.
- Whereas, in theory, with waterfall
and a gunshot, you do.
Although in practice you may not, of course,
because things might go wrong.
- Well it depends on the customer,
I mean if you work on an agile team
and a customer doesn't have a lot of changes
and don't care about the feedback
then they'll get exactly what you decided in the beginning.
But if the customer does then, you know,
then you still deliver what they wanted
it's just much different from that first discussion.