https://git.ir/
- [Doug] Sure!
which is, I was talking to someone else about Agile
the other day, it's all I talk about nowadays, and
he was saying that
there's a thing called the Cone of Uncertainty
or whatever and as time goes on,
you home in more and more on what you're making
and what you like and what you want,
but he said that's not true, because actually,
every time you make a decision,
you close off other options.
So the example he gave me was,
Suppose you're driving in an Agile way,
towards a destination.
And you don't have a map, because the Gantt chart
is like an overall map of how we're going to get there,
but the problem is, sometimes roads are closed and things
so the argument is,
because the map may not be 100% accurate,
we won't have a map at all.
This is kind of, this is what I think Agile people are doing
in a way, they're saying, well,
because something might change, let's just not,
let's make it up as we go along, almost.
- We'll get somewhere.
- And as long as we got a compass
and we're going roughly the right direction,
- Yeah.
- and actually, I have noticed with my SatNav,
that if a road is closed, it just says,
well, okay, take this one instead,
and it adds almost no time, it says,
because this road is closed,
your journey is going to be one minute longer.
And you think well, that's interesting,
because I had my optimized route,
but actually all the other routes,
they're not much different, really.
So I do take that point.
So, anyway, he said that if you're applying this to sort of
just head west,
and kind of make it up as you go along,
and every junction just decide,
which is more the Agile approach,
he said there's a flaw in that.
Because what if you're going along next to a river?
And it's only a small river, so it's not a problem,
and you go, and there's the river,
and then there's a bridge across the river, and you think
because you don't have a map, you're doing Agile,
you think, Shall I go across the bridge or not?
The bridge has a little, a small cost,
and you think I won't, I'll, you know,
I don't need to cross the river yet.
And you carry along, and later on you discover that
that was the last bridge.
And you're now on the wrong side of this,
of the Mississippi,
and you're thinking Oh, no!
New Orleans is the other side of the Mississippi,
I'm screwed!
And so is there not a risk, when you do Agile,
that later you're going to regret decisions you made earlier?
And then have to chuck it out.
Maybe that's just the risk you run for being more flexible.
But, you know, wouldn't a map have been better?
A map/Gantt chart have been better?
(laughing)
- I almost want to make a Gantt chart together now.
The issue is that, if you were going to,
if you were going to use a map,
like you said with your Google maps,
then you run into the challenge of, like you said,
a closed road.
So, but a lot of times you don't figure out that
that road is closed, until very late into the project.
And that's what the Cone of Uncertainty is,
is that if you, like,
I spend a lot of time in Florida, the States,
which is very nice.
And so they have, you know, hurricanes that come up,
every so often.
And so when you're sitting in Florida, and they say
Oh, there's a hurricane.
There's always beautiful weather before a hurricane.
And then always like, you know,
the hurricane's going to hit anywhere
from Fort Lauderdale to Miami.
Which if you know Florida, is like 100 miles, you know,
I mean.
- But it gets more precise as the whole thing gets closer.
- Exactly.
And so if you can't, if I decided that, you know,
I was going to run and start, dig a hole and, you know,
store up a bunch of Pop-Tarts and beer,
which is what Floridians buy when there's a hurricane,
then, you know, I may have wasted a lot of effort
is that, as you go further along,
the cost of change becomes much greater.
And so, it's depending on where your road is closed.
If your road is closed at the very end,
really close to where you were supposed to,
where you wanted to go,
then you could kind of end up screwed.
Because you just invested a lot of money
to get 90% of the way there.
But with an Agile approach,
what you're doing is that you're breaking things up,
work up, into little sprint, and so you are
reevaluating every stop or,
- But you don't look very far ahead, do you?
You're only looking,
There's the road closures, and then there's the river
that's there originally,
and I'm just thinking, with Agile,
you never look further ahead than that two weeks,
you aren't, you just constantly just,
you know, like, looking at a tiny bit of your map each time
and thinking oh, I didn't see that over there!
I mean, that's what worries me about it.
Or is there somehow a bigger visibility, as well?
- No, I think that whether or not you're working with
the deterministic approach, or Agile,
you're always going to be working with imperfect information.
- [Chris] Yeah.
So, if you use a deterministic approach,
you can have a lot of projects that are failed projects
when you've already invested 80% of the resources
that you need to get there,
which is like the road being closed near the end.
But, and I don't know that the information that you'd get
from a deterministic approach would let you know about
the bridge going across the river before,
you know, if you're not sort of getting that information.
- And my map could be wrong, it might say there's a bridge
and when you get there, there isn't.
But I still think a map, you know, a rough,
- You'll at least be able to drive down the countryside now.
- Yeah, but I sort of think a rough map
is always better than no map.
But I think maybe what it boils down to is
how much work is involved in the planning,
like if the map is really expensive, you know,
like takes ages to plan your Gantt chart,
then you might think I should just not bother with a map,
and let's just go Agile. - [Doug] Yeah.
Or, you know, if it's going to cost a lot of time and money
to bury your Pop-Tarts and, what was the other thing?
- Beer. - Beer, oh yeah,
forgot the beer.
So, if it's going to cost a lot of money to do that,
you might think, well, let's wait until the hurricane
gets really near, and then do it.
And I think there is an assumption amongst Agile people
that the Waterfall is a lot of work,
to do the planning up front, and therefore
not worth it, since things will change anyway.
And, actually, I think often people do spend
far too much time,
and they've got really laborious processes,
and lots of horrible Microsoft project Gantt chart,
which I hate, and all that, and I think
you know, personally, maybe the answer is,
is a really quick, easy Gantt chart.
Just a rough Gantt chart, I mean, why would you not have
just an approximate plan of what you think's going to happen,
and then at least you can see whether you're kind of
on schedule or not, and, you know, maybe that's the answer.
- If it feels right, but the problem is that it's,
with a Gantt chart, you're just,
there's nothing for you to record an Agile project.
So it'd be empty. - You literally couldn't
mix the two.
- Right, well, it's not that you couldn't mix it,
it's just like, it, you know, it's like,
having a map when you're trying to cook muffins.
And so, it's just a different, you know,
it's like a different sort of,
you're using kind of a different sort of report
for something that you need.
And, you know, with Agile, there's just,
you wouldn't be able to put anything into a Gantt chart.
Because, again, you could pivot and change,
so there's no way to measure out all the dependencies,
and there's no way to figure out when you're going to deliver
what you're going to deliver,
because you can't manage the dependencies,
because you don't know what it's going to be at the end.
And so, - Oh, I'm feeling anxious
again. - I know.
So you really couldn't, there's nothing,
so it'd just be an empty Gantt chart.
What I would do is just create a burndown chart
and just call it a Gantt chart.
And so, it's, there's just no, there's no,
wouldn't be any information to sort of,
to put into it, and so it would just be kind of
a bunch of boxes and at the end you would say,
Something will get delivered here.