https://git.ir/
which one to use then, I think there's no doubt
that manufacturing and that sort of stuff
has to be traditional project management,
which you call deterministic, which I always
feel is you're somehow insulting it subtly.
(both laugh)
I don't know if it's judgment, or whatever
you want to call it, yeah.
Sort of like control freak method,
which I'm happy with.
- I mean in terms of you're trying to determine
what you're going to deliver at the end.
- Yeah.
And then there's no doubt that for stuff
where there's going to be big pivoting,
and it's software, and you can do things
in order of importance and value,
that Agile's got it's place, no doubt about that.
Do you think there are some things
where you could use both, and where
it's difficult to choose?
How would you advise a person to choose,
'cause you understand both, you're not a dyed in the wool
Agile all the time guy, are you?
- No, if you have your requirements,
there's no reason to do it.
And the requirements are going to stay the same.
- So that for you, that's the big factor
is how well nailed down are the requirements?
- Or if the customer's just like,
"Here's what I want."
If a customer hands me a design spec
for a shoe, and says, "Here's what I want in six months,"
I'm not going to be like, well let me give you
a flip flop in two months, and then I'll give you--
- But what about a website, for example?
'Cause one of my customers recently said
that they were going to build about 30,000 pounds,
I could translate that into dollars, but--
- Well I have an idea.
- It's one-to-one at the moment, isn't it?
(both laugh)
It's $30,000 as well, oh the pound,
but anyway, so it was a reasonable sized website,
I didn't spend that on mine, and she was saying
that she had three people quoting,
and two of them were Agile, and they said,
"We'll work closely with you,
"we know certain things you definitely want,
"there might be some other things.
"We don't know how long it'll take really,
"we don't know what it'll cost,
"but we'll do something really good, and trust us."
And the third person was a Waterfall person
who turned up and said, "Here's my Gantt chart
"of what I will do for you, and you'll get
"all the things you told me about by this date,
"for this money.
"And you can change it if you want,
"but if you change it, it's going to cost you more
"and take longer."
And she went for the Waterfall supplier
because she felt safer, and because she didn't
know the Agile, I think if she'd known the Agile people
and trusted them.
So I think you could say, for a website,
where you more-or-less know what you want,
that Waterfall is probably a better way,
but I guess there comes a point where
if you want something really exciting
and different, then you'd want to go Agile
because the team are probably going to have ideas
as they're going along.
So do you think that's what the essence is,
to try to work out how much change there might be,
and that's how you would choose your method?
- Maybe, with her I would've steered her
towards Agile just because if she's a novice at it,
then you're putting a great deal of trust
into people that you don't know.
- I think she wanted a website that was kind of a bit
like the last one, only nicer looking,
'cause she's pretty boring.
- Which is fine, as long as she knows the developers.
But you have to remember that in a Waterfall,
deterministic approach, I mean that in the nicest
possible way, the deterministic approach is that--
- I don't even like the word Waterfall.
(both laugh)
I just think it's a Gantt chart,
it's not a waterfall.
I know it looks a bit like a waterfall,
it's a Gantt chart.
I wish they'd call Waterfall Gantt.
- It would be nice.
- But anyway, we'll go with Waterfall,
'cause that's what people call it.
- It's so pretty.
But I would advise her to work with an Agile team
on the product because--
- I knew you'd say that.
- Yeah, I know.
Although there are times, but she's putting a lot
of trust in these teams, and so because remember
they're going to be working, she's going to be paying them,
they're going to be working presumably for weeks
or months, and then at the very end,
she's going to get her project.
She's going to get what she paid for.
But if you're working with an Agile team,
then every two weeks, she'll see it,
and she'll see where things are going.
And so if I were going to work on something
and I was a novice, I hadn't worked
with a team before, then I would use an Agile approach
just because I wouldn't want to necessarily
want to give someone a bunch of money,
and then hope for the best.
- And you don't trust the colored-in Gantt chart
to give you that same thing?
Because the stages in the Gantt chart
don't show a fully working room,
they just show let's say, foundations,
which you can't prove.
Is that?
- Yeah, Gantt charts are great,
but for me, I would prefer working software.
It might be different if I were building
a house, I wouldn't use an Agile approach.
- Because you can physically see what they've done,
whereas software, who knows if somebody's tapping
away at the computer going, "I'm halfway through,"
and you just don't know.
- Yeah, but if you've ever seen a house being built,
that's also very nerve-wracking.
And so I worked with a school, they were building
a new school in Detroit, and I went out
a week before school was going to start
to do some IT stuff for them,
and I looked and I said, "There's no way
"that there's going to be kids in this school
"in a week."
It was like no walls up, or anything like that,
and then like 100 people came in,
and they finished it within a week.
So that for me would be anxiety provoking.
So I wouldn't want to do that in software.
- But your Gantt chart would tell you
it was okay in the school example.
So is there anything other than software
that Agile can work for?
You mentioned big data sets.
To me that's software.
Do you think you'd use Agile for anything
other than IT really?
- I think you could use it for anything
that's more scientific than manufacturing.
- Okay, yeah, so research and development
type stuff then?
- Yeah, and so anything where you're going to get
a lot of value from a more empirical approach.
You know, turning the knobs and seeing what happens.
But there's a lot of things that I wouldn't
use an Agile approach with, like I said,
houses, cars, boats.
- So my map analogy, exploring Africa,
when those guys were doing it in the 1800s
or whenever it was, that's Agile
because there is no map, and you don't know.
Whereas driving to London, there is a map
and it wouldn't be so appropriate.
So anything where you really are in the unknown.
- Well, not necessarily in the unknown.
There's always a little bit you won't know
with either approach, but I would say
anything where you get a lot of value
from running experiments, from getting feedback.
If that's valuable to you, then I would go
with an Agile approach.
If you want to see a product at the end of every
two weeks, like your friend, I would go with
an Agile approach.
If you want to just get a Gantt chart,
which I completely understand,
look at it, and say, "Okay, I'll see you in six months,
"I've worked with you before, I trust you.
"Here's the big cheque, I'll see ya in six months,"
then that makes perfect sense.
- And you can have meetings with a Gantt chart,
we've done the first stage and here it is,
you can see it.
The foundations are in, you can see them.
- Yeah, absolutely, but ideally you'd
want to just hand it off to them and go to Miami.
- [Chris] Yeah, if you trust them,
you don't need to do it, Miami.
- Yeah, exactly.
- I've never been.
(laughs) I need to go.