https://git.ir/
- I think we know the answer to this one now
but could you ever use a mixture
or are the two things so different
that there'd be no benefit to doing a bit of each?
- That actually, sadly that's the most common
way to do it, because most teams will say
we'd love to run as an Agile team, but man,
we've got a plan that we received from whatever,
and we need to follow it, so we'll
just use a little bit of both.
And Agile--
- And they do that, they use both?
- It's bad.
- Yeah, from this conversation, I can't imagine
how you could use both.
- It's bad.
And then they call it, you know,
it's a ScrumBut.
We to everything Scrum, but this.
AgileFall, you know, there's a bunch
of different terms for it.
But it's, to me when you mix these two approaches
you get kind of the worst of both worlds.
Because you spend a lot of time planning
at the beginning, but then your team is free
to throw away that plan.
- So this is where,
So the next year you'd have a Gantt Chart,
and each stage of the Gantt Chart
you'd do in an Agile way, sort of thing.
But I can see that would be awful.
- It would be, but it's the most popular, unfortunately.
That's what most teams do, some variation of that.
- So it's true Agile, or nothing.
- I wouldn't say true Agile or nothing,
but I would say it--
- Well, true Agile or not Agile at all.
By nothing, I mean Waterfall.
You caught me there.
- Everybody does something.
I would say that if you understand the benefits
of each approach, make a decision,
and then move with it.
You're much better off doing a Waterfall,
or a deterministic approach, and then doing it well,
than you are doing a mixed approach poorly.
And you're much better off, obviously,
I think, doing an Agile approach well
than either for software,
but I've been to many organizations
where they say, well we want to become Agile
but we still want our plans,
our manager still wants milestones,
and I say well, you could do something Agile-ish.
Maybe put up a kanban board, or something like that
but you're not going to really get
that much benefit from it.
So you really have to embrace the idea
of doing iterative and incremental delivery,
and getting feedback from your customer
and delivering something every two weeks.
That's another huge challenge.
- So if you were a big senior manager,
and you had a whole load of projects going on,
in, say, your IT department or whatever
of this big company.
On the plus side, you'd see things
delivered every two weeks,
but on the minus side, you wouldn't
really have a big overall plan of what was going on.
You wouldn't have what I dream of,
which is a Gantt of Gantts.
I like to see all the projects.
We're going to do this project, then this one,
then this one, and I can see that's
half-finished, as indeed it should be,
and you wouldn't have any of that,
so it's really down to trust and enpowerment,
and that sort of stuff.
But you can at least see a little bit's been delivered.
- Yeah, I would say you can trust them less,
because you're looking at it in real time.
I would say that you have to trust people
more when you do a Gantt Chart.
Because the Gantt Chart's beautiful.
I mean I used to be a project manager, too.
It's beautiful, you look at it,
but the thing that hurts your heart
when you make a beautiful Gantt Chart
is it always, someone always screws it up.
I know, it's, it's--
- But I don't mind if my Gantt Chart,
well, I do mind, but it gets adjusted slightly
and this has run late, so we have to
squeeze this down just to finish on time,
or whatever.
But I still feel I'm always in control
as I keep re-jigging my Gantt Chart.
You know, I can see as I run my marathon
that I was a bit slow on the first half,
I'm going to have to speed up on the second half,
but I still know where I am,
and even if I'm heading to finish
five minutes late,
I'm not going to ever run a marathon (laughs)
but, you know, in theory I can see, I can tell you
half-way round that I'm going to finish
five minutes late.
So I still feel in control, even if
I'm overspending or running late.
- Yeah, and I would totally get that,
but I would argue that you are
in better control of your schedule,
but I would argue that Agile teams are
in better control of the product.
Because you're delivering at every two weeks.
- But they don't know whether they're going to
deliver seven out of ten of the options, or nine.
- It's up to the customer.
- But then those last few are things
you're not too bothered about, anyway.
- If you're delivering the highest value first,
they should be lowest value stuff.
So you always, you're going to do a house
you always end with the dog house.
Not that I'm not a dog lover.