https://git.ir/
- One of the criticisms that Agile people use of Waterfall
that I feel is deeply unfair and hurtful is
that Waterfall has loads of documentation
and Agile, you don't have to bother with documentation.
I would say that I think Waterfall doesn't have
to have much documentation at all.
You probably do need to use post-it notes
to work out the running order of your tasks
and you do need to have a Gantt chart of course,
but that can just be on Excel, quite simple, you know?
You might have a high level Gantt chart
and perhaps some sub-Gantts for some of the bigger tasks
a bit more detailed but it's not a lot
and I think you can plan a project in an hour.
It obviously depends on the size of the project,
but I think you can plan something pretty decently large
in maybe two or three hours maximum
and that's time well spent.
So, I don't think that Waterfall has excessive amounts
of documentation it it's done properly.
I have seen horrendous ones, but if it's done properly,
and I suspect that Agile must have some documentation.
I know you've got your Kanban board and you've got
a backlog which you groom, but so tell, just briefly,
because I'm not excited about documentation
I've got to admit, but does Agile have significantly
less documentation do you think?
- Well, I think that Agile and the Scrum calls it artefacts.
So, that's the--
(laughs) - I know!
- I love the names!
- You have to come up with a new pretty odd name.
The thing that Agile does, most Agile teams,
Scrum teams in particular, is that they split
that documentation up into high-value documentation
and low-value documentation and so no product owner
is going to want to have documentation delivered at the end
of a two-week sprint.
Just like, oh we didn't really develop any software,
but man here's a great report about what your software
will do eventually-- - [Chris] Yeah, yeah!
when we make it. - [Chris] Absolutely!
- Exactly, so that's kind of of a bad sprint review,
but there's a high-value documentation
where the documentation can actually be the product,
where if you're developing software and you have like
a manual or something like that,
then that can be delivered.
If you're talking about the documentation that you create
for each other to work, then Scrum tries to keep the
low-value documentation, the e-mail back and forth,
the meeting minutes, all that stuff, the memos,
it tries to keep that to the bare minimum
because you've got to deliver something in two weeks.
- [Chris] Yeah!
- So, you can't really sit around and write long memos
about work you're going to do in the future and so
there's not really, since you're working with these
small little innovative, you know, incremental chunks,
there's not really a need to create the documentation.
- And there's nothing bigger written down
because you really don't have that longer-term--
Right! - plan.
- And the documentation in a deterministic Waterfall
style plan is designed to limit communication.
You know, if you create the perfect requirements document,
then no-one will come back to you and be like,
"Chris, what do you need?".
- [Chris] You never have to have talk.
Exactly! - [Chris] That's the drain!
- It's in the document, but it's--
[Chris] Yeah! - and an Agile team,
it's in the Agile manifesto,
focuses on communicating, getting people that you
and I sitting in a room talking about the product,
will always be more efficient than you creating
a document on your own and then giving it to me.
That's true! - [Doug] I think so.
- So, when you're building your imaginary house,
not that it would be a house if you're using Agile,
you don't have even a list of all the rooms
you're going to do at some point.
You just think,
"Right, dear Mr. Customer or Mrs. Customer,
"what's the most important room for us to do next?",
and you just have that conversation.
You don't even have a list of all the rooms
you're going to build.
You know, you don't even that documented.
- Well, you might do something that sometimes
Scrum teams will work with, epics or something like that,
which will be large groups of user stories,
which you'll try to sort of figure out at the beginning
and then you break down as you get closer to the sprint.
So, I might have a conversation with you that's, say,
"Okay, how many rooms do you want in your whole house?",
but we wouldn't get into conversations like, you know,
"Well, what kind of flooring do you want
"in the entire first floor?".
- [Chris] Yeah.
- "Or what kind of, you know, how do you want
"your walls painted?",
because you're going to have a fully functional room.
So, you can look at the floor,
you can look at the walls,
you can say,
"I like this!
"Do more of this!".
- But the epic is a description of the whole house
and the user stories are each room, kind of,
are they written down?
Would an epic be written down or, just very briefly,
would it just be bullet points?
- I think you'd be very unsatisfied with an epic.
An epic is just a sort of a big kind of statement
about something that will be broken down
into stories later on.
So, it's not like documentation the way you might think
of it in project management.
- It's going to be, you're going to drive through London easily
on a great vehicle?
- [Doug] Exactly!
- That's sort of, it's almost like the objective,--
Yeah! [Chris] the mission?
- Yeah, and you might break it down further into,
you know, it should not take very much gas.
Yeah! - It should be able
to weave through traffic--
it's quite good! - I quite like that actually!
I've got to admit, I quite like that.
- Yeah, it's not bad.
- I'm just still worried about you starting work
on it when that's all you've got but, yeah!
I can get it.
If it's software I can see!
- [Doug] Yeah!
- If it's software only, the fact that you can change,
you know, as you did with my app,
you changed all sorts of things around significantly
as you went along and that worked well.
- Yeah, and you could even do it more efficiently.
[Chris] Yeah! - Like I said,
if you was living in your living-room!
It might be tough to explain to your wife,
but they'll be there!
- (laughs) Yes, exactly!