https://git.ir/
- Okay, so, Agile is working fine
on small software projects.
There's, we talked about SAFe, Scaled Agile Framework
where they're trying to make it into big things
and release trains and all of those things.
But, what do you the future--
do you think it will die off again?
It will just become one of many tools?
Is it going to get bigger?
Is it going in the wrong direction?
Tell me about the future of Agile, (mumbles).
- Well, I think that one of the challenges around Agile
is that it's generally not done very well yet.
There's a lot of Agile coaches out there
and I worry that there's a lot of bad Agile out there.
People who do the mixed approach that we talked about.
And so managers and executives think to themselves, okay.
This is kind of a West Coast weird thing.
There's a lot of stuff in Agile that is questionable.
Like shared spaces and things like that.
There was a big move toward shared workspace,
everybody sitting at the same table together and working.
Turns out there started and a lot of people hate it.
Which I understand, I would hate it.
- Is that mob programming?
Mobbing, of is that something different?
(laughter)
- Well, it's--
- Going one step even further, everybody works
on the same thing as a group.
I can't imagine how that would work, but still.
- Sounds horrible to me
but I've seen shared workspace and so there's a lot
of practices that get thrown into Agile.
I'm worried that executives and managers
are going to be like, well, this Agile was interesting
for a couple of years but is not quite ready for primetime.
I think some of the scaling frameworks
will only exacerbate that problem.
Instead, they'll just say,
why am I adding all these processes
when it's not really adding that much value?
I don't think they have great metrics
about whether or not it's that much better
than just doing a traditional deterministic
waterfall style approach.
But I'm much more optimistic about using Agile
for more scientific products.
I think that Agile in data discovery,
Agile creating A.I. products,
where you're really figuring things out as you're--
- A.I. is Agile almost by definition, isn't it?
The machine is doing some sort of Agile process,
you don't even know what it's doing.
- Well, no one knows what it's,
but if you're doing machine learning, it's a black box.
But Agile's a very good approach, this kind
of empirical approach because some of this stuff
is getting so complicated.
You could never say what I want to do,
'cause if you knew what you want to get from your data,
then you wouldn't be exploring.
And so these exploratory products are, I think,
very well suited to Agile.
- Brilliant.
Well, thanks very much for your time.
Thanks for coming all the way from America
to be interviewed (mumbles). - I know, terrific!
- It's been fascinating and I think I'm a lot clearer now
on where the edges are, what's good and what isn't
about Agile, so thanks very much.
Doug Rose.
- Chris.