- I'd like to thank you for
joining me on this journey.
There's a lot to putting
together a good YouTube channel.
And as such, we've had to go
through many different topics.
I fully expect that you
have even more questions.
I would suggest a few things
to help you complete your education
and succeed at building your channel.
First up, don't be
afraid of the Help menu.
Visiting YouTube's Support
page is a good idea.
YouTube frequently changes things,
adding features, subtracting
features, moving features.
I find myself opening up the Support page
just about every time
I want to do something
in-depth on my channel
beyond just uploading a video
or moving something around.
YouTube has a lot of great features
and a lot of new things
that keep popping up.
So if you don't read the Support articles
or the blog on YouTube's site,
you might miss out on those.
So make sure you pay attention
because there are lots of
developments that pop up
that might be beta or might
be implemented for real.
Additionally, we covered a lot
of related skills during this class,
topics like video compression
and graphics and branding.
Well as such, you might want to explore
some of the other courses
available in the online library.
I also have a course all about producing
webinars and events,
and there are some live streaming courses
that are quite useful as well.
Check these out if you'd like
to learn more on these topics
and go a lot deeper.
But all in all, YouTube is a platform.
It's a platform for your content,
and you have to remember that good content
is what's going to work on YouTube.
So just knowing how to make a channel
with pretty thumbnails
and great descriptions
and good tags is one thing.
But if you don't have
content that's engaging,
well, it's not going to work.
So make sure you balance
out your creativity
and storytelling
abilities with the ability
to use a great database, tag structure,
and search engine optimization.
And if that seems a little bit difficult,
don't be afraid to partner with people
and get some help.
Fortunately, YouTube has
become a very viable platform,
and there are a lot of resources
to continue to learn it and master it.
My name's Rich Harrington.
Thanks for watching.