- One of the most exciting
additions to YouTube
is the ability to live stream.
This opens up all sorts of great options
for engagement with an audience
whether you're covering a
corporate event, a concert,
or just on-the-go with a mobile device.
Live streaming used to
be tremendously expensive
and it still is with many providers,
but YouTube has democratized this process
making it easy to stream 720p video
or even higher quality video
if you take advantage of
some dedicated hardware.
Now when you go to live stream,
YouTube gives you a few useful options.
You can choose stream now
which just means start sending
out a stream immediately
and this allows you to
send content automatically
and they'll start and stop your stream
as soon as you make the signal available.
Some folks will do this
with screen sharing
or other software tools
or streaming out gaming
or using their web camera
to talk to the world.
You can also schedule events.
This gives you greater control
because you can set a start time
for when you want an
event to start and end
and this could be great
for meetings or webinars.
Additionally, you can do mobile streaming
from the YouTube app.
Once the mobile stream is over,
you simply end it and then
it's archived to your channel.
You also have the ability
after the archive is done
to make this something
that is a private video.
Or you can use a web cam to go live
without even needing an encoder.
Now let's show you these
things really quick.
I'm logged in to the mobile app here
and if I tap the camera icon,
you see I get an ability
here to do one of two things.
I can record the video
and then post it later
or I can tap and go live.
With a simple click here,
I just need to allow access
to some of the controls
on my mobile device
such as giving it access
to the location services.
And you can decide to allow for live chat.
Now it's going to prompt me
to put in some information.
I can also switch from the
forward to the backwards camera.
In this case, I'll just show
you forward for a moment
and I could put in some information.
I'm going to set this to not
be public as an unlisted video
and I can choose a location here.
If I tap more options, you'll
see some other choices here
including the ability to
schedule this for later
where I can type in a specific start time.
Or under advanced settings here,
I've got the ability to decide
if I want to allow people to chat,
if this video should be age restricted,
whether or not it's promotion,
and if we want monetization on the video.
I'll go back from the advanced
settings here and tap next.
It counts me down,
takes the thumbnail for the video.
I know the shot of the desk
is not very interesting,
but you get the idea
and we tap go live.
Now I'm sending out a live stream.
We did not make this public
so I don't expect anybody to join,
but you'll notice here
that I can flip around to the front camera
and we're sending out a live stream.
We can start to enhance the video.
Or if I tap the more icon here,
you see that we can actually
share this out socially
so I can tell people,
"Hey, join me on Twitter,"
or maybe I copy the link
and put it out there.
So even though it's an unlisted video,
you can actually take advantage
of different sharing services
to put this in more places.
I'll go ahead and share
this to Twitter for a moment
and you see inside of our studio
as we're making the video.
Now we have two viewers.
So you see this does actually work.
Three viewers, hello three viewers.
We're doing a test stream here,
walking people through how
YouTube live streaming works
so we're able to actually send this out
and you should be hearing me.
Now viewers have the ability
to click a thumbs up if they want
to indicate that they agree
or that they're hearing the video.
They can like the video.
And we actually have the
ability here if we want
to see other options so I
can turn on chat right now.
If people were to send any
messages, they would appear.
So there's a hi, thank you.
So we've got an overlay.
So I can actually see
things from the audience.
They can ask questions and
engage in the middle here.
Now the live streaming is just one option.
Thank you guys for tuning into that.
I'm going to go ahead and close that
and I'll click end.
Now the video is uploaded
and you can see a little bit of statistics
about what happened.
When I click done, it's all there
and you'll see that it
becomes a draft post loaded
waiting to be used.
So the stream is there
and it proceeds to upload
and becomes available.
This is an easy way to live
stream from your mobile device.
Additionally, besides
using the live stream,
you have the ability to use a webcam.
Many laptops have it built in
or something as simple as a webcam
plugged in to your USB
port is going to work.
This is a great way to webcast
from just about any computer.
Now this is going to give you
the ability to send out signals
and if you need higher quality cameras,
one of the devices that I use
is this device from Blackmagic
called the Blackmagic
Design Web Presenter.
This lets you plug in two sources,
one via HDMI,
one via HD STI, a
professional video connection.
This will make it quite easy
for you to send out a signal
and it turns any professional
camera and microphone
into a web camera that works with YouTube.