- Now, just because you have
access to live streaming
doesn't mean you can live
stream every piece of content.
This is a relatively expensive service
for Google to offer for free,
so they do place some limitations.
If you want to live stream,
you have to make sure that your account
is in good standing,
and it will be disabled
if you do any of the following things.
If you get a Community Guideline strike
for offensive content,
you're going to lose
the ability to stream,
at least for a while.
If your live stream is blocked globally
because of offensive
content after the fact,
and they discover a video
that you live streamed
that they feel violates
the Community Guidelines,
well, then you're going to be blocked.
And if your live stream
or an archive live stream
receives a copyright takedown
notice for a violation,
well, you're going to be blocked.
And if your live stream matches
a copyrighted live broadcast,
like you point your live camera
at the big Pay-Per-View fight
and start live streaming it,
you're going to be blocked.
What this comes down to
is YouTube doesn't want
to give live streaming ability to people
that are going to use
it for hateful things
or to steal other people's work.
Now, if you are violating
copyright accidentally,
they pick up something that's
registered with content ID
like background music that's copyrighted,
YouTube will pop up a warning
during your live stream
to let you know that
you're violating copyright.
But if you keep doing this,
particularly for things
like live sporting events
or rebroadcasting television,
you're going to have problems
with your live stream.
Now, the restrictions are
going to last for 90 days
or until you fix the issues
that were in violation.
You can check your status by
going under the Channel menu
and look at Status, and
you'll be able to see
if a feature is enabled or disabled.
If you are deemed to be broadcasting live
something that is copyrighted,
that cannot be appealed.
They will just simply
block you automatically
as a copyright violator.
Remember, it is against
the Terms of Service
to use third-party ads in a live stream,
including burned-in commercials.
So if you're doing an event
and you've got your own
commercials you want to play back,
maybe it's a local sporting
event for a high school
and you've sold commercials
to the local businesses,
well, you can't play those back.
This means that YouTube wants control
over the advertisements.
They don't want you selling your own ads
and putting 'em on YouTube.
Rather, you have to use their ad engine
and play by their rules.