- One of the easiest ways
to go live is with an event.
And the easiest way to
do this completely is
with the Hangouts On Air engine
that used to be part of Google Plus.
Now Hangouts On Air,
also known as YouTube
Live are pretty simple.
You go to the Live Streaming
section in your Creator Studio
and you click on New live event.
Then, choose Quick using
Google Hangouts On Air.
Give your live stream a
title and click Go live now
if you want to immediately
start broadcasting.
Or you can enter in
details to schedule it.
Then you use the Google
Hangouts engine to do
a live broadcast which can
include multiple panelists
and guests as well as screen sharing.
Now, I use this sometimes
to do live events
on photofocus where we
teach people software
with guest experts.
As you can see here, it's
easy to schedule it in advance
and then during the webinar,
multiple people can join us
for the conversation as
we take a look at tools.
It even has great tools for
putting things like lower thirds
or graphics over the top,
so as you're teaching,
people can see who's talking
and what's happening.
To schedule a live broadcast,
it's pretty straight forward
Make sure you take advantage
of the built in scheduler.
And this can also control
who can see a broadcast.
Is it public, unlisted, et cetera.
When you create the event,
you have a few options.
Public means anyone can
find it and watch it.
Unlisted means it's not shown publicly,
but if you put the link out
there via social media, a blog,
or email, people can find it.
I'll sometimes use unlisted
for smaller meeting or events
that I want people to be at
but I don't want to
publicize quite largely.
This way I can email the link around
and people can watch and view.
If I'm really concerned
about who's attending,
well then I can set that event to private.
A private event means
that only people you've
specifically invited
by an email address or a web
domain or a particular group
that you've set up, can
see the live broadcast.
To access a live broadcast is easy.
Just log into your channel
and go to Creator Studio.
Then, click on Live Streaming.
If you want to go live
now, click on Stream Now
and you'll see here that you
have the ability to go live.
You simply put in some general information
and from Stream Options here,
you can decide what to do.
This means for example,
that we can stream this
and then make an archive.
We can stream it and allow
people to have rewind, et cetera.
We'll talk more about these
options in just a moment.
Now, what I want to suggest is
that you use the Events section.
This is going to give you more control.
Click to make a new live event.
Then, enter a title.
You can choose to go live now
or set this for a specific time.
You can also add an end time.
Feel free to put in a description.
And tags.
You can decide the publicity
status, and decide on a method.
The easiest one is the Quick method
with the Google's Hangout On Air.
Once I create the event,
a new video is made
that's designed to be a
container for the live stream.
If we scroll down here to the bottom,
you see that it's got the
date and the information.
If people were to go to that
page or I was to embed this
into a webpage, it would look
just like a YouTube video.
But in the mean time,
it's got a countdown timer
until the event starts or
they can click set a reminder
and get notified when the event begins.
Now there's more to running
a Google Hangout On Air
and I invite you to check
out some of the courses
in our library about webinars and events
or some of the documentation
on Google's website.
But the Hangout On Air
engine is the easiest way
to do a live video stream.
But there are other methods
and we'll talk about that next.