- If you've moved beyond streaming
with a simple mobile device
or the Google Hangouts On Air engine,
you can actually use YouTube
as a pretty viable platform for streaming.
You will need some software or hardware
in order to pull this off,
and I'm just going to
give you a small taste
of what's involved.
I invite you check out some
of the full-length courses
on webinars and streaming in the library.
Now, in order to stream on
demand, it's pretty simple.
When YouTube detects that you
have put out a live signal
to the channel, it will
go live, and it will
actually send this out and
automatically adjust the quality
of the stream based upon
people's internet connection,
so if they have a slower connection
like a mobile device, it will adjust.
When the stream is live,
people can actually interact
using live chat or Super Chat.
They can also share the
link like any other video
across social media platforms,
and you can monitor the stream,
looking at the status bar,
to see how it's doing.
Are there any bandwidth problems?
Now, in order to pull this off,
you're going to need some software.
One of the most common ones
is Open Broadcaster Studio,
which is a free tool available.
If you visit obsproject.com,
there's a wealth of tutorials
and documentation, and this allows you
to set up complex
studios on your computer.
You could actually have multiple inputs,
multiple screens, picture-in-picture
effects, graphics.
It's really quite powerful, and
free free to check this out,
as it allows you to do a
very rich mobile broadcast.
If you're looking for a paid tool, well,
then take a look at Wirecast,
which is a well-rounded
solution that's been around
for many years and makes it
easy to do live broadcasting.
Now, I'm a big fan of OBS Studio.
It makes it easy
to get my content out
there, and it's free.
They also have excellent
documentation and support forums.
Once you've installed
it, it's pretty easy,
and you simply go through
and add different sources.
You'll notice here, for example, that not
only can you use different local devices,
but you can load in
graphics or other sources
or a video capture device like a webcam
or the Blackmagic Design Web Presenter.
Then, it's pretty simple.
You switch over to your streaming channel.
Select the live stream
option, and click Get Started.
Type in the details about the stream
and whether or not you
want it public or private.
Click Reveal at the bottom of the page.
This is very important,
and I'll show you it in just a moment.
Then, highlight the
stream key and copy it.
You need this, because the
Open Broadcasting software
or Wirecast is going to
need this key in order
to access your YouTube channel.
Copy that key, and then
paste it into your software.
Then, in the software,
get it all set up and start to stream.
Choose YouTube as the provider,
and put the stream key
in so it knows how to access it.
This is going to connect your computer
to YouTube for the live stream.
Click the Start button,
and you should now be broadcasting live.
Back in the web browser,
the status will change
to online, and your live
stream will be available.
Let me show you how this works.
It's really pretty straightforward.
It just has a lot of steps,
so I'll try to go slow.
In YouTube, simply make sure
you're visiting your Creator Studio.
Then, go to Live Streaming,
and choose Stream now.
You'll now see a simple
checklist to follow.
I'll click Set up encoding software,
and it's got some interesting information.
I can also get information
about the stream
and take advantage of other features,
so there's lots of great articles here.
Let's go ahead and leave this
as is, Photofocus Live Stream.
This is only a test.
I'm not going to worry about categories,
but you can decide where it gets mapped
and what is the privacy setting.
There we go.
I'll make this one unlisted for now.
Under Advanced settings, there
are lots of other controls
that you can access, and you'll see here
that you can decide how you want to chat,
copyrights, and other options,
and whether or not it's allowed to embed.
These options are very much like some
of the things you saw before for a video,
but I do recommend that
you tell it to record
and archive as well as
decide if you want comments.
The DVR option will
allow people to rewind,
and you can even set the
quality of the stream.
For example, we can do
higher quality streaming,
but it's going to have more of a lag.
And so take a look
at these advanced options
for additional control.
I'll click Save changes here.
Now, let's go back to the
basic info for a moment,
and I've got the option
here selected for custom.
Now, let's go back to
Stream now for a moment,
and you'll see some of the key info.
We've got our general options.
I see that I have Super Chat,
and here's my encoder setup.
Well, this is really important here.
I'm going to reveal that and copy it.
Later on, we can reset this
so people can't see it,
and it will change out the key.
Here's also the URL
for sharing this video.
Now that I've got that
key, I need to switch
to Open Broadcaster Studio,
and let's add a new device for Source.
I'll choose Video Capture Device,
and choose this from the
preset list for the USB camera.
My camera turns on, and there's my video.
Hi.
Let's adjust the angle a little bit.
Now, I'll turn on the
camera, and it's available,
and I can adjust the camera slightly
or mount this at a better
angle so it's not shooting up
to the ceiling, but
for purposes of a test,
this is going to work.
You'll notice that you could
also choose a quality setting
depending upon your camera,
and I'm going to click OK.
Now, it's actually seeing
it, but what's not coming
through is the audio
yet, so I need to click
to add an audio source,
Audio Input Capture.
I'll click OK and tell it
to use the built-in
microphone or my webcam.
There we go.
So now we've got our different sources.
Let's go ahead and click here
and choose Audio Input Capture,
and we'll select our source and click OK.
So now, I've got audio and video.
Now, this allows us to get
the general content in,
and what I'm going to
do next is set this up,
so I'll simply run the wizard here,
Tools, Auto-Configuration Wizard,
and let's step through the options.
I'm going to tell it that the
main purpose is to stream.
And what do I want it to use?
Well, the resolution's fine.
Set the frame rate.
Click Next.
I can now choose which
streaming service to use,
such as YouTube, and I can paste that key
in there, and I'll click Next.
Now, it's going to take a moment
as it analyzes the settings
and attempts to configure.
There we go.
I'll click Apply Settings,
and we now have a live signal with video,
and in fact, I can see the studio here.
Later on, I can load more
than one source up here,
and this can be quite useful.
All right, let's go head over
to YouTube and take this live.
In this case, I'm sending out a signal,
and I'll click Start Streaming.
You see the green light
indicating that it's there.
Now, if we switch back over,
you see that the stream health is solid.
It says that my content
is there, and I am live,
so now we are sending a signal,
and it takes a moment, and it kicks in.
Now, my lips are going
to be totally out of sync
with my voice, because I chose
the higher quality method.
That's because there's more of a delay.
Now, that general process you
just saw might have seemed
a little bit confusing,
and you're going to
want to dig in and look
at the documentation and
watch that video a few times.
The secret is this.
Use a tool like Open Broadcasting Studio
and get your set up, whether
you're using built-in hardware
or third-party hardware.
Then, absolutely,
positively take advantage
of the setup wizard.
All you need is your streaming key,
and YouTube will take care
of the rest in the background
as it all becomes configured,
but what this means is
that you can use multiple cameras
or special hardware devices
and have even more control
of what gets streamed live.
Now, once the video's over, you'll see
that it completes, and
then you can go over
to your video manager to control this.
It's now a video like any other video,
and it will appear momentarily
in the video manager.
Here's that live stream
we recorded a while ago.
I'll go ahead and delete that one,
and within a few minutes,
the video that we
just recorded will appear in this list,
and then we'll have the
ability to edit the controls,
modify it, or do anything
else that's needed.
It will take a moment for
YouTube to move the file over,
but it will become a
video like anything else
in the video manager, and
you can control the privacy
and the information about the file.
All right, hopefully that
gives you a pretty good idea
on how live streaming works.
I do invite you to check out
some of the other courses
in the library about live video streaming
and a class I have on webinars,
and you'll learn a lot more
about putting this all together.